Go Cowboys.
Come on.
Hey. Hey.
Go cowboys.
Go Cowboys.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Go kill boys.
Go Cowboys.
Heat.
Go cowboys.
Go Cowboys.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
The Dallas Cowboys Radio Network is on
the air. This is the 2026 NFL draft with
Kyle Yman's, Zack Walchuk, Brian Brous,
Bobby Belt, Nick Harris, Tommy Yarish,
and Vach Lombardi.
Night one of the 2026 NFL draft is upon
us. It takes place in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. But all eyes for Dallas
Cowboys fans are on the war room inside
the Star in Fris, Texas. Welcome in to
the draft show and the coverage of wall
to wall coverage. Over 257 selections
over the next three days right here on
the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
dallascowboys.com.
Welcome in to the SWBC studios everyone.
Over the next couple of days, we are
going to have the best combination of
DFW draft experts that you will hear
throughout the weekend. From 1053, the
fan NFL insider Bobby Belt, DFW sports
expert Zack Walchuk, and of course the
godfather of the draft show himself,
Brian Bratis makes the return to the
Star in Fris from the Fort Worth Star
Telegram. Dallas Cowboys do or former
Dallascowboys.com beatwriter, but now
Dallas Cowboys beat writer, Mr. Nick
Harris from Cl Cr Crown Global Media,
YouTube superstar and film guru Vach
Lombardi will join us. And then from
DallasCowboys.com, beat writer and
Cowboys insider Tommy Yarish and myself,
TV and podcast host for the Cowboys,
Kyle Yman's. Gentlemen, it's here. We've
waited a long time for this week, but
Brian, it's good to have you back in
studio. I'll let you kick things off.
>> Yeah, thank you very much. I just came
back for the free weekend shirts. Is
that what Yeah, those nice draft polos
that you guys give us. So, no, it's it's
always a it's an honor to be back. It's
an honor to be in this chair again, and
it's an honor to be working with uh with
guys and gals that are so committed to
covering the NFL draft the right way.
You guys are all a credit to uh to the
to the the craft that we do. Uh it you
said it, Kyle, it's the absolute best
draft coverage that you could ever ever
take on. And so, love being a part of
that.
>> It's going to be a long week, no doubt
about it. We're about 20 hours of radio
over the next 48 hours total is what
we're headed toward. But it's one of the
best weekends of the year, Nick, because
I would argue it's the most
unpredictable weekend of the sports
calendar. Not to mention this draft more
than any other draft that I've covered.
This is going to be unpredictable and it
starts really with pick number two and
the rest of the draft is still
completely up in the air.
>> Yeah, the parody in this draft
specifically is is pretty wild. It's
it's it's it's staunching. I I think
with uh as it pertains to Dallas
specifically, these two picks and they
talked about it yesterday, it gives them
so much freedom to move around. We are
going to be keeping an eye on that war
room camera all night to make sure that
that phone when it picks up is it is it
maybe earlier than usual, later than
usual? Uh when does that happen for
these guys? And if they do stick at 12,
does one of these defenders fall? Do
they take a receiver? and then we're
having a completely different
conversation after George Pickkins uh
apparently is getting ready to sign his
franchise tag here pretty soon. Um
there's a lot that could happen here
over the next 48 hours. I'm excited for
it and glad to be in this room with you
guys.
>> You bring up the small tidbit of
breaking news there and it's a pretty
big one when it comes to the possible
draft plans for Dallas. George Pickkins
expected to the franchise tag uh and
play on that tag possibly this year.
Does that change anything in your
mindset, Tommy, now that you have a guy
like George Pickkins? After yesterday's
press conference, many were saying and
questioning the future for him in
Dallas, but now he's saying, "I'm okay
playing on that tag."
>> Yeah, it brings up a lot of different
possibilities. Now, I think, you know,
the first possibility is George Pickins
could be staying in Dallas on a one-year
deal worth $27.3 million. And that's
obviously going to be yet to be seen. We
the other option now that he is expected
to sign the tag. He has not signed the
tag yet but he's expected to do so here
in the short future I would assume uh is
obviously a trade option which is you
know something that I'm sure has been
discussed at length uh externally and
we'll see if that's something that the
Cowboys are interested in. But now
that's an additional option that Dallas
has with Pickkins. And of course, we've
talked a lot about the last couple of
days, what if it's a wide receiver at
pick number 12 or pick number 20 for
Dallas? Is that maybe pushed the needle
for a trade to go down more? But, uh,
this essentially opens the door to a lot
of different things. And of course, if
Pickkins is to stay in Dallas, that now
makes mandatory mini camp and training
camp events that he has to be at,
otherwise there'll be fines incurred
there. So, it's going to be very
interesting to see what happens now that
he's expected to sign that tag. You've
got options now if you're Dallas or
George Pickkins. You can play or you can
be traded. Bobby, based on what you're
hearing in the last couple of hours,
where do you feel like you lean on where
George Pickkins would lie?
>> I think he's playing. I think he's
playing. I think he's showing up. Um I I
don't know if he shows up right away for
all the OTAA stuff. We'll we'll see
about that. Um but I think he's here for
training camp. I think he plays football
this season and after that we'll see. I
think that they they have not this is
not a secret. They they talk openly
about it. George Pickkins arrived here
with a certain reputation. U fair or
unfair, he arrived here with a certain
reputation and he had a great year last
year and it it it probably wasn't enough
for people who are not here physically
to just erase some of the things they
thought about him last year. And so I
think that what you're looking at is
being in a position of if they're going
to make me play on the tag, I probably
just need to play on the tag and and you
know, approach the season with a a prove
it mindset of like, I'm going to go out
there and I'm going to do it again, not
just on the field, but off the field and
and you know, the perception that exists
out there. Um, again, fair unfair, which
I think a lot of his teammates would say
is unfair at this point. Mhm.
>> Um but I I think that yeah, he's going
to play um because he he understands
that he doesn't have the luxury, I don't
think, with the rest of the league to or
or here in Dallas to be able to just
say, "I'm I'm going to sit this one
out."
>> Brian, how does that change the way you
could draft tonight specifically? Yeah,
I you know I there's as we're kind of
working on the draft, we're hearing all
kinds of different possibilities when it
came to the wide receivers and and you
know it's been very much a defensive
heavy whether it's the edges, the
corners, the linebackers and then the
really the last say week or so we're
starting to hear more about wide
receivers and you know when whether it's
you know Tyson or Tate or or Cooper you
know all these names were kind of
appearing and everybody's going, "Wait a
minute. What's Dallas doing?" Talking
about these these wide receivers. And I
I think in a way it's like Will Mcclelay
is I think is really good at, you know,
protecting himself. You know, when he
starts to build his roster, he's like,
"Listen, if I feel like I'm going to be
a little short somewhere, maybe I can
protect myself." So, it's not surprising
to me that they're talking about these
wide receivers because I feel like they
stack just as good as some of those
positions that I just named.
When it comes to wide receiver in the
draft, I know there are some names that
maybe draft fans have heard of, Nick,
but who are the guys at the top of the
list that Dallas would even consider in
that first round?
>> Yeah. Uh, you'll take a look at Carnell
Tate and Jordan Tyson. If those two guys
start to slip and the Cowboys are
getting close to being on the clock, the
defenders are coming off the board, then
we're having conversations in this room
and they are certainly having
conversations upstairs about what that
strategy looks like. Um, and if they end
up do they end up falling on a receiver,
uh, whether they move up and take one or
they take one at 12, I don't see them
moving up to take one. I will say that,
uh, they would probably stick and pick
at 12 and and take a receiver if that
scenario were to play out. Um, but if
that happens, then, uh, yeah, we're
we're going to we're going to be in for
a wild ride. And that postdraft press
conference is certainly going to be one
with a lot of antics.
>> Do you think they would go up to draft
anybody?
>> What do you mean?
>> Would they move up to go get You said
they wouldn't go up to get a wide
receiver. Yeah. Would they go up at all
in the draft?
>> What I've been saying what I've been
saying over the course of the last week
is do they have a potential desire to
move up? Yes. But they want to pick
twice in the first round. That is very
important for them. They got that asset
in the Michael Parsons trade. They want
to be able to utilize that asset. And
the only way that they move up and still
keep that scenario happening is if they
move up with Kansas City and it's a swap
9 and 29 for 12 and 20. Uh that's the
one I've been pointing out all week.
Unless it's that I don't necessarily see
a reality. You could look at Cleveland
at six if David Bailey or Arll Reese
were to fall. I don't see them getting
out of the top five. So, I don't think
that scenario plays out. Um, so, you
know, we look at Kansas City and we go
from there. But, again, I I've I've
mentioned it more over the course of the
last few days. Sticking and picking is
more of a realistic possibility than
we've talked about, I would say, over
the last seven days. But, man, once this
once this thing starts here at the top
of the hour, anything is is up for play.
It's very rare that you think about
going up and then with the second pick
going back within the same round, but
there's a couple of teams I was hearing
that the the New York Jets were going to
be one of those teams. There's teams in
the middle of that board that how
depending on how many first round grades
you have, if you're in that mode of 11
or 12, 13 first round grades, there's
some teams that are behind that number
that are thinking about how could I go
up and get one of these players. But in
the Cowboys case, if it's the Kansas
City trade, then it's that go up and
then let's go back. Uh by going back,
you're into that potentially into that
29 range. And they might be a little bit
more comfortable taking some positions
that uh that that they weren't when they
were picking at 20.
>> How many first rounds did you end up
with?
>> 13.
>> Okay. All right.
>> 13
>> around the around the table here. I'm
curious
>> where did you get
>> uh 16. And I felt like it was a little
heavy, but I I like my 16.
>> I I stayed at 16 as well. I'm right
there with you. 14.
>> 14.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, across the board, you're under
what you would normally have. Usually
under I'm 18 to 20, 25, something like
that.
>> Yeah. It's it's very rare that you get a
a draft where you're only talking about,
you know, 13 14. I I talked to a team
the other day that had 11, you know. So,
these are the things that now that, you
know, and when you we start to talk
about, well, I have a second round grade
on him. It's not that the player is, you
know, he just did not fall into the
window of first round grades. It's just
your evaluation. And a lot of people
can't understand that when you when you
say, well, hey, I he's outside. There's
some there's some players that are going
to be taken and on my board, of course,
at 14, 15, 16 that are second round
grades on my board, but they will be
taken in the first round. That's just
the way teams operate. A lot of people
say, "Well, you need to put them in
tears." Well, for forever we've put them
in the rounds and that's and that's how
you know that we stack our boards.
>> Where did you put Sunny Styles?
>> Put him at 16 is what I did. And this
>> How many first round grades you have?
>> 13. He's outside. He's He's clearly
outside. I think with Sunny Styles when
you start to talk about him as a player,
he's played the position for two years.
And there's there's things that you
could see with Sunny Styles as a player
where they that that maybe that they
fool him a little bit with some
misdirection stuff. Maybe they play with
his eyes a little bit. You know, Sunny
Styles, the the measurables, everything
about him is is outstanding. You this
40inch vertical, the broad jump, all
these things, but as a player, you know,
time on task, you know, you're thinking
about plug and play. You're thinking
about all the things you have to do.
Yes, that you can get this type of
player in the future, but you might be
in a situation where very early in his
career, he's going to have to learn the
position. He is a converted safety.
>> Can Can I ask you a question? I'm
curious cuz this is something that uh
I'm sure we've covered in years past.
I'm just not recalling. How much of when
you're evaluating somebody are you
evaluating what they are now versus what
they could like? For instance, you you
think I'm assuming that I think Styles
could be a first round player by the
time his rookie contract is over.
>> No, he absolutely. You know, the thing
that like I said, I was watching him as
a player and I was watching the stuff
where early in the season where he was
struggling getting off blocks. there's
stuff you can watch and by the time you
got to the Big 10 championship game
there was playing a little bit better. I
just feel like though that the
experience if you want to say, you know,
I I said earlier everything about him is
it could be super positive the you know
the way he gets experience as a player.
But right now I mean listen let's be
honest guys like Donovan Ezaraku last
year third I thought Donovan Ezaraku was
the third best rusher in the draft and
all of a sudden in week one he's playing
Jordan Myada and he looks like he never
rushed a passer in his life. So to me,
you know, these sometimes these players,
they could look pretty, they could look
great. You know, this this guy reminds
me very much of a guy like a Willie
McInness. That goes way back in the day,
but that type of athlete, that type of
size, you know, but it takes a little
bit of some time. And there might be a
little bit of of a learning curve for
him as a linebacker. Everything else
about him is super positive. Who are the
guys at the top of your list, let's stay
specifically on the defensive side of
the ball, that are NFL ready? Because
we've heard it from the Dallas front
office quite often throughout the draft
process. They want guys that are ready
now to play and ready to contribute to
this team in 2026. Who are those guys
for you?
>> I kind of feel like that if you look at
Bailey from Texas Tech, I feel like that
he is a readymade pass rusher. I feel
like that Delane when you look at Delane
as far as what he is able to do uh you
know coming into the uh coming into the
to the league you know you you watch him
the way that he plays I thought McCoy
was that way too when I watch McCoyy's
2024 tape it's unfortunate about the
knee situation with him but the couple
of these corners I kind of feel like
Bailey is a pass rusher I kind of feel
like that Ruben Bane's the same way I
watched Ruben Bane when he when he was
you know everybody talks about the the
physical limit limitations that he has,
the the shorter arms and stuff. I
watched him for 17 weeks break down
offensive tackles and he has a plan. He
has a pass rush plan. He plays the run
particularly well. Those are the guys
defensively that, you know, we'll see
what happens with Ree. You know, Ree is
one of these guys, too. Is he is he a
linebacker? Is he an edge? You know,
where does he kind of fit in that mode?
So when when you're when you're talking
about these types of players and you
think, oh, plug and play immediately,
you know, guys like Zack Martin to me
way back in, you know, that draft,
that's plug and play. That's immediately
you don't worry. Booker to a point last
year for the Cowboys was a little bit
plug and play. I think defense is a
little bit different story when you look
at the defensive side of the ball.
That's going to be a big talking point
for Dallas throughout the NFL draft. And
a big part of that is the new defensive
coordinator and Christian Parker, what
he's going to bring to a new scheme and
a new formation for the defensive side.
When we return on the other side of the
break, I want to talk about how that
could affect the draft process. I know
we've heard from the front office and
Will Mcclelay has said that it shouldn't
affect the way you build your board, but
will it affect some of the conversations
between players that are close on that
NFL draft board? Just getting started.
It's night one of the 2026 NFL draft.
You're listening to the 20 26 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
Hello internet friends. This is the the
true troopers that are watching with the
video that are watching with the stream
and know that we don't actually take
full commercial breaks even though we do
so on the radio side of things. Back
with Nick Harris.
>> We pee in this cup.
>> What? We pee in this cup whenever we
have to go. We don't get breaks around
here.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> You're going to finish the drink first,
right?
>> Yeah. You see that's why it's got a
little color to it.
>> That's what the colors already strength
when you don't leave the room. That's
the whole idea. Feeds a strength.
>> It's like a sibling.
>> Yeah.
>> The amount of buttoned up we were on
that first segment on the radio and then
to turn into that loosen up a little
bit. I'm glad you brought that up. I
really am. There's a lot of topic of
conversation going on between offense
defense. Do you really think an
offensive player is in play at 12 and 20
for Dallas at either position?
>> Well, I think absolutely, especially if
they get in a situation where guys are
coming off the board and if they start
to eliminate guys, if say they
eliminate, you know, we we want to
believe about the whole thing with Bane.
If they eliminate Bane, they eliminate
McCoy, you know, all of a sudden then
you start drafting guys, you know, maybe
eliminate Messador because of his age.
Yeah. Yeah, I mean you start eliminating
defensive players and all of a sudden as
you stack your board, this team is
really good when they stack their board
in a way and then and take that player.
We could go back through the the
history, you go back, I mentioned Zack
Martin earlier and and the whole thing
with Ryan Shayer and all the CD Lamb
draft. I mean, they when they stack
their board and they go for generally
the player that they feel like that they
they they have the best feeling on and
they take that guy, it usually works out
pretty well for them. I could, like I
said earlier, I can see some wide
receivers having some better grades than
some of these defensive players and and
that would make a lot of sense.
>> Can I bring up a Debbie Downer scenario
at the moment?
>> Sure.
>> So, I was on a uh radio call with a
station out in Jacksonville and
basically what they do is they call a
beat writer from every beat and do a
mock draft in the first round. And when
they called me, all the defenders were
off the board and Tyson and Tate and I
couldn't trade out of it. And um but
Spencer Fono was on the board. Huh.
>> And I I wonder like if is Spencer Fono
or a Francis Malangoa or um uh who else
would maybe be in that top mix? I doubt
Kaden Proctor would make a lot of sense
for this team. But if that's the best
thing you got at 12 and you can't trade
out of it, you're stuck. No one's on the
phone.
>> Hey man, tackle isn't the best position
on this team. You know, I we would hate
it because man, we've
>> another offensive lineman so many damn
offensive linemen on this show in the
last five years. But they that would be
your BPA. That would be your best player
on the board probably.
>> Does Sadi fall into that category from
Oregon?
>> Maybe not at 12, but maybe at 20.
>> He could probably fall in either way.
He's a good enough playmaker where I I
could see it happen.
>> I could see I understand why you took
Feno at at at uh I can understand why
you took him when you did because it
does kind of fit what you're trying to
do.
>> But uh but man, I I I think with Sadi
that might be one of those ones that
like, okay, do I take this tackle? Do I
feel good about it or do I take a guy
that could be this type of this weapon
as a as a pass catcher at tight end?
>> Yeah,
>> all of that could could play a factor in
terms of offensive tackle, interior,
offensive line, all of the things
elementwise on the the scheme. And when
we come back on the radio side, I want
to save it for that that conversation.
There are changes coming to the
defensive side, but what are those
changes, right? Is it really a three
four base? But how what's the percentage
of what they're going to play?
>> We just don't know exactly. We just
don't know. I mean, this this this this
defensive coordinator is going to have a
lot of say in what happens in this
draft. They are going they they Jerry
and Stephen and Will, they lean on these
coaches hard. Yeah.
>> And I'll tell you what though, Christian
Parker has so far, you know, he's said
the right thing, done the right things.
Everybody seems to be really, you know,
hanging on every word with him kind of,
but we don't know. That's that's the
that's the big mystery here. We don't
know how this is all going to be.
About 40 minutes away from the official
opening.
Welcome back in to night one of the 2026
NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com. Back with
Brian Bratis, Bobby Belt from 1053, the
fan from the Fort Worth Star Telegram,
Nick Harrison from dallascowboys.com,
Tommy Yish, and myself, Kyle Yman. So
glad you're with us as we lead you into
the opening of the NFL draft that is set
to take place at 7:00 Central time.
Prior to going to the break on the radio
side, uh we were talking about certain
prospects that could be intriguing on
the defensive side of the ball. It also
helps knowing what type of system and
what type of formation you'll see on the
defensive side of the ball under
firstear defensive coordinator Christian
Parker. Brian, we were talking in the
break there for a minute. You don't
necessarily know what is going to be the
the breakup of a multiple defensive
scheme. However, what can we learn
tonight based on how they pick? Well,
you know, Christian Parker, whether it's
interviews that he's done with
DallasCowboys.com in front of the media,
you know, with with everybody involved,
or whether it's on 1053, the fan, you
know, he's tried to give us some hints
of what his defense might look like. And
this is why, you know, as media scouts,
we might not be too happy with the pick
of a guy like Faulk from Auburn, but
where they understand him as a guy that
could play potentially, you know, as a
down lineman, maybe not a pass rusher.
So, they have ideas of certain players.
I kind of personally watch the Dallas
Cowboys play defense. I'm like, who's
the guy that's the rusher? Who's the guy
that's going to get the quarterback on
the ground? And right now, I mean, with
Donovan Ezra, we'll see. But if they
take a guy like Faulk, then all of a
sudden you kind of understand, oh well,
maybe this guy is a four eye. Maybe
they're not using him as a pass rusher.
Maybe they have an idea where it's
Williams, Clark, uh Faulk, those kinds
of guys. Okay, that's their defensive
line. And now they're going to kind of
build around that. So, like I say,
that's those are the kinds of when they
take a player, then you're going to kind
of say, "Okay, wait a minute. What is
his skill set and how does he fit?" And
to them, it makes a lot of sense. to us,
we're kind of like going, damn, get
somebody to get the quarterback on the
ground. You got enough, you've got
enough pass, you got enough defensive
linemen that potentially could just be
really, really good run defenders and
occasional pass rushers.
>> Tommy, you've been on the the proday
trail. You've been at the the owners
meetings, the combine, the senior bowl.
You've talked with the staff as much as
anybody in the room. Do you get an
instance of where they would maybe value
some of these prospects that are at the
top half of the draft and how they would
utilize them?
>> Well, I think when you look at
everything that they've done in free
agency, offseason acquisitions,
everything like that up to this point,
they've constructed this defense from
the back to the front.
>> Yeah,
>> it's been a lot of building from the
secondary and building up corners,
safeties, coverage players. You know,
typically you see a lot of people talk
about, okay, we want to build our roster
from the front lines, defensive line,
your pass rushers, and go back from
there. It seems like they've done the
inverse up to this point. So, if that
tells you that, hey, we we value the
secondary. We want to be able to cover
more than anything and maybe force more
coverage sacks if like Brian pointed out
you don't necessarily have a alpha kind
of pass rusher
>> and we just want to have guys in the
back that can cover everything take away
every portion of the field then you look
at you know guys that we speculated for
a long time about Ohio State's Caleb DS
LSU's Mansour Delane those kinds of
players that they feel like they can
plug back there now I think Brian also
makes a good point eventually you do
need to load up a little bit in the pass
rush position and Kendrick Faulk is a
guy that for eye we've talked about a
ton over this offseason because
Christian Parker said that's an
important part that could be an option
or in those trade up scenarios that we
discussed for a long time where hey if
they really want to go up to six which I
don't think they will
>> it would probably only be if one of
those two pass rushers Texas Tech David
Bailey or Ohio State Arville Reese was
there um but everything that they've
told us so far says how much they value
the secondary and the coverage portion
of this defense which isn't really much
of a surprise given Christian Parker's
background.
>> Yeah. When when you hear that from
Christian Parker, the outside in
mindset, Bobby
>> and back to front like Tommy
>> like Tommy was talking about earlier.
>> When it comes to whenever it gets to
that point, is that something they've
already been doing? Have they shown that
throughout the offseason? Signing safety
Jaylen Thompson and uh bringing in Kobe
Durant and bringing in guys like that.
>> They don't have a linebacker at all.
like they don't have a linebacker and
they they added uh Rashawn Garry and
they added corners and um you know even
the the safety that they added is a guy
who can play some some nickel stuff.
>> Well, I was going to ask you guys this
question then. They've been very
>> very I want to say almost they've tried
in free agency maybe to get some guys
>> but they but they've been kind of lax
like we we're sense of urgency. They're
a little bit more calmer about it. Do
you feel like they have a deal already
in place with somebody potentially
>> that like like postdraft they've already
got they've got whether the Dolphins the
>> they did that with Pickkins last year.
Yeah,
>> they they they had a contingency in
place. Um
>> you know I would I I think it's it's
interesting to note that who was this
team's biggest free agent signing? Not
the trade free agent signing
>> this year. It's Thompson, right?
>> Yeah. Who would be second?
>> Kobe Durant
>> probably. Who would be third?
>> Uh maybe Lock.
>> PJ Lock. Yeah. Safety.
>> Everybody in the secondary. And now
we're talking about their top pick is
going to be somebody in the secondary. I
think it's very clear like where they
the thrust of this defense is going to
be. And it's going to be in the way that
they attack with their secondary and the
way that the different multiple looks
they can get from that. And I don't
think they're just going to, you know,
reach on a linebacker or if they don't
love an edge rusher. I don't think
they're going to just reach on one of
those things because they feel like,
well, we've got to find this cuz to them
it's like, no, we want Christian Parker
as being a defensive backminded guy.
Clearly wants to stack that area with
the type of players that he really
thinks they need. And I think he thinks
that everything else behind that is
secondary.
>> And hey, if all else fails, you still
have Kenneth Murray out on the open
market.
>> That's true. Yeah.
>> Bring the bit back. I had to bring
>> 25 minutes into the weekend.
>> I had to bring the bit back.
>> 25 minutes in and that's all it took for
>> Kenneth Murray Smith. either one of
them. The uh does that bode well for
taking
>> Kenneth Murray? No, that's awful.
>> Stop it.
>> Does that bode well for taking somebody
in the secondary when they've already
invested that much into the secondary or
are they still wide open whatever the
best player? Yeah, I think I think
they're they're pretty open, but I mean
I think that if they're looking at let's
say miracle situation, Styles, Delane,
and DS all fall to them where they're
picking. In theory, you would say, "All
right, well, all things equal, the the
position they really need is linebacker.
Take Styles." I think there's a chance
Styles would be the third one they would
take there.
>> Wow.
>> Because I think they just I I think they
do view it as really important to make
sure that they get those guys right on
the perimeter. And is that more about
getting the guys right on the perimeter
or the confidence that they have in the
defensive tackle duo of Quinon Williams
and Kenny Clark just to be like, "Hey,
we can get by at linebacker. We can go
get someone in in the trade market that
can do the job. Let's get the elite guys
on the outside. Let's cash in on the
people."
>> Well, and to Brian's point, they may
have a contingency in place where it's
like if we don't get somebody here,
we've got a contingency. We may not have
a contingency to do what we think Caleb
DS can do for us or what we think
Mansour Delane can do for us. Could that
also be a a sign of what is to come in
terms of the health of your cornerback
room specifically?
>> You've revamped your safety room to
>> Oh, there's no question about that.
>> An extent, but your quarterback room
almost everybody across the board has a
medical on.
>> They they don't have a nickel. I mean,
and and if you draft a lane, you could
potentially use him for that. And you
know, I know we had a chance to talk
with Muhammad from Texas uh yesterday on
on 1053 the fan,
>> Malik Muhammad, and he was talking about
he visited with the Cowboys and they
were already talking about nickel stuff
with him,
>> you know, they were already saying,
well, hey, do you do this? Do you do
this? So, I I kind of feel like though
if you address it, whether that's downs,
you know, whether that's delaying, that
that's something I think that's still
weighing on their mind. But I don't know
how you can look at the secondary and
look at the corners and feel great in a
way that listen Bland's foot that's got
to be a concern. I think Rival he's
going to be I think he's going to come
back. I think he not you know the whole
thing he had to deal with. I think there
was some setbacks. I think he kind of
fought through that. You know three
games in 12 days. I don't think that
helped him at all dealing with the
brace. I think there was all these
things. The fact that he can work have
an offseason work on his craft. I think
he'll be a better player. But there are
some concerns that you have at that
position. So, I could absolutely see why
they're looking at corn. It
>> It is fascinating to me though because I
think you definitely if you had to roll
the ball out there and play tomorrow, I
don't have a second linebacker. But I
think I do have at the very least three
or four guys that could play some
nickel. Like I think Durant can play
nickel. Jaylen Thompson can. Uh Don
Bland can and Ready Stewart would be the
maybe fourth. Uh I don't right now I'm
running out with Justin Baron and
Demarian Overton at linebacker.
>> Oh no. I but I to me I I I said I'm
looking at it as I'm looking at like
Durant I see did did you see him play a
lot of nickel?
>> Yes. Not not last year but for
for his career he has played the same
number of snaps in the nickel as Don
Bland has.
>> Okay. Okay. Now okay and we don't want
to move Don Bland inside. Right.
>> He they don't seem to want to but Bland
has done it before and and so it's a
they've both played about 30% of their
career snaps in the nickel. It's just
Durant did a lot of his previously and
last year he was pretty much outside but
he's done it before and Thompson can
>> see I the the one with Thompson that's
I'm thinking I'm thinking why they're
talking about Delane is because I think
they're looking for a real nickel. I
mean I think they're looking I think
they're looking I mean it to me if
you're
>> if they take Dellayan or downs that that
is your primary nickel but I'm saying if
they had to go out there tomorrow I
think the contingency is they have
people on the roster who could in theory
do it whereas with linebacker I don't
know that they've got anybody who can do
it right now
>> the linebacker situation is a mess. It
really is
>> just based off of draft value in terms
of the prospects that you could take in
the first round 12 and 20 overall for
Dallas.
Are they just stuck because the
secondary players match the value? Guys
like DS and Delane and those early
secondary possibilities, but outside of
linebacker at Sunny Styles, there's not
a ton of confidence in the guys that you
could take at 12 and 20 because if you
don't take one there, you don't have a
pick until 92. Maybe they address it
there. Is that why this conversation is
what it is at the moment? Yeah, and I
mean that's not to say that there
wouldn't be a linebacker for you at 92
because I I I do think there's a
scenario where they don't take a
linebacker on day one, they get to 92
and a Josiah Troder out of Missouri is
there or a uh depending on how they feel
about Bryce Betcher out of Oregon. I
like Bryce Betcher. Um is is CJ Allen's
medicals enough to slip him to 92? I
don't think so. But you think about
those things. I like Jimmy Rder out of
Michigan. And so there's there's some
Keshan Elliot out of Arizona State.
That's another one. So, do they take one
of those guys and then just sign Bobby
Wagner in free agency and call that I
think that's a fine way to address the
position because not only do you have a
veteran and a young guy in the room, you
have a bit more depth. You're going to
need to probably triple up on linebacker
still in this draft. But, um I I think
that is just as fine as, you know, going
out and trading for one and sacrificing
future capital next week.
>> They may go get one. I think what they
have absolutely told you to this point
by not willing to overpay in the
linebacker market, not making a move to
this point, seeming like they could be
potentially fine taking delaying or
downs over a styles in some instances. I
think what they're telling you there is
that one of the ways Christian Parker
will probably be different from Vic
Fangio is he doesn't feel like he needs
a Zack Bond or he doesn't need like one
of these other big-time linebackers. He
may feel like he can make do with
certain deficiencies at linebacker that
maybe Fangio didn't think he could and
and that Parker thinks he can insulate
him a little bit more. I think they have
told you that with their their moves.
>> Wasn't Zack Bond a player that was kind
of a deficiency initially.
Bond was considered a guy who had just
been a disappointment I think. Um but
but was somebody who it was just more
like where where have you locked into
the potential but but then they dug deep
and he became
>> Bon Bond was somebody that New Orleans I
don't feel like the this might be
coaching malpractice.
>> They didn't know they didn't they didn't
seem to have a clue of what they wanted
>> very similar
>> because there was a question about was
he a edge or linebacker type of player
>> he was exactly that to me that's kind of
like oh wait let's Dan Quinn figures out
that Michael Parsons can rush the
passer. Oh, here we are. You know, I
mean that that sometimes coaches have
got to come up with plans and stuff like
that, but after you watch Bond play,
that that was a that New Orleans for him
just to be a special teams guy, that
that seems like a that seems like a a
gross neglect right there. You know, the
other thing that you might be hearing
from them at this point is that they
feel good enough about the depth of the
linebacker class to say, "Hey, we we we
feel good about waiting until 92 or 112
and feel like we can get a starting
caliber player, whether that be
rotationally or or a pure starter
because you think about what they said
yesterday in the pre-draft press
conference, among many other things, uh
was Will Mlelay saying, "Hey, we feel
like the depth of this draft is in the
second through the fifth round." And you
think about Dallas has what, five picks
in that time span. So what do they do
with those picks? Do they feel like
there are going to be linebackers that
get to that point and can come in and
step up day one and do something?
>> I I think Troder, Rodriguez, Gold, I
think guys like that. I don't think the
league is as high on them as we have
been. And I think that there's a chance
they could get pushed down a little bit.
Not maybe not all the way to third round
in '92, but I I I definitely don't think
that the league has been it's it's like
you're going to see like five
linebackers go in the top 50. I don't
think that's going to be the case.
>> How does the linebacker stack for you
guys stretch the in terms of guys? Let's
let's cut it off as starting caliber in
terms of 50% of the snaps in year one as
a rookie. How how deep into your
linebacker stack can you go before you
cut it off and say that guy's not ready?
See, I would classify that as a third
round grade like what you just
explained. So, I have 10 linebackers in
the top three rounds, but six of those
are in the third round.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> So, the depth of the draft.
>> Where what about you, Brian?
>> I think I could go seven and I get down
to York and I maybe because of the size
that I would have a little bit
questions. I think
>> is he eight?
>> He Yeah, he's eight. I I think I would
draw the line at at Murdoch from
Buffalo. Okay. is kind of where I would
draw the line. I mean, I'm just talking
about the those inside guys is what uh
is what I'm thinking. But there's a
couple of guys, like I say, the there's
a couple projections, the Barum from
Michigan, there's a you know, those
guys, maybe there's others, but I kind
of feel like that I get to York and
beyond him that I'm a little bit uh
little bit thinking, oh man, I should
have maybe done this a little bit
earlier in my life. It's it's
fascinating because I think it's Yeah,
it's probably goes to like third round
or something.
>> Yeah, that's where it stops. Then there
there are other people who I I don't
have in the top three rounds that I
would say in the right context or if
maybe this answer this is answered for
me about them whatever else maybe like
for instance the first person that comes
to mind to me for that is like Lander
Barton
>> like like I I I think I I I don't think
Barton is a top three round player but I
also think that in the right context
Barton could play significant snaps for
you if you're you're
>> in the right sort of scheme and the
right sort of defense.
>> He's got the right measurables for it.
He's above that measured line, 6'4, 233
lbs.
>> His family might be more decorated than
him when it comes to all the things that
they've done in their lives. I mean,
maybe. But I, you know, that that's
that's one of those I because I think of
him a little bit further down the the
board than where, you know, I guess
where you guys would
>> Where do you have him?
>> I have him actually in the fifth round.
>> I have him in the fourth at LB14. I've
heard that some teams view him as a
tight end.
>> Yeah. I mean, you could actually watch
some tape and see played a little bit.
>> He did. And some teams view him as a
tight end.
>> Wow. Interesting. Very fascinating.
>> He's one of a number of cases in this
draft that when we get into day three,
we're going to have some fun breaking
down some tape because there's some
two-way guys, there's some possible
quarterbacks that could be wide
receivers. There's all sorts of wild uh
scenarios that can happen. But when we
come back, I want to get everybody set
for the first round of the NFL draft.
Let's outline what the pick order is
going to be, especially in front of
Dallas 1 through 11, and tell you what
Dallas does have to work with. If this
is your first time tuning into the draft
show, we'll get you ready for all seven
rounds. You're listening to the 2026 NFL
draft on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com.
On the.com side of things, taking a look
inside the war room. They have now
filtered through the tours that come
through on the day of the draft. There
are some tours that happen uh and the
front office staff is in the war room
for that. It's kind of like a exclusive
deal, but they're all gone. It is now
all business for Dallas. Less than 25
minutes away from the official opening.
We'll hear from Roger Goodell right
after that 7:00 Central time start. What
is the conversation right now in the war
room there, Brian, when it comes to the
the final minutes to the leadup and then
finally kicking this thing off?
>> Yeah, I think you need to have
everything. Uh, as you see right there,
Todd Williams, the director of football
operations administration is going
around. I think they're probably looking
at they've got their make sure
everybody's got their trade charts ready
to go. Uh, you know, he's going to pick
up maybe right there and he was going to
his computer. They have all that right
there. He's him, Adam Pacifica, those
guys are responsible for the trade
charge. So Jerry's probably looking down
at his looking at the order of where
he's uh you know what this where the
draft maybe he's talking about still
kind of thinking about potential trades
that they who want you know who wants to
go back, who wants to go up. Maybe going
through that in his mind kind of getting
an idea that once this once the opening
bell hits, you're going to then be ready
to get on that phone if you have to and
and make the and make the calls. So
yeah, it's just a matter of now just
making sure all the preparation that you
have their board set, everything's ready
to go, but it's just maybe you want to
make one more call. So you'll see
Stephen Jones occasionally pick up a
phone, somebody calling, checking in
saying, "Hey, we're do we still have a
deal?" You know, and Steven would
probably say, "Hey, well, if yeah, we
got a deal with you if our players on
the board." So those are the kinds of
things that they're going through right
now.
>> Brian, who did you hate receiving a call
from back in the day? I liked I thought
it was fun to get all kinds of calls.
The team that never called us was
Cincinnati.
>> So they hated calling you. Duke Tobin
who uh I used to call Duke and I would
say hey Duke has brought us in Dallas.
He goes, "Hey, what's going on Brian?"
I'm like, "Hey, just making sure the
phone works." He goes, "Okay, man. Good
luck with the draft. See you later." And
then I would never talk to Duke Tobin
again.
>> Brian, you got to stop pouring into
people that don't pour into you.
>> Yeah. I just, you know, it but yeah,
there's we did a we did a we did a draft
if you if you remember a very famous
draft with the Roy Williams, the
defensive back from Oklahoma.
>> We forgot to turn the trade trade in.
Just that that's the draft that Jerry
had uh Carl Peterson on one line and
Frank Gilliam on the other. And he got
Frank Gill he got both and I've never
seen this in a war room happen. He got
both general managers to tell them who
he was they were going to pick. And
Jerry said, "Okay, hang on a second."
and he put had the phones on his chest
and he goes, "They're not taking our
guy. Let's take the Kansas City deal."
So he said, "Frank, we're we're going to
hang on here. We're going to do
something else." Thank you. Hung up with
him. He goes, "Carles, you got a deal."
And then we went to we every we said,
"Okay, great. We got a deal." And Chris
Hall walked into the room and goes, "Did
anybody turn the trade in?" And the
clock was bleeding. Wow. the D and like
Robert Blackwell was sitting in New York
kind of like and they were filming him
and he's kind of smiling like I don't
know who we're going to pick. I don't
know. And you know and the clock so the
trade had not officially gone in and
Stephen Jones had to basically dive on
the table hit the phone and hit the NFL
trade button and said he goes this is
Dallas we got to trade with Kansas City
and basically made this trade with 8
seconds on the clock. If you if if one
side calls it in. Yeah. And you do not
have if if they do not match all the
exact terms both sides, the trade does
not go through.
>> Wow.
>> So, and and and Joel Bustard, who
>> you can't just say, hey, I'm calling on
behalf of both of us.
>> Yeah. Joel Busard, who was at the time
was doing the the player personnel
stuff. He called back and Stephen picked
up the phone and goes, "Uh, Dallas and
Buster goes, don't you effing do ever do
that again."
>> Wow.
>> And Stephen goes, "Okay, we got you,
Joel. Thank you." And started cracking
up. But literally, we're watching and
and God bless Chris Hall. He walked in
goes, "Did we turn in this trade?" Cuz
the clock kept bleeding, you know, and
and sure enough, it was that was the way
it was.
>> Let's hope tonight if they make a trade
with Kansas City, they'll turn it in on
on time.
>> The most amazing thing was Jerry because
usually you talk to a general manager
and and and you will they will say,
"Hey, well, who you taking?" And they'll
say, "We're taking offense. We're taking
defense. They will never tell you who
they're taking. Yeah.
>> And Jerry Jones got two two general
managers to do that. Amazing. Never seen
it before.
>> Interesting.
>> Can't wait to see what kind of wild
scenario happens this year.
>> They're a lot of fun. Usually there's
one. A lot of fun.
>> Think Aaron Rogers is going to announce
he's coming back to play.
>> That might be one of them. Who knows?
>> Diana Rsini just deleted her Twitter.
>> Oh, stop it.
She deleted her career.
Final segment before the 2026 NFL draft
gets underway in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. We are about 20 minutes
away from hearing from Roger Goodell,
the commissioner of the league to kick
off this year's NFL draft. We continue
on here from the Star in Fris just a
couple feet away from the Dallas Cowboys
war room where Jerry Jones, Brian
Shottimer, Will Mcclelay and the Cowboys
front office are currently sitting in
there. I don't see Steen Jones at the
moment. Doesn't mean he's not in the
room, but uh in terms of the war room
camera that we are taking a look at now.
No movement from Steven quite yet, but
>> Brian, these are trying times. A little
bit of nervous energy from anybody.
Doesn't matter how long you've been in
the league. There's nervous energy going
into night one.
>> Kyle, are we not going to recap Nick's
news before we were back on the radio
side?
>> If you would like to, I will give you
>> I would not go ahead behind me.
>> Okay.
>> It is it is an interesting story.
>> But uh
>> we'll just leave that for
interpretation.
>> Yeah. No, you're you're actually to be
honest with you guys, this is the calmst
that you are when you the the really the
stressful times are the stressful times
are are leading up to this when you're
trying to kind of figure out where
everybody's going to go or what's going
to happen ahead of you and and this is a
draft with only uh 11 12 13 first round
grades. You know, are you going to get
in your window? Are you going to be able
to, you know, pick the player that you
absolutely want? And now you're trying
to figure out with so much uncertainty.
And I think there's going to be a team
that I think there's a couple of teams
that are going to try and go up in this
thing. You know, I I think the Detroit
Lions from 17 are going to try and get
up in there. We've already talked about
potentially, you know, the New Orleans
Saints who are in that top, you know,
top eight, maybe they're going up to
Arizona. I could see Arizona trading
twice in this thing depending on them
going back, you know, and so that those
are the those are the times. But you've
prepared for all this, you know, when
when you the last few days, you've
worked on your board to the point where
you have an idea where people might be
going to get might going to get players.
And so with that being the case, you
know, you'll be ready to, you know, you
be ready for any situation that happens.
You know, you got to be ready if that
phone calls, maybe a team, maybe you're
not thinking that like that, you know,
maybe you're thinking about like, I want
to, hey, I want to be involved with this
one. And you you could pick up your
phone or somebody might call you and
say, hey, listen, we're interested in
moving this pick. and then that kind of
sets you in motion. But they prepare for
a lot of these a lot of these scenarios.
>> For those that may not have been
following the NFL draft process as
closely as those that have listened to
the draft show or 1053 the fan all all
season long, let's go through the top 20
picks and how they outline for Dallas
just because it it it could turn into
one of those scenarios where everybody
one through 20 could move around and
shake a little bit. It starts with the
Las Vegas Raiders at pick number one
overall. The general consensus is that
they would take a quarterback and most
notably Indiana's Fernando Mendoza would
be that number one overall pick. Number
two is the New York Jets. Then followed
by the Arizona Cardinals at three. Those
two are selections that generally are
mocked to see edge rushers premium
positions go at two and three. The order
in which they go is still up for
interpretation. Pick number four is an
interesting one for the Tennessee Titans
at fourth overall. That could be where
you see the first offensive player off
of the board if of course the Jets and
Cardinals stick with that edge rusher
mock. Then it's the New York Giants at
five, followed by the Cleveland Browns
at six. There's been a lot of
conversation for Dallas possibly trading
from the 12th overall pick up to the
sixth overall pick because of the trade
charts that these teams use universally
throughout the NFL. it could line up
from a ma mathematics situation where
they could go all the way up to 12 and
you still pick twice in the top 40
overall. They would pick at six and 39
if that's the case. At least according
to the trade charts, Nick.
>> Yeah, if if I could stop you uh really
quick, I would be surprised if Arizona
picks at three.
>> Okay.
>> I I think I think somebody's going to
trade up. And if you're asking me what
makes the most sense, it would be New
Orleans. But we'll see.
>> And that number three pick is going to
be certainly one to watch for the
Cowboys because let's say it's New
Orleans. They jump up and take Arll
Reese or David Bailey.
>> Cardinals come back to that would be
eight. They're taking an offensive
player there. I don't think they're
going to steal one of those defenders
from you.
>> So that's a good thing for Dallas if you
see a trade happened like that.
>> I think so.
>> Okay. So six with the Browns, seven with
the Washington Commanders, former
defensive coordinator Dan Quinn. And
then you've got the New Orleans Saints
at 8 for now is what you're saying.
Yeah. At at eight for now. Nine. Kansas
City is another team that teams have or
that Cowboys fans at least throughout
the draft process have tabbed as a
possible trade up scenario. Yeah.
Because they could pick twice in the
first round according to those NFL draft
trade charts.
>> Kansas City's been talked about about
doing both going up or coming back.
>> Interesting. Where would they go up to
that
>> airs? They would be one of they'd be one
of the ones potentially talking about
three.
>> And the Dallas and Kansas City front
offices, they are so tied in with each
other. I They talk to each other even
when it's not football season. like they
are friends at their neighbors. So yeah,
press the Preston Road trophy. Um but
>> that's how they got the Payton
Hendershot deal done.
>> Exactly. And the Eric Scott deal done.
Yep. So um maybe maybe a third times a
charm.
>> Maybe.
>> Hey, that Pton Hendershot conditional
seventh round pick is the reason you
have a seventh round pick this year. So
I don't want to hear anything from y'all
when it's 218 and there's finally a pick
on the board after like 60 picks.
>> Sorry guys. Uh so teams at eight and
nine, New Orleans and Kansas City both
as possible trade uh opportunities. The
Giants did trade into the 10th overall
pick. They send Dexter Lawrence to the
Cincinnati Bengals. They go to 10.
>> Yeah, Cincinnati was going to reach on a
defensive tackle. There was a lot of
talk that maybe that they were going to
look at at Woods from Clemson.
>> Interesting.
>> I think they did reach on a defensive
tackle.
>> Dexter Lawrence. Yeah, they they but
that they they were going to go into
this draft and everybody kind of had a
defensive back there. They were very
talent poor defensively, much like
Dallas was in a lot of areas and people
were thinking, well, they're going to
take a corner. They could take the
safety. But it sounded like to me
talking to some folks that that Peter
Woods was going to be the pick there at
10. And so they went ahead and made the
trade. And now you put the Giants in
that position. Giants I think are going
to go offense, defense, defense,
offense. Uh but uh one way or another,
listen, if they if they don't if they
don't get and I think that at five they
would absolutely take love if he was
there and then that's the one I would
worry about at 10 potential with Downs.
Maybe this is why Dallas is thinking
about if they have to go and they want
to go for a guy like down maybe you have
to get ahead of what uh of what uh the
the New York Giants are doing. If the
Giants take downs at five, does that
take Dallas out of the mix? You know,
maybe there's a couple other opt options
for them on some of these defensive
players.
>> Tommy, do you feel like you got a good
read on where New York could go defense
or offense first or if they could still
not out of the equation, they could take
two defensive guys in those spots?
>> Sure. And there's been a lot of reports
that they like both Sunonny Styles and
Caleb DS from Ohio State. So, if there's
a way where they can get both of those
picks to be the defensive players, I
don't I don't think John Harbaugh's
necessarily upset about that. Um, but
they they've also been connected to
Jordan Tyson, the wide receiver from
Arizona State. So really their options
are open and I think that we talked
about this scenario a couple times. What
Arizona or New Orleans or whoever is at
three does if it is just backto-back
pass rushers. What does Tennessee do
because Jeremiah Low has been tied to
Tennessee a bunch. I think
>> I I have seen Tennessee insiders, no
joke, I'm gonna try and think of every
single player I've seen them tie to the
Titans at some point to this point.
Bane, the majority,
>> Bane, Styles, Love, Tate, uh, who else
have we seen there? I mean, if Reese or
Bailey falls, we've seen them get I've
seen Bane.
>> There's Yeah. Yeah. Bane, Styles, you've
got I mean, they've had they've been all
over the map with And that Bane one was
not from a French person. That was from
one of Tennessee's bigger beat reporters
who had consistently put Bane out there
for a while.
>> Yeah, I kind of feel like that Tennessee
is the team that if Love's on the board,
they're going to take him. I just feel
like that that's going to be the the
pick, especially if all of a sudden
somebody like New Orleans or somebody
trades up the three and Arizona gets out
of there. I I could very well see Love
Love Love could go was going to go with
three spots. He could have gone to
Arizona. He could have gone to uh
Tennessee and then the Giants or all
three opportunities that I know talking
to people around the league the last
couple of days, that's kind of where
they were trying to to to to put love in
in those three positions. Do do you all
feel like you know roughly who the 10
players in the top 10 are going to be?
>> Just depends on the
>> Yeah, just you don't know where they go.
But do you feel cuz for instance, one
name we have not talked about in the top
10 at all, even though I think
everybody's talked about how we all
generally like him. Um but one we
haven't talked about at all that I know
the Giants ESPN reporter said was his
favorite to go 10 was Yani from Penn
State. And so it's like it makes me
wonder, is there anybody that we've had
>> that we think is is a good player,
really good player that we just haven't
been able to find a spot for that maybe
some team just says, "No, we're going to
take him in the top because they're
they're a quality player."
>> I'm surprised that uh I'm surprised with
the thing with Malinoa, how he's gone
from maybe being in the top, you know,
three, you know, maybe you were talking
about him at Arizona to potentially
being down
>> a lot of people have him going at like
11 now.
>> That's what I'm saying. And he went from
being that guy kind of up there a little
bit higher and then now he's it's like a
back drop.
>> Let me ask you how would you feel at 12
>> mount? I I would have I would have no
problem with
>> if you're standing at 12 and the
defenders are gone. Go for it.
>> That's the best lineman in the class.
>> I'll say the name that you hear a little
bit of chatter about and it could be
smoke,
>> but the name you hear a little bit of
chatter about like maybe could end up on
the edges of the top 10 is Kaden
Proctor.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. which
>> I think I I had Detroit trading up for
him when and when I was starting to
think about the spots where people I I
had I had Detroit going from 17 to 11
>> in Miami. Yeah, that's where I that's
where I kind of felt like that Miami
would drop back, but Detroit would go up
there and maybe grab Proctor with that
11th pick.
>> You think it would be Proctor or
Freeling from Georgia?
>> I think it's probably going to be
Proctor is who it would be. It's if you
like Proctor, you like a very specific
type of player and it would make sense
that you would want to like for
instance, I think the Giants
>> look I mean you you you want big guys,
right? Like uh like like you take for
instance, I know the Giants
>> very little has come out of what about
what John Harbaugh's philosophy is going
to be. When you talk to people out
there, one of the things they are
consistently telling you is he wants to
get bigger on both sides of the ball in
the trenches. He wants the defensive
line and the offensive line bigger. So
Proctor like is that just somebody who
like when you're hearing about fringe
top 10 interest is that because some
people think well Proctor could be a guy
that they look at go like let's add some
size here. Um Baltimore historically has
because Harbaugh was there has been a
bigger team.
>> Monroe Freeling also bigger offensive
lineman if you want to try and build
into the trenches there too.
>> Can I ask folks where did you guys stack
Freeling
>> because I he was the he was the third
tackle for me.
>> I have him at 24. He is uh tackle five
for me. He's tackle four for me and he's
just outside the top 20.
>> Four for me, 28 overall. Where where do
we have the Arizona State offensive
tackle?
>> He's my top second round player.
I love
>> I love him.
>> See, I I have him over Freeling. I do
too.
>> I do. I I just the the the first time
that I ever saw Monroe Freeling's name
was Dame Bugler's very first mock draft
and he had him right where you guys were
talking about him at 2526 somewhere
right around there. But I listen for him
to be talked about in the top six I'm
like man they are they are putting a
bunch of air in this guy.
>> He's athletic and he showed that at the
combine but yeah I I agree with you. I
don't think the tape shows top 10. Yeah,
>> it's a draft show tradition that on
night one we have to talk about
offensive linemen for the Dallas
Cowboys, for the guys or the teams in
front of them. Whatever it ends up
being, you're going to have that
conversation throughout. But when we
come back, it's the official start of
the 2026
NFL draft in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
We've got wall-to-wall coverage. All 257
selections will be on the airwaves
throughout the weekend, and it all gets
kicked off in a matter of moments.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> All right, so Nick, tell us about that
Twitter thing again.
>> I'll let Zack Walchuck do that as he
rotates in.
>> There you go.
All right,
>> Nick.
>> Is that the man coming in?
>> I don't know.
>> Yes.
>> I'll go get somebody.com site. Yeah.
Yeah. See you guys in a bit.
>> All right. Good job, gentlemen.
>> Well done.
the
final leadup here for of course one
through 12. We just went through those
picks. Let's talk a little bit here,
Brian and Bobby and as Zach and Vot
rotate in.
Rams at 13, Ravens at 14, Buccaneers at
15, Jets at 16, Lions at 17, Vikings at
18, Panthers at 19, and then the Cowboys
there at the 20th overall pick. any of
those that possibly could be a second
pick lay mine for Dallas to try and
navigate in terms of defensive play.
>> I don't know. I'm taking advantage of
them getting up and I'm moving into this
chair.
>> You're going to move into the chair?
>> I don't know who's going to get the kids
table.
>> Zack. Zach would be good for that one.
>> I like it. Good for you.
>> You've been on here a couple years. What
What draft is this for you?
>> This is four,
>> right? I think. Yeah, because it would
have been
>> Sounds about right.
>> Uh Tyler Smith was the first one I was
on.
>> 23. So yeah, 23 24 25. Yeah. So, it's
been Tyler Smith, Mazy Smith, Tyler
Gayton, and now or Tyler Bson. Oh, wait.
We've done four.
>> I've been on four, so this will be five.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, wow. Time flies.
>> It's tough.
>> So, who are some of the landmines there,
13 through 19 that you could see
possibly taking players that Dallas
would want to see at 20?
>> Let's look here. Let me pull up the the
board as it looks like. Do you got one
of those? Yeah, we got one. Yeah, you
got it.
>> See, the thing about the thing you have
to worry about is like I don't think the
Rams are going to go up,
>> but I think they're taking offensive
players there at Rams.
>> Uh Tampa,
maybe the the Jets that but see what the
Jets do at two.
>> You know, of course, they're probably
going to take a defensive player. I
talked about the Lions going up. I think
Minnesota
>> if you want a corner, the Bucks could
take a corner. Um yeah, Lions, Panthers
on offensive line. Vikings, if you have
not taken like one of these safeties,
let's say you like Theamman, that's been
a threat to take Theamman the whole
time. Yeah.
>> Um, so I think that those would be in
play as guy as people that could take
players from you.
>> We're still live on the air as voters,
>> fellas. Top of the morning. Top of the
morning.
>> Fix your lapel pin there.
>> Oh, pardon me, man. It's nice. I want to
be straight for you.
>> Hey, look, I I am going to take the the
jacket off at some point. I do have a
backup.
>> You're going to You're going to take
what?
>> Just Just Huh?
>> You're going to take what?
>> What' I say?
>> No, you said I didn't hear what you say.
You're going to take what?
>> Take I'mma change clothes like like we
going we going to bring you to take the
jacket off.
>> Oh, at some point I'm going to take the
jacket off. Yeah. And just rock just the
vest. So, I got a backup lapel p. You
y'all can't see. There you go. A backup
lapel pin just in case, man. You know,
we got to coordinate our clothes and our
outfits around here, you fellas. You
feel me?
>> Hey, man. What y'all What y'all doing,
man? Y'all ready to ready to draft, man?
Y'all All right. anything that we say in
the first that that we said in the first
hour that you either disagree with or
wanted to talk about.
>> Uh I am a particular shade, so I was a
little late, so I didn't hear
everything. You know what I'm saying? I
didn't get a chance to listen.
>> He got to talk about it that way.
>> They had to move around and do some
stuff. I just can't sit down and listen.
But I am uh I'm thrilled about this
draft. I'm fascinated with what's going
to happen with the uh with the first
pick, of course, but I think the board
is going to open up with that second
first round pick, of course. I I want to
know is it pass rush going to be
happening later? Is it one of those
quarterbacks that we like? Uh I've been
talking to Brian about this. Are we
talking about DTackle enough? You know
what I mean? Like we got some guys and
some of those guys may not be long-term
guys for the for the Cowboys. I was
like, Brian, are we talking about
DTackle enough? He was like, "No, Vash,
we're not talking about DTackle enough."
I think that could be a surprise. Maybe
not today, but if the right guys there,
I don't see why you can't take a guy
like that.
>> Where would be the earliest that you
would take a defensive tackle? I'll take
Kate McDonald 20 whatever right now at
20 at 20 whatever right now and I'll do
it with a smile and I'll be like all
right whoever is when Quinn comes off
the field or when Kenny comes off the
field you're directly going to be
competing with that character so it
could be uh Jay Towi or something you
know what I mean hey new new
administration guys get moved around all
the time I'm just not opposed to taking
one tick you know what I'm saying
>> he's tonging right
>> will they do the haka for us
>> yeah do do a little dance
>> that's the first thing you said on the
Air waves.
>> First thing
like rip that band-aid off.
>> We're here. We're back.
>> Do a little dance. Do it.
>> Let's do it.
>> I love your tie, by the way.
>> Hey, thank you very much to the
godfather Brian Bratis. He's the one
that hooked me up with the uh the draft
day tie as you can see here. I'll pop
the other way. It's got all the teams on
it, all the logos. I mean, we got old
school Giants, old school Falcons, old
school Bucks, even Redskins.
>> Whoa.
>> Can't say that anymore. Brian, how old
is that tie?
>> Can't say Renior Redskins.
>> It's probably older than you guys. I've
had that for since probably 1990.
>> I was born in 92.
>> Yeah, that ties older than you.
>> Damn, do
>> listen class on radio.
>> The time has come. It is 7:00 central
time, which means the 2026 NFL draft is
moments away from officially getting
underway. and Roger Goodell taking the
stage in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. And
then the Las Vegas Raiders will be on
the clock. It's our second hour of
coverage out of 20 over the weekend
covering pick by pick all the way
through 275 or excuse me 257
selections in the 2026 NFL draft
alongside those of 1053 the fan Brian
Bratis, Bobby Belt, Zack Walchuk. We've
also got Fort Worth Star Telegrams Nick
Harris, DallasCowboys.com's Tom Yarish,
and YouTube superstar Vach Lombardi in
studio for the first time today.
>> Is that the best way I I could describe
it? YouTube superstar global media.
>> Paul know
thank y'all. Thank y'all so much. You
know, it it gets kind of weird here cuz
it's like when I'm here, I'm supposed to
represent what we do here, but I I think
most people would know me from YouTube.
So, I appreciate y'all if y'all watching
right now. So, thank you very much for
that uh for that intro.
>> Hey B, I got a question. Hell yeah. By I
was about competition.
>> How happy are you to to have uh Mike
McCarthy back in this draft?
>> He back. Oh. Oh,
>> he's at the host city.
>> How about I say
>> that's why they picked the place drafted
for us? I would have been a
>> I would have been a little upset
drafting draft for us.
>> A late call as a late pivot.
>> But I I would just have to assume that
uh he didn't do a whole bunch of
research for whoever they about to draft
in Pittsburgh. So, I hope they uh do
well. Shouts out to him. You know,
>> that scouting department better be
ready.
>> Hey, man. I hope they I hope they want
We've got a great one here. I hope they
want no input from their coach, man.
Shouts out to Mike, man.
>> Can I drink one of these like later
>> when we toast the pick at 12 and 20 if
first round picks got chug,
>> but can I take a sip out of it? Yeah,
>> is what I'm saying.
>> Okay. Well, Dallas Cowboys draft
coverage is brought to you by Miller
Light, the only beer the Dallas Cowboys.
It's Miller time.
>> I just want to know, man, cuz they're
sitting in front of me. They they they
they just looking gorgeous. You know
what I mean?
>> Like a pyramid in front of you. I'm just
saying like if it was a pick that I
wouldn't be happy about, they'll just be
right there exactly how they left them.
But if it's I just feel really good
about what's possible to happen tonight
and if it's a pick that's like worth
celebrating, I might drink all these is
what I'm saying.
>> All of them. All of them.
>> All of Unless y'all want to partake or
something.
>> Thanks, man. Give us one just to have
some fun with
>> or like I'm sure these ain't the only
ones in the building. Bean probably got
nine more in the back. Rim Jones in. You
>> might be right. You might be wrong.
We'll talk about it. Assuming assuming
the Cowboys do something that's going to
make me incredibly happy. Go ahead.
>> All right, let's go ahead and hand
things over to the commissioner of the
NFL, Roger Goodell, as we get things
started in the 2026 NFL draft.
>> We send things to the stage to get
things started.
>> PITTSBURGH, HERE WE ARE.
Come on. YOU DO BETTER THAN THAT.
We have over 300,000 PEOPLE. LET'S GO.
HIT YOU.
>> 300,000.
>> There you go.
WELCOME TO THE 2026 NFL DRAFT.
We are proud to be here in a city built
on grit, built on steel, and home of the
one of most dominant franchises in
history.
your sixtime Super Bowl champion
Pittsburgh Steelers.
But tonight, we're going to celebrate
Western Pennsylvania heritage. And as
you can see, I didn't come alone.
Steelers captain, eighttime Pro Bowler,
and defensive player of the year, TJ
Watt.
Hey,
>> we got to sit through this.
>> We do have to sit through it just for a
little bit.
>> It's symbolic
>> and the heart of like lighting the
torch.
>> I just hate when they got All right,
y'all. We got the mayor of Pittsburgh
here to give the
>> 2023 Walter Payeyton NFL man of the
year,
>> Cam Hayward. I just want to say, guys,
>> hey man,
>> take it away, Cam.
PITTSBURGH,
MAKE SOME NOISE.
>> This is Steelers football. Tough,
physical, and built to last. But
everything we do today is built on the
standards set by the legends before us.
Let's bring out the men who paved the
way to greatness.
A Hall of Famer, a true shutdown corner,
A PIECE OF THE STEEL CURTAIN, MEL BLUNT.
>> That was Cam Hayward, by the way, the
defensive tackle as they welcome in Mel
Blunt. He's wearing his gold jacket,
Hall of Fame jacket. One of the few, one
of the few they earned.
>> One of the few not
Super Bowl MVPs
and Oh, there he is. Got it there.
Hines, of course, Hollywood superstar
from the Dark Knight.
>> L only got in the Hall of Fame for two
catches.
>> Not technically.
>> And now we got to talk quarterbacks. Two
quarterbacks,
>> two wins, one standard, Super Bowl
champions, and legends of the city.
Big Ben walking up to the stage. There's
Mason.
>> I think he's the next one.
>> Yeah, they're going to have
>> Terry.
>> There's Terry Bradshaw.
>> Rogers come out.
>> This would be a way to
>> This would be the way to do it.
>> This is if you wanted to do that draft.
>> Yeah. Just have him walk out here and
say, "I'm coming back."
>> And your 2026 starting quarterback and
then just have him walk out.
>> Just run it back. I know. Ryan brought
us six minutes. He ready to get going.
He don't like all the catchment.
I mean, we're just waiting for the
Raiders. 6 minutes from the top of the
hour. We've already gone past 6 minutes
of this.
>> Are the Raiders even on the clock?
>> No. No, they haven't opened.
>> We have a shorter clock this year, by
the way. We haven't talked about that.
>> That is a good conversation. We'll talk
about that here in a moment.
>> Pittsburgh,
this is a moment you all been waiting
for.
>> Yins ready.
>> Yins. Oh my god. the ines.
>> The 2026 NFL draft is officially open.
The Las Vegas Raiders are on the clock.
>> All right.
Wild crowd.
>> Go. It is a big crowd.
>> That is massive. Holy cow.
>> 300,000 is probably accurate of what
Roger just said. It's It's big time. All
right. You just talked about it. This is
a new clock this year that the NFL is
going to. It's shorter, more compact.
How does that change things from a
drafting? Yeah. I mean, it's 8 minutes
instead. What, Brian? Back in the day,
first round for you guys was 15, right?
>> 15 minutes. Yeah.
>> So, I mean, and then they had brought it
down to 10 and now they're down to
eight. So, uh, it's going to be
>> more commercials.
>> It's going to be tightened up a little
bit. I I assume this will more impact
trade talks than anything else.
>> I hope so. Yeah. The the thing back in
the day though, if if you go back when I
ran the 98 draft in Philadelphia, if you
go back and look at the quickest pick
that was made in the first round, your
Philadelphia Eagles with Brian Bratis at
the helm. I'm like, listen, hey, this we
know who we're taking. We're taking
>> pitch clock brought us.
>> Yeah, let's let's go. I mean, let's turn
this card in. Phone phone don't ring. I
Votch is right. I don't have time for
all this. Let's start drafting. Let's
start, you know, and I know the NFL
likes to have a big production of it
all, but yeah, let's get to start
picking these players and stuff. And I
think the clock will. I mean, you can't
wait late in the clock to try. And I
think that's why some teams maybe have
some pre-deals done. Yeah, I think if
players if players are there that like,
hey, if our guys there, be ready. We're
going to call. And I think I think some
teams are alerted and and we should be
ready for that.
>> I think when you ask around the league,
that's the area where you've seen the
most shift probably
>> just with this clock is that it's it's
caused some teams to maybe just do a
little extra ground work on trades
potentially in advance of the day. So,
it's like, all right, we already kind of
have a starting point of where we're
going to where we're going to look at
this and then they can execute it from
there when they're on the clock. I know
we talked about it a little bit in the
pre-show, but Zack, where do you expect
that first trade to possibly happen?
Where do you feel? Because right now the
Raiders are on the clock. They're going
to probably take Fernando Menosza, we
would assume, the quarterback out of
Indiana, and then the draft starts at
two. Is that as early as we could see a
trade?
>> Uh, I mean, I don't I think the Jets are
going to probably stay in pick. Now, the
Jets could jet and then they end up
taking a player that it's not Reese or
Bailey and maybe it's Carnell Tate or
it's Sunonny Styles or they make a
really surprised pick. But I think
Arizona's made no surprises that they
want to bail out of there. And I don't
think that Jeremiah Love is a pick that
they really want to make. If you look at
the running back position, they bring
back James Connor. They drafted Trey
Benson from Florida State in the second
round a couple years ago. They're kind
of set. I mean, they just signed Tyler
Algier. Like, is Jeremiah Love an
upgrade over all those guys? Yes. But is
it a massive need for them? No. They
need an offensive lineman, and maybe
there's just not one there at three that
they feel comfortable taking. So, they
want to bail. It just depends on do they
get the value for the pick. I think you
know Nick mentioning New Orleans earlier
makes a ton of sense for me. That is a
front office that has been very
aggressive in their history. Kansas City
going up for a differencemaking edge
rusher makes a lot of sense for me as
well. So I I'd actually be stunned if
Arizona does stay in pick at three. I
think they are the team that is going to
bail out.
>> Brian, do you agree with that?
>> Absolutely. I think there's some teams
you got to look at here. Arizona could
be I think Arizona is going to trade.
Tennessee is a team. Uh Cleveland's a
team, the Commanders are a team, New
Orleans, obviously we talked about them
going up and Kansas City. So yeah, we're
in a situation right now that where
maybe some like we've talked about, if
there's some players on the board, then
you're going to see some of these trades
fire off and some of these teams are are
going to start to talk about getting out
of there and I think they're going to do
it in pretty quick fashion.
>> What do the Joneses always say about
being the team that picks up the phone
on a trade? Generally, you're the one
that loses when when you pick up the
phone,
>> which
>> Jerry said it in the pre-draft press
conference. He said, "Usually those
calls are better when they're coming in,
>> which I think I should be clear on this
because I I think this is what they mean
by it. I guess I should totally fill in
the gaps for them, but I think what
they're talking about is when you are on
the clock."
>> Yeah.
>> Like like they're talking about you
don't call to go back because that's
where you lose. I think they just
generally think the team that calls is
the one that wants to go up. So if
that's us and we want to go up, we place
the call. Cuz if somebody's calling from
back, they're going, "Hey, will you come
up here and take our pick?" that's a
losing position, which I can see 100%.
Um, because of that, Arizona has been
really hard up to get out of that
position. Arizona has called several
teams. Arizona, I believe, has called
this team a couple times and ask Dallas
like, "Hey, would you want to come up
for that?" So, I'm going to be very
interested that if they do move, what
they move for?
>> So, you just talked about it. What would
it take for them to move up and to get
on the phone themselves? Or it does that
change the maneuvering if it's a trade
possibility that's already set in place?
Because like you said, if you're on the
clock, that value goes down if you're
trying to get out of that pick and pull
the parachute. But if you've already had
a trade talked about and agreed upon,
gentleman's agreement.
>> Yeah.
>> Does the value stay relatively the same?
>> Right. Like it it may shift things. I
mean, we'll we'll have to see if that's
the way that it kind of plays out. I
would guess that it's still I guess
you're not going to get quite as good a
value if you're the one who's been
calling so frequently, which it seems
like Arizona has been. It seems like
whatever deal Arizona gets done, if they
get one done, it feels like one they
probably prompted the discussion because
it felt like they were talking to a lot
of different teams and so
>> or at least word got out to that team
and that was the call
>> 100%.
>> Yeah. Votch, who would you go up for?
Let's say if you were in the war room
for Dallas,
>> who would be worth trading up for and
how far would you go?
>> I mean, you want to get one of those uh
big six is what I've been calling them.
You know, one of the edge rushers, the
linebackers, the corner or the safety
there. It just kind of depends on how
far you want to move up. If you don't
want to give a waste, please
>> can we outline that? Big six. Can we
>> Okay, so uh David Bailey, so Bailey,
Reese, DS, Delane, Bane, Styles.
>> Okay, those are your big defensive
players.
>> Defensive players. The Cowboys were
terrible last year on defense. They're
not I don't think they would move up for
a wide receiver. I saw that online
somewhere. I I don't think they'll
they'll be moving up to do any of that
if if they do move up, but it just
depends on are they comfortable giving
up a three. Are they comfortable giving
up a four and a five? I've heard that
they don't want to get out of the the
first round. The Raiders on the clock.
Go ahead.
>> Sorry to interrupt you. Here is Roger
Gell with the first pick of the 2026 NFL
draft. Tyson
>> with the first pick in the 2026 NFL
draft.
The Las Vegas Raiders select, Fernando
Mendoza,
quarterback Indiana.
>> And now the NFL draft is underway
because that was the one pick that I
think everybody had right on their mock
draft. They get one across the board.
We're going to go ahead and step aside.
Fernando Mendoza, first pick off the
board. quarterback out of Indiana to the
Las Vegas Raiders first overall. You're
listening to the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, back here on the internet
side of things, we're taking a look at
Fernando Mendoza's tape, but Bobby, you
noticed something in the war room there
that we probably should talk about here,
and it's part of why we wanted to take
the early break, just to give us a
little bit of window. Well, and it's
it's one of those things where a lot of
times it can mean nothing, but you're
always watching any sort of change in
the war room or anything else. I do
think it's fascinating that Will
Mccclelay just has his hand like on the
phone and it's it's not moving. He's
just got he's got his right hand just
placed on the phone looking at some
chart or something else. So maybe it's a
a case of they're just working ahead on
on some other things or or they're
fielding calls for, you know, trade back
or trade up. But but it's just it's and
now he's out of the room as we cut back
to the war room.
>> Could he be could they be a part of the
Arizona trade? That's what I'm just
saying. I It's getting close to
Arizona's pick. So, him just having his
hand on the phone. He was never on the
phone, but him having his hand on the
phone was interesting to me because he
generally is not going to just sit there
with it on the his hand out there just
non-stop for four hours.
>> Absolutely. They're 12th on the on the
clock. And
>> there is no Jerry, there is no Steven,
there is no Will right now.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, only only one of the
big names is Brian Shottenheimimer
there. But I will say though, Kyle, far
as teams moving around in the first
round, I I think it depends on when
these runs are going to happen, right?
So you got three top tier receivers. If
you a team that wants to get one of
those guys, and you know that's Tyson
Lemon or or Tate, if one of those guys
go, you're like, "All right, maybe we
should we really want one of these
guys." If two of those guys go, you're
like, "All right, let me jump in front
of this real fast." Uh we saw in some of
these mocks, uh DJ mocked, um yesterday,
there was seven offensive tackles
yesterday. When does that run happen?
When does the first wave of that happen?
Is it going to happen all at one time?
Tackle tax gets kind of weird. So, it
may be a tackle, let's just say Blake
Miller or something like that, who may
be talked about as like like a late
round tackle, but if a team loves them
at 10, 11, 13, whatever, you know, that
that that may make someone want to jump
up and move. So, it depends on who's up
there and uh who's been off the board.
>> Brian, who would you go for up there?
>> I would I would think if you're if if
you're talking you're talking about go
to Arizona or
>> Yeah, if you're going that way, I think
it's got to be right. Yeah, you've got
to you've got to look at Absolutely. You
got to think about the guys like Vach
was talking about the big six and just
pick it out. If you if you think it's
going to be Reese, uh, Styles, DS, I
think that all those guys would probably
be in play right there. Whoever the Jets
don't take, then that's kind of where
you're at. But I I think that those
those are the three names I would look
at on my personal board. The way I would
stack them, Downs would be number one
for the guys that I would I would try
and get there. Let me ask y'all. Uh, you
know, the Cowboys haven't really put a
bunch into linebacker this off season
>> or anything really.
>> You know, I mean, I think they put a
little more into DB than they've done
linebacker. I mean, they just kind of
looked at linebacker and just looked
away from linebacker, right? Does that
>> I think they tried but you're right.
>> They made some attempts but nothing
really got invested in it. Like they
tried but it didn't happen. Like does
that boost styles up their board or if
if if they had an option between let's
just say Styles, Downs, Delane. Yeah,
they need linebacker, but if they have
those other guys ranked higher, would
they take those guys or would they take
the linebacker that they need?
>> I think that goes back to the outside in
conversation that we were talking about
in the pre-show, I'm interested to see
what you think.
>> I mean, I think that if you're going up
to three, it's Arll Reese because I
think Arll Ree feels that. I think he
fills your linebacker need if you want
to play him off ball similar to how you
did Micah Parsons to start his career.
Now, I think Arll Ree has shown more
than Micah did at Penn State his ability
to rush the passer, but I think he's
actually a better linebacker prospect in
my opinion than what Micah was coming
out of Penn State. I think Arll Ree as a
freak athlete is an absolute star that
I'd absolutely move up and get at three
and that fills a hole for the Cowboys.
>> Who do you have above or you you just
said Ree, would you rather or did you
stack Ree higher than you did Bailey?
Reese out of Ohio State, Bailey out of
Texas.
>> Yeah, I mean I've got Downs as my number
one player, but I have Ree over Bailey.
And for the Cowboys, Reese makes sense.
>> Yeah.
>> Downs is your number one overall player.
>> Number one overall player.
>> I could go there, too.
>> Reese is one for me. Downs is two for
me.
>> Uh Ree is one and down is two.
>> Okay.
>> So, we right there. We're right there.
>> One pick has been announced. Fernando
Mendoza, the quarterback and the Heisman
Trophy winner from Indiana. off the
board of the Raiders with the first
overall selection. The Jets on the clock
and their pick is in at second overall.
The pick has not been announced quite
yet. If that's the case, that means the
Arizona Cardinals, a team thought to
possibly be trading back, is on the
clock as we hand things back over to
Commissioner Roger Goodell with the Jet
selection at number two.
pick of this draft is
>> with the second pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the New York Jets select, David
Bailey,
>> linebacker, Texas Tech.
>> First edge rusher off the board, the
Texas Tech.
>> Sorry, Bobby.
>> Linebacker or excuse me, Texas Tech edge
rusher David Bailey goes to the Jets.
>> Ian Rapaort just worded it very
interestingly. He goes, "The Jets have
made rather than traded the pick. They
take David Bailey,
which makes me wonder if they were
fielding calls."
>> If they were talking about it, maybe
we're sitting here talking about three
as the first possibility. Maybe two was.
>> David Bailey is awesome, by the way. He
He is a total monster. Um I I mean
that's somebody who he was like the
first player I watched during this whole
process and just violent understands how
to rush the passer sets up you know
every move that he has in a pass rush
plan is setting up the next plays with a
really high motor. The biggest way he
gets himself in trouble a lot of times
is playing so aggressively that he
sometimes overpursues. Yep. Um but man
he is he is a lot of fun to watch.
That's somebody that if Dallas had the
number one pick in the draft, that is
who I would want them to pick would be
D. That's who I would have been all over
is picking David Bailey.
>> Bendy, bursty, flattens. Well, and I
just value dudes that just know how to
rush, that just know how to get sacks.
I'm not one of these people that will,
you know, think that a player that
doesn't get sacks in college will all of
a sudden learn how to get sacks in the
league. I'm just not one of those guys.
David Bailey is a dude that knows how to
get sacks in college. So, I would assume
that he will get sacks in the league.
>> Super productive player. The spin move
for him is absolutely nasty. I think
you're absolutely right with the angles
he takes. There's not a lot of wasted
steps with David Bailey. The motor he
plays with keeping his chest clean. The
Jets got a heck of a player. I mean, I
would have taken Reese over Bailey
personally. But if you just want a
product that you know what you're
getting, best pure pass rusher in the
draft right now is David Bailey from
Texas Tech.
>> But Zach, you know what though? This is
what I think it came down to and this is
what I think the conversation about Ree
is. I'm very high on Reese, but some
teams may be like, "Okay, well, he's not
a linebacker V. He's just a pass rush
for me. Some other teams will be like,
"Well, Vach, I don't think he's a pass
rusher at all. I think he's only a
linebacker. He doesn't know how to pass
rush just yet." So, if let's just say
that the Jets, cuz we don't know. Let's
just assume that the Jets have Reese,
you know, just he's purely edge guy.
Bailey would be a better edge guy than
Ree is, right? You would only put Reese
over Bailey if you're banking on the
upside of him being a linebacker and a
pass rush guy like like I am. So, I
guess that makes sense for them if
that's the case.
>> So, pick number one was of course
Mendoza. Pick number two is Bailey.
Arizona on the clock at the moment. Any
word here, Bobby, on what they could
possibly be doing with this election,
>> trying to trade the hell out of there.
That's what they're trying to
>> They're definitely trying to move back,
>> which I I'm I'm going to guess they're
going to find somebody to to dance with
them. It's just going to be a matter of
who. The the buzz heading into today
seemed like it was New Orleans would be
potentially the trade partner. Yeah,
that's what everybody that I was talking
to on the way in was talk was saying
that that New Orleans was they had a
trade already
>> if uh and ready to go. This was this was
several hours ago. Again, we're talking
about teams that are preparing uh to,
you know, to make these picks quick and
they get the trades in and out pretty
quick, too. You don't want to be waiting
around on this one. A lot going on. And
the Saints were the team that I was
hearing was going to be aggressive in
this draft. They're having some sort of
discussion in the room right now. It
looks like Jerry and Will are talking
about something.
>> Not like super animated, but
>> Bobby, you was you was noticing. You
were just quietly noticing and Will kind
of did it again. What you think will
hovering over the phone for? Because if
it's a if it's a trade conversation,
wouldn't the Joneses have that
conversation?
>> I don't think I don't think it's like a
Cardinal. I think it's more just
they're prepared to to make a deal that
maybe they've already like, hey, this is
contingent on how things play out here,
then then we'll make a deal. I think
it's more just sitting around waiting
for potentially to pick up the call to
say we're on or we're off is is what
that could be.
>> And to this point, I think they thought
it would go Mendoza Bailey. If let's say
Arizona does pick here at three, do you
think they're going Arll Reese out of
Ohio State or is it somebody else? It
looks like
>> they're clapping.
>> Arizona is clapping.
>> But are they clapping on a trade or a
pick?
>> Or a pick.
>> Could be interesting.
>> I mean, I think that Arizona needs to
take an offensive lineman. I I would
take Francis Malinoa from Miami. I I
don't But Jeremiah Love could just be
the highest rated player on their board.
He's my number two player, so I could
totally understand it. If you're going
to stay true to it, and you're not
window dressing, as Brian would say,
then you take Jeremiah Love. Uh, but I
think Arll Reese makes more sense for
them than Love would. I would still lean
an offensive lineman
>> and remember they did hire the Rams
offensive coordinator Michael Lafleur as
their head coach. So an offensive guy
>> up front Laflur as he would yeah as
Votch would say
>> 115 remaining on the TV side for
Arizona's pick. No indication on whether
or not the pick is in.
>> They're picking
>> or if they trade it. Oh,
>> they're picking.
>> Wow.
>> That's is that the first shock of the
draft is that they are picking here?
>> Uh yeah, that's a surprise.
Yeah, they were they could say the the
last few days have been nothing but
trade back, trade back, trade back. It
was I mean I was talking to people in
Arizona and they were saying offensive
line, defensive line, you know, they
were not talking about really love at
all. A lot of teams had love there.
We'll see what the pick is, but uh they
were they were the one team that was
really anxious to get out of there.
>> Do you think it's because they didn't
expect Reese to be there? like, you
know, maybe they weren't going to take
Bailey, you know, maybe they were fine
trading away from Bailey, but hey,
Arville Ree is here. We may have him
rank much higher. Should we just take
Reese here, you know, as opposed to
trading back?
>> Yeah. I think it's they might just not
have gotten the offer that they wanted.
They might gotten have received the
quality free
>> everyone.
>> They were calling everybody.
>> Yeah. I mean, if they're staying and
picking, I I just don't think they got
the value for the pick and they just
said, "You know what? We love whoever
we're taking enough uh to go ahead and
just stay here and pull the trigger."
All indications were if they stayed
there it would be Jeremiah Love. I just
don't think that pick makes as much
sense for them.
>> And you said offensive line first
offensive line. Absolutely.
>> That's what that's what they the people
in the in the building at at Arizona.
They were because I was asking about the
whole thing with love, you know, and and
>> you know and a lot of people were saying
that hey this might be a thing where
Michael Bidwell the owner got involved
and was thinking about butts and seats.
Maybe maybe that that Love was a guy
more so than say taking Ma Noah here or
one of these offensive tackles.
>> All right, here's the selection. Roger
Goodell walking to the stage.
Celdendrick Faulk
into their time on the clock. Ty Simpson
>> could be
>> with the third pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Arizona Cardinals select,
Jeremiah.
>> Wow, they took him. They took him dead.
>> No. That's the first time that Arizona
has taken a running back in the first
round since Beanie Wells back in 2009.
>> That's significant. And that was at 31
overall. This is at number three.
>> Jeremiah Love, best running back by a
wide margin in this NFL draft.
>> Pie Wells has had some great verses over
the years.
>> He's better. He's better than Wells.
He's much
>> Oh, no. That's Pin. Never mind.
>> No, they got a hell of a player with
Jeremiah Smith with love. He is a
mismatch problem. I mean, to me, I I do
think that the Jir Gibbs comps, I can
see that with the explosiveness, the
ability to catch the football out of the
back field. I mean, he made a one-handed
snag in the&m game that was absolutely
phenomenal. He's probably got some
untapped potential when it comes to
being able to be a receiver, but the the
explosiveness he has, the ability to run
between the tackles, fight for extra
yards. He he's a tremendous player. I
mean, this definitely helps you
offensively if you're just looking for
good football players. But I I wonder
how much they considered trying to even
go with Malinoa here. If there's an
offensive lineman they had graded
higher, maybe it's Feno, maybe it's
Yawani, whoever it might be, because
it's just you you you have capable
runners on this roster right now. Who's
blocking for him?
>> Yeah. Who did you have graded higher,
Brian? Ashton Genty last year coming out
of Boise State or Jeremiah Love out of
Notre Dame?
>> Well, Love was my second best player on
my board and I would have taken Ashton
Genty over him.
>> Wow. is what I would have
>> which is an indication of the skill
level of the draft at least the top end
of it
>> right
>> but for him to go three and remember
Genty went six to the Raiders and a lot
of individuals in the NFL draft
community thought that was high for the
pick even though Ashton Genty was a
phenomenal player and a great prospect
>> I think this is great news by the way
for Dallas
>> that was going to be my next question
because now Arll Reese is still on the
board Titans are on the clock at four
that was really where Jeremiah Love was
most popularly mocked where Does
Tennessee go now at four?
>> Well, that's Yeah, that's I think that
Tennessee can go a couple
>> Tennessee has been one of the big points
where everybody thinks like the draft
kind of turns on them. And so I I think
it's they've done a pretty good job of,
as a lot of times happens, you get new
staffs in somewhere and local beat
reporters who are going to be on the
ground and have a good vibe for where
people are going. It's a new staff that
they don't necessarily have
relationships with yet. So, I think it's
been really murky as to which direction
they could go. But I mean, it's been
talked about styles.
>> Um, Bane has been talked about here.
>> That's the one that's the one when you
when you the one that would be
surprising to me
>> would be the Bane one.
>> Yeah. I would be stunned if they went
Bane, but that was what something that a
couple that Paul Kowarski who has
covered the Titans for a long time.
Kowarski had put Bane there several
times.
>> Yeah. even even late too when the bank
conversation cooled off over the final
let's say month of the draft process he
was still one that was staying and
mocking him to four overall to the
Titans
>> now was that in the thought process that
love was off the board and that Ree is
still there
>> um
>> maybe in certain
>> so I I think Ree was not on I think Ree
and Bailey were off on most of these
mocks where he had been projecting Bane
for and so obviously it was like oh
That's the third edge rusher.
>> Um, I will say it's it's odd. Mike Sando
had an article in the Athletic about six
weeks ago where two executives at the
time after the combine had projected
they thought two separate ones had
thought the Titans would take Faulk at
four, which sounds wild, but who has
Faulk most consistently been compared to
from last year. Mico Williams,
>> Michael Williams was a 49ers pick last
year and that's a 49er staff that's in
Tennessee now. That would be incredible
to have to have Faulk go number four and
now Reese is there at five. Downs and
Styles survived. Delane's still there.
Go ahead, get Kendrick Faulk off the
board here at four.
>> And mind you, I love Kendrick Faulk. I'm
just fearful of Kendrick Faulk at 12
basically. You know what I mean? But if
somebody love Kel Faulk at four, I love
y'all for taking Kel F. Hey man, knock
yourself out. Knock yourself out, man.
What's the possibility of another
offensive player? If they were leaning
toward Jeremiah Love at three, where
could they go outside of it? Because you
talked about the tackles. Do they really
need offensive line help? They've
invested
>> quite a bit up and JC Laam playing
tackle right now.
>> So, they're they're probably fine at
tackle.
>> They're set at tackle for the most part.
>> They're fine at tackle. Yeah.
>> So, does that mean a a skilled player
could be in play? And then if that's the
case, is it too high?
>> I'm looking at their wide receivers.
They got uh Calvin really last year.
They drafted Ellio Manor from Stanford
and they got they just signed Wandel
Robinson. So
>> he was a draft show darling for a little
bit of time. I Manor was
>> for sure. For sure. May maybe they go
defense. May maybe they you know maybe
they go defense. I'm looking at their
their corners and they got Cardell Flat
and Alante Taylor. So Konsor the lane
maybe. I don't know. But uh it'll it'll
definitely be
>> Jam McCoy.
>> That definitely be
>> just go ahead and get that one out of
the way.
>> Jam McCoy. Yeah, that would be
interesting at the fourth overall pick.
For those on the radio side, Fernando
Mendoza goes number one overall
quarterback Indiana to the Las Vegas
Raiders. The Jets take edge rusher from
Texas Tech, David Bailey at two. The
Cardinals take Jeremiah Love, running
back from Notre Dame at three. The
Tennessee Titans are on the clock,
followed by the New York Giants, the
Cleveland Browns, the Washington
Commanders, the Saints, the Chiefs, the
Giants at 10 again, and then the
Dolphins and Cowboys at 12th overall as
the pick is in now for Tennessee.
>> I just want the chaos, boys.
>> Expect the unexpected in this draft.
>> This could be chaos depending on where
it happens because I would argue
Jeremiah Love was pretty much the
thought here at four.
>> Yeah. I mean, maybe they stay with
offense. I mean, who would be your best
offensive player? I mean, my top
receiver is Lemon. I've got Tate at two.
>> Offensive line.
>> The offensive line.
>> Malo would be a great pick for them.
>> Here's Roger Goodell heading to the
podium with the Titans pick. Fourth
overall.
>> With the fourth pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Tennessee Titans select
Cardell
>> T.
This good news. This is good news so
far. me. This is perfect.
>> All right,
>> this is perfect for
>> if we're going to get through pick five
and Arll Reese is still there. I'm
picking up a phone.
>> You got one more landmine and that's a
conversation.
>> Well, and there were some reports that
the Cowboys and Giants had.
>> Now, I don't know if it's true.
>> I mean, that's an indivision type of
deal. Cowboys have done this before
though,
>> two weeks ago.
>> Yeah.
>> Where that that kind of lofted up that
conversation.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. I mean, look, if
the Giants want now, I mean, I think if
you're the Giants, are you really going
to pass on Arbell Reese?
>> Go offensive line, dude.
>> They need it. I mean, they could use a
lot of they absolutely need a guard
>> cuz they have rushers. Like, if they if
they think that Reese is a rusher, then
they may not because they have rushers.
Sure. They got they have a ton of
rushers.
>> Just go get Matt with Noah, dude. And
just let him let just just let
>> just keep the offensive run going.
>> Just let Reese fall.
>> Just take Tyson. You just had a wide
receiver go off the board. Do you think
Tyson's making
>> Oh, hell no. Take Lemon.
>> Go. I like Bobby. I don't know why. I
don't know why y'all are wishing for
like take wish for F. Take Lemon. Take
take CJ Parker right now.
>> Why would Cardell Tate be the pick here
at four for the Titans? Why is he this?
>> Because he cold blooded. Catch
everything. And if you worried about
your quarterback being accurate, uh
Cardell Tate catches those. Uh if you uh
worried about your quarterback, you
know, making your wide receivers
catching tight windows, Carell Tate does
that fantastically.
>> He's so safe.
>> He's so He's so
>> He is to me the guy he reminded me of
the most was uh Calvin Ridley. And I
remember I remember Calvin Ridley felt
very very safe.
>> Now he's teammates with him, right?
>> Uh yes, he's still in Tennessee. He is
short hands, vertical ball, medium ball,
whatever you want to do. Slant guy,
whatever.
>> Super smooth.
>> That's the conversation then. If you're
saying, "Oh, he's so safe." This is a
draft where safe almost automatically,
>> right,
>> is well, especially the top 10.
>> Yeah. You know, that's the thing. You
just do not want to make one of these
mistakes and and reach for a guy. I
mean, this guy is You guys are right. I
mean, this guy is so smooth the way I
mean, you know, he he just doesn't drop
the ball. I mean, he can get down the
field. They
>> we've seen him like if you watch the
Texas game, he had a great adjusting
catch on a on a deep ball, the body
control. Um, you know, there's a lot of
confidence in the way that this guy
plays. But, uh, I mean, the when you
watch him, the intermediate stuff, I
think he just thrives down the field,
intermediate, the size that he's got. I
mean, that's a that's a good looking
player right there running routes.
>> Yeah, he wins at every level and he is
quarterback friendly and and that helps
when you've got a second year
quarterback in Cam Ward. Let's go ahead
and try and get him some more weapons. I
can understand the thinking there in
taking a Carnell Tate.
>> Not to mention, you you have invested up
front on the offensive line
>> trying to protect your secondyear number
one overall pick from a year ago in Cam
Ward. M you give him a weapon that can
get coached up by another similar but
veteran weapon with Calvin Ridley. I get
it. I don't know why the thought process
was anything other than Tate in certain
situations. It still feels high just
because of the other names that were on
the board because of Arl Ree and best
player available. But maybe Tennessee is
looking at it and saying not only does
he fill a under the radar need for us,
but he also is the best player we have
too. Big five is intact, man. As a as as
Cowboy fans listening right now online,
on the radio, whatever, your big five
>> only one off the board.
>> We're looking really good right now. Uh
Daniel Daniel Jeremiah has Sunny Styles
going four to the to the Titans. So if
if Tate goes here, we just survive one
more pick with Styles. So we're just
hoping for the Giants to go offensive
line here like they should. I wonder
what the neighbors injury means for
>> We got We got a trade at six. Sher says
the Browns are trading six to the
Chiefs.
Wow.
>> So maybe maybe they know that Reese is
going to be there at six and the Giants
aren't taking him. Or do they want
>> the Chiefs have been really hot on Fono
and Tyson?
>> Yeah. Offensive line. They need and wide
receiver.
>> Browns have been threatening to take
Fondo. Does your does your wide receiver
run happen here? You know what I'm
saying? Or or happen soon. So, you know,
I don't know. And if you're Dallas,
you're sitting there and the two most
mocked trade possibilities.
>> Yeah.
>> Just made a deal with each other.
>> Dallas was talking with Cleveland or not
maybe talking, but the talk around
Cowboys fans
>> Yeah.
>> and draft fans was Dallas could trade
with Cleveland because the math works
out.
>> Yeah.
>> Dallas could trade to nine with Kansas
City because the math works out. Now
Kansas City is trading with Cleveland.
that messes up maybe both scenarios for
>> so this is uh Ian Raport says it is 649
74 and 148
>> oh okay so that is
>> Wow would that be a slight overpay from
Kansas City
>> that's Kansas City going up three spots
and giving up a third and a fifth I
believe
>> it's not bad to go get your guy at all
>> I got a third
>> yeah that's not bad let me keep 20 I got
a third to go get honestly just in
cowboy land nothing stopping you from
calling the Browns at 9 like, "Hey,
man."
>> I don't think you need to.
>> I think it it might stop you though if
you don't want to give up an extra If
you don't want to give up an extra f if
you don't want to give up 20.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Like it helped to go KC and just do the
swap
>> with Cleveland. Cleveland's not going to
give you,
>> you know, they're not going to go 9 and
24, I wouldn't think, for 20 and 12.
>> And remember the talk around Cleveland
was they wanted more picks.
>> They wanted more. They got darts at the
dart board. They have that now. and they
only go back three spots and they've got
two more opportunities later in the
draft to make a selection. The pick is
in for the Giants at 5. We'll announce
this and then we'll take a break and
then we'll kind of break down what is
happening at six. Moving on as now the
Kansas City Chiefs are picking at 6. The
Browns will then pick at 9ine. Those two
flop.
>> That's kind of jarring to uh to a
Cowboys fan base, Brian, that's been
waiting at both of those spots to
possibly make a move.
>> Yeah. you're thinking about maybe that
Kansas City that was a spot where you
can get up to and then it kind of worked
with them Dallas picking at nine and
then them picking you know in the back
end at 29.
>> It's about even on the trade chart by
the way for that Cleveland trade that
that's almost an exact point match.
>> Okay, Bob, let me ask you something just
in just in Cowboy land. I'm a I'm a big
fan of yours. I always listen to you.
You always talk about Washington being
the team that is going to go offense.
Like they just they just feel like they
should go wide receiver. Well, they were
they were really big on love and tape.
>> So, they're gone. They're gone.
>> So, are they a threat to one of your big
five men?
>> Styles. The Styles are down.
>> This is Yeah. Styles to me that every
everybody in Washington was kind of
talking.
>> There was a lot of buzz that Dan Quinn
like Sunny Styles.
>> This is a Dan Quinn thing. Yeah.
>> Sunny Styles too big to play lineback
for Dan Quinn
>> because he because of Bobby Wagner. No,
>> he's just too
>> how short he was.
>> He's gonna play safety.
>> Dan Dan Quinn like his linebacker is
more two 215ish 210ish. Yeah, whatever.
Styles is a big linebacker for them.
>> Be playing downhill too big for
what you got, Bob. You made a face.
>> As long as the Giants don't take downs
here, I think you're in a great spot,
fellas.
>> As the Giants don't take because if they
take a defensive player that's not
downs, then you would anticipate them to
go offense at 10.
>> Yes, absolutely.
>> So, that's another offensive player off
the board.
>> Yep. Yep. And I think the Kansas City is
going to go offense at six. That's where
Tyson's probably in play for if you're
talking about the Giants at
>> especially if Kansas City goes on. What
if Maloa gets to him at 10,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> I think this is falling really nice for
you.
>> All right, here is the Giants selection.
Roger Goodell walking to the stage with
a couple of Giants fans at pick number
five.
In partnership with the Tragedy
Assistance Program for Survivor, TAPS,
one of the NFL Salute to Service
partners, we are honored to recognize
the surviving family of United States
Army Major Paul C. Vulki.
Major Vuli sustained tragic fatal
injuries while deployed in Afghanistan.
He is survived by his spouse Tracy and
their two sons, Andrew and Benjamin.
Major Vulki was raised in the Hudson
Valley and was a lifelong fan of the New
York Giants, a tradition he proudly
passed on to his sons. Bokei family,
take it away.
With the fifth overall pick of the 2026
NFL draft, the New York Football Giants
select
>> Arll Reese, linebacker from the
>> They made the right pick.
>> That's a good pick. I mean, that was the
best player left on I mean for them. If
they didn't want to go downs because of
the safety value, I would take downs
over Ree, but Reese kind of makes sense
as a Giant, man.
>> Reese and Carter's insane. That's going
to be wild.
>> Well, now Kavon Tibido and
>> probably trade.
>> Does Dallas need to take a tackle at 12?
>> You got you got to face them twice a
year now. And not to mention you got to
see Philadelphia and whatever Washington
wants to do at seven. Tell me a little
bit about Arvel Reese, Brian.
>> Yeah, I'll tell you what. But I mean,
when you start to talk about there's
this this one of these players that when
you watch him play his there's so much
like a little bit of some rawness to
him, but the position, but when you
watch the chase, when you watch the
ability to play with his hands, you
watch with the length, the rare size,
his ability to to get off blocks, to put
pressure on blockers right away, the
explosiveness that he plays with, and
his ability just to close. When you get
when you see him in space, you see him
really running. People, ball carriers
have a hard time getting away from this
guy with the way he plays.
>> All right, we'll continue breaking down
Arville Ree to the Giants at pick number
five. When we come back, the Kansas City
Chiefs, a trade with the New Orleans
Saints. They are on the clock at sixth
overall. We are five out of 257 down in
the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
Radio Network and DallasCowboys.com.
All right, back here on the
DallasCowboys.com side of things, taking
a look at Arll Reese to the New York
Giants. So, that's I love the pick for
them.
>> It's a great pick. Now, does that take
them out as as a defensive player or at
an of a defensive player at 10?
>> Yeah, I think it'll depend like let's
say Kansas City is moving up to go get
Jordan Tyson here. How does the how do
the Giants feel about the other
receivers? If Yani I I I think Minoa or
Yawani should both be there or one of
them at least will make it. It depends
on if you know if Tyson's there I think
he definitely would be the pick at 10. I
know Jordan Renan was linking him uh to
the Giants and he's been really spot on.
But I mean you just look at when the
Giants have been successful in winning
championships. It's along the defensive
line and now you've got your core
nucleus in place with Abdel Carter and
Arville Ree and it stinks because it's
it's it's in the division and you don't
want as a Cowboy fan the Giants to be
good but you are getting back to their
bread and butter. When you think of
Giant football it's we're going to win
along the defensive line when they're
beating Tom Brady and the New England
Patriots. That's what it is. It's Justin
Tuck. It's Matias Kiwanuka. It's Michael
Strahan. It's all those guys getting
after the quarterback. You're starting
to build that now with Arl Reese and
Abdul Carter. They've got it on both
sides of the line of scrimmage and
burns.
>> Dallas is gonna Yeah, he's
>> and Brian Burns 100% man. That's the
rotation.
>> Harbaugh's got some guys.
>> And you still have Tibido for now.
>> Shfter says they're not moving Tibido.
>> Okay,
>> that's what he just put that out there.
>> Just said that.
>> So, they're just going to keep four
edges.
>> Looks like it.
>> Or they're playing somebody at
linebacker.
>> Moving somebody back. All right. Chiefs
on the clock here at six. Where do you
feel you you guys talked about the
Chiefs possibly coming up to try and get
some weapons for Patrick Mahomes and
company even though he's out for a
little bit of time. Uh do you think
Jordan Tyson's in play here? Arizona
State wide receiver.
>> I mean they've been all over Tyson.
They've been all over Fondo. That that's
but now that was also with them picking
nine
>> trading up at nine or from
>> That's what I'm saying. They they were
that was thought to be nine for them was
were those two. Now maybe they feel like
there's been chatter about New Orleans
going to Tyson. if they like Tyson
enough, maybe they go, "All right, let's
leap frog." Um, Fono, the Browns could
have just held you hostage and said,
"We're gonna stand here and pick him if
you don't come up and take it. So, if
you if you want the pick, you need to
come make a move for it." Um, and then I
mean, they
>> they had the entire secondary decimated
on their own doing in a lot of ways.
>> The corner situation,
>> the corner or the safety, they lost they
lost the entire starting secondary.
>> So, downs downs and the lane are there.
You could look at either one of those.
There were some mock drafts where like
when we were talking about McCoy being
healthy that were that you know with
Kansas City even picking at nine they
were talking about them taking
>> right
>> taking McCoy. Not to say they would do
it now but I think Bobby's on to
something with this with this
quarterback situation.
>> Yeah. I mean I think that with Spags the
fit there because he plays a lot of man
physicality that did make a ton of
sense. I just and now that they traded,
it maybe even makes more sense to go
with the corner because you think you
thought maybe Chris Johnson from San
Diego State or Colton Hood from
Tennessee. One of those guys could have
been there for them at 10 at 29 at the
back end of the first round. But I mean,
hey, that's also a team when and and
they're not far removed from winning
Super Bowls. But Tyron Matthew having
some elite safety play if they wanted to
go downs, that would also make some
sense as a good chess piece. If my
argument would be if you're Kansas City
and you're trading above the Commanders
and the Saints to go get corner help,
why would you do that? If the Commanders
and Saints are two teams that probably
would not take either one of those.
Here's the selection for the Chiefs at
six.
>> In the 2026 NFL draft, the Kansas City
Chiefs select Monsour Delane.
>> That's a bummer. LSU
>> as the top top cornerback in the draft
across the board. LSU Msur to Lane and
Bobby just to answer that question
there. Why would you trade from 9 to six
to go get a guy like that?
>> Uh so I mean there was some threat there
was some talk that again if you're
talking about jumping New Orleans. Um
New Orleans was thought that they could
be focused on potentially an edge rusher
or a receiver like Tyson, but there was
some chatter that people thought they
could take the lane. Um, and if you are
if you're the Chiefs and you look at I
think a lot of the NFL believes after
Dellay, there is a significant drop in
the corner tiers. Yeah. Um, and so with
McCoy having the injury questions that
he does,
>> this could just be the Chief saying,
"Look, we got to go get our guy." Now,
they are known to pick some corners in
the first round and then turn him back
out four years later. But this is this
sort of the Chief's way is to take a a
corner in the first round. They've had
success with it and and attack it that
way.
>> Yeah. I I think you're talking about a
very high IQ player here. And I mean,
he's not afraid to get his nose dirty,
too, by the way. They'll like the
physicality that he plays with as that
press man corner and his ability to come
in there and tackle. Uh he is more than
willing to for that position. And
sometimes you don't get these corners.
Backto back. selections on the defensive
side of the ball. The Giants at pick
number five take Arll Reese, the edge
rusher from Ohio State. And the Chiefs
who trade from nine up to six. They go
get Mansour Delane, the corner from LSU.
Couple of defenders off the board that
Dallas would have loved to see continue
falling down. But Brian Bratis, tell us
about your LSU Tiger there.
>> Mur Lane. This is an accomplished
quarter corn quarterback. You know, he
he was accomplished when he was at
Virginia Tech and he can play left
cornering, play right corner. There's
not an assignment this kid can't handle.
He's a sticky man cover corner. He
thrives in the physical side of the
game. Impressive with the way he carries
routes. Super flexible, bendy in the way
he moves, footwork, pedal. All those
things are top shelf with him. He's not
afraid to tackle, not afraid to get his
nose dirty, and it's more than willing
for the position to do that. I mean, I
think a team that plays a lot of man
coverage will love this guy. And then
here he is. He ends up in Kansas City.
>> Good in zone, too. Patient, you know
what I'm saying? good feet, good hips,
and all that. He can do whatever you
want to do. Off man, press man, zone,
whatever. They uh they they got him one.
I was getting real excited about the
Cowboys getting months or you were you
were I know you were really
>> Look, Downs to me has always been the
dream, but Delane would have been really
really nice as well. I mean,
>> he fits what you're trying to do on the
defensive side of the ball.
>> And even when it seems like maybe he's
given up position, he finds a way to
redirect himself and recover. I mean, he
he he you talk about sticking in
coverage, that dude gets it. I agree
with you, Brian. He is physical. He'll
come up and support the run. He is
constantly challenging at the at the
catch point. I mean, teams just didn't
want to throw the football at him.
>> No. To me.
>> And when they did, he made plays.
>> Absolutely. I mean, it was I I don't
know that he is Patrick Certan the
second. I don't want to put that on him,
but it was very reminiscent when you
watched his tape at Alabama where it's
like you get bored because he's just
technically so sound and doing
everything right.
>> All right. So, with that pick being in
for the Chiefs at six, the Washington
Commanders pick is in at seventh
overall. Former defensive coordinator
here in Dallas, Dan Quinn, has made
their selection. Cowboys fans, while the
team is making big picks, make the smart
pick at home. Call Onime Experts, the
official AC, heating, and plumbing
partner of the Dallas Cowboys. Fast,
reliable, always on time. That's the
Ontime Experts. Visit ontimeexperts.com
and click book now. Once again,
alongside YouTube superstar Vach
Lombardi from 1053 The Fan, Brian
Bratis, and Bobby Beld alongside Zack
Walchuk. I'm Kyleman for
dallascowboys.com. As we hand things
back over to the commanders selection,
Roger Goodell at the podium in
Pittsburgh.
The Walter Baiton NFL Man of the Year
award presented by Nationwide
is awarded to one player each year and
celebrates their profound impact on and
off the field.
I'm joined on stage by former winners
Lynn Swan and Jerome Bettis.
And the league welcomed its newest
member to the prestigious club two
months ago, Super Bowl champion and
sixtime allp pro Bobby Wagner. Way to
go, Bobby.
On behalf of the Payton family and
nationwide, I encourage players drafted
this week to make their community and
the league a better place.
You want to go for it or do you want me?
>> With the seventh pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Washington Commanders select
Sunny Styles,
>> linebacker, Ohio State. Apparently, he's
not too big to play linebacker for Dan
Quinn. He is the selection for the
Commanders. Quickly here, Votch, before
we take a break, tell me a little bit
about Sunny Styles.
>> Hey, man, size, speed, measurables, all
this kind of good stuff. And he projects
to be somebody that's going to be
really, really good in coverage. He can
walk down and pass rush a little bit,
too. Um, good verse the run. And, you
know, he apparently like the off the-
field stuff is good. I didn't get a
chance to talk to him, but they say that
the Alterfield stuff is fantastic for
leader captain, communicator, all this
kind of good stuff.
>> Gets everybody lined up.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. All that. All
that. So, yeah, man. Sunny Star is
fantastic pick, man. You know, when when
he's in the trenches or whatever,
they're probably going to want to work
on him dealing with those offensive
linemen down there, but just right now
just he's their mic linebacker right
now.
>> All right. So, we're going to step aside
because we want to take a break just in
case there is some conversation in the
Dallas Cowboys war room. Sunny Styles
off the board, seventh overall to the
Washington Commanders. You're listening
to the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas
Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
trading up. The Saints on the clock now
at pick number eight. The Browns follow
at 9. Wanted to get that break in. We're
back on the DallasCowboys.com side of
things as we continue to break down what
Sunny Styles is now going to see uh on
the defensive side of the ball against
Dallas twice a year.
>> Yeah, I I love Sunny Styles. I mean,
here's the thing. I think that some of
the things that I know Vod and Brian,
you've talked about him when it comes to
the trenches. You're absolutely right
and that has to do with you've played
the position for two years, but I think
what really stood out is when you watch
him in the season opener against Texas
and then you turn on the tape later on
in the year and throughout the season,
he's getting better every single week
and he is a player that played his best
in the biggest games. You look at their
national championship run, he ends up
getting career highs and tackles in the
Cotton Bowl against Texas. He does it
again uh in the national championship
game. Like this dude was absolutely
phenomenal. Just 21 years old,
tremendous athlete. you the coverage is
there with him, but I think the untapped
potentials as a blitzer. He had six
sacks two years ago. I think he can
really get after the quarterback. This
is scary working with Dan Quinn because
I assume he's got a good plan of how to
use him.
>> Remember Dan Quinn took a linebacker
that was a little bit of a tweener at
one point in time here in Dallas and
that worked out.
>> Yeah, it did. It absolutely did. Maybe
he ends up being an edge rusher.
>> Yeah, Mike possibly could be. Yeah,
this, you know, the thing I think the
only thing that with Sunny Styles and
the question I brought, you know, was
and Bobby asked me about why would you
have him as your 16th overall player is
because like I say, I think just two
years as a starter as a linebacker. And
so to me, I was, you know, and I I have
a feeling like we you're right, he got
better as the year wore on when it came
to playing off blocks. I think people
played with his eyes a little bit, you
know, in some of the misdirection things
and and tried to move him around. I know
Vach and I've talked about this uh quite
a bit on our various platforms and
stuff, but he's a guy that all the
measurables, all the testing stuff. Like
I I I'm I'm super impressed by all that.
I'll be interested to see, you know, how
Dan Quinn absolutely uses him in these
in these games. So, let's just run down
the picks really quickly. Uh since five
when the Giants took Arl Ree, edge
rusher from Ohio State, Chiefs at six
take Msort Lane, corner from LSU.
Commanders take Sunny Styles, linebacker
from Ohio State. The Saints are on the
clock now at a VAC. If you're the
Saints, what's the best player available
on your board that kind of matches what
they would be looking?
>> The best player on Vatch's board. Let's
see. Uh Caleb DS is my is my number two
player. Bane is my number four. Uh we're
not going to go Jamal McCoy there. Uh
Jordan Tyson is my
>> eighth guy. So,
>> don't you think that's got to be I mean,
they've been linked to Tyson wide
receiver. I think that I think they got
to go with some offensive help here at
wide receiver. You know, they they've
evidently they've hit on their
quarterback or they like their
quarterback. You got to get him some
help. They've had some problems with
some injuries over the years. You know,
their guys not being completely healthy.
It might not be things, Zach, with
Jordan Tyson might not be the healthiest
guy to be out there.
>> No. Yeah, that's the issue.
>> But but I I think the Saints have to be
looking at wide receiver here.
>> And I think he'd pair really well with
the Chris Olive if that's who they
wanted to take. And I mean to me the guy
could turn out to be I I I kind of saw
some flashes of Justin Jefferson when
you watch him play just with the release
patterns, the ability to play inside and
outside. He just scares the hell out of
me because the injury concerns and
that's why I had him ranked lower on my
board.
>> I thought this was George Pickkins when
I was watching him with the intermediate
stuff, the down the field stuff, the go
the ability to go get the football, you
know, to high point balls to kind of
make himself small to go get a ball
along the sidelines. So, yeah, this this
guy is a super impressive. He's my wide
receiver number one. I actually had I
had him over Tate. Me, too. When uh when
uh when I broke this thing down.
>> And I think if you're Tyson and you look
at or excuse me, if let's say they do
take Tyson, that's a bit of a
disappointment for Dallas. Dallas wanted
at least the possibility for him to be
there at 12. If that ends up being the
case,
>> yeah. If it's not the case and he
continues to fall, is that a
conversation you would anticipate? Maybe
not over a Caleb DS or one of these
other uh defensive players that are up
there, but still a possibility. Botch.
>> Yeah, man. But I'm just looking at these
at these tackles and how they're kind of
falling a little bit, you know? So, if
you're if you're the Cowboys and maybe
you're having a conversation about
Tyson, maybe in the room right now,
they're having a conversation about
these uh that's you got to talk about.
going to ask you and I and I was trying
to kind of gauge in my mind how far did
I need to get before I start bringing
this up and and if you get to you know
if you're getting to the Giants there at
at 10,
>> you know, and and he gets past the
Giants, you have to have this
conversation
>> about, you know, and and and listen, we
could we could say, oh, well, you know,
you've got uh you you got Steel and you
got, you know, Steel took a reduced, you
know, contract this year to to stay on
board, but man, that is not keeping and
me from potentially drafting Francis
Malaninoa.
>> Yep.
>> Lots of opportunities there as we go
into hour number three of our coverage
on the 2026
NFL draft.
Closing in on the 8 o'clock hour of the
2026 NFL draft in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. Welcome back in to our
coverage from the Star in Fris on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com. We're taking a look
inside the Cowboys War Room on the
streaming platforms and conversation
happening. The Cowboys are about four
picks away now at pick number 12. The
Saints pick is in at 8 after the
Commanders go with Sony Styles at 7.
Msort Lane, the corner from LSU, goes to
the Chiefs at 6. And Arl Reese, the edge
ruffer edge rusher from Ohio State, goes
to the Giants at 5. So with all of that
being said, Brian Bratis, our resident
scout, what do you think the
conversation is for the Cowboys in the
war room at the moment?
>> Yeah, I think they're they're they're
hopeful that uh in fact that that that
safety gets to them. I mean, that's kind
of where Ohio.
>> Yeah, everybody's holding their breath
and there's there's a spot, you know,
there's a spot. I mean, talking to my
friends at the Giants, you know, DS was
a guy that that that they really thought
the world of, but you know, they need a
right guard and, you know, that's where
and in and doing some mock drafting
stuff with those guys on the giants.com
on the phone.
>> I gave him Francis Mino at five. So, you
know, yeah, this could be Stephen might
be somebody might be talking about
coming to Stephen here, I think, is is
what they're is what they're looking at.
>> All right.
>> Potentially,
>> Saint selection is in at pick number
eight. New Orleans on the clock. Here's
Roger Goodell to announce the pick.
>> Somebody cover
with an Oscar now.
>> Oh my goodness.
>> Sweet Carolina.
Oh, stop it. Votch.
>> Votch.
>> That's terrible.
>> How dare you?
>> I think living on a prayer should be
>> in the 2026 NFL.
>> The New Orleans Saints select Jordan
Tyson.
>> Wide receiver.
>> That's a big sigh of relief for me.
>> All right.
>> Why is that? Why is that a sigh of
relief?
>> I mean, you got a guy that missed like
35% of his games in college.
>> Oh,
>> I I just don't know.
>> Tell us why you don't like Tyson.
>> It's It's the hurt guy thing. That
That's what it is. And if
>> What about the route running? I love the
players and the explosive and yak.
>> You're talking about two bad hammies and
we just talked about minimizing risk and
safety for a team like the Cowboys that
has had plenty of players that you've
drafted and have been hurt. I hope he
ends up being an allp pro phenomenal
player. I just I'm fine with letting
some other team go ahead and be the hero
there. And I know that there was love in
this building for Jordan Tyson.
>> There's a ton of love in this building
for
>> You know what? I'm I'm glad he's not a
cowboy personally.
>> No, that's fine. You can be wrong about
that one. Well, I'll be right when it's
Caleb DS and we're all celebrating.
>> See, I think it's fitting that Vach just
said live on a prayer because I think
that's kind of what Dallas is doing at
the moment, hoping that Caleb DS falls
to them at pick number 12 because you've
got two more, actually three more teams
in between them and the 12th overall
pick. You've got the Cleveland Browns on
the clock at pick number nine. Remember,
they traded back from six to nine with
the Kansas City Chiefs. So, they go with
a a move to the ninth overall pick.
Where could Cleveland be going? And then
you've got the New New York Giants for
their second pick of the top 10. They're
sitting there at 10 and then a Miami
Dolphins at 11 overall. Which out of
those three teams, Bobby, do you feel
like could disrupt the possibility of
Caleb DS wearing a star on the side of
the helm?
>> Giants. Uh, it would Giants are the one
that would be terrifying there. I think
the Browns pretty consistently have been
looking at offensive line. So you would
assume that's Maui Noah or Fono or
there's some they were tied a little bit
to Freeline at one point. So I would
assume you're looking at offensive line
there and now you just got to see what
the Giants and the Dolphins are.
>> I think if you're a Cowboy fan here, you
want them to take Feno.
>> I think you want them to take
>> or Minoa because the Giants probably
like Mino more.
>> Yeah. Because they can move they can
move him to guard. They can move him to
guard. Yeah. And I I think if if you're
hoping for downs because you don't need
him to go and maybe something because of
the back. Maybe there's some medical
stuff with the with with with MOA with
the back and the disc. He's played
through it.
>> But Cleveland, if Cleveland were to take
Feno here,
>> that would open things up for the
Giants. I like I say downs I know they
absolutely love but man you you talk
about what Francis Mau Noah could do for
their offensive line situation that
would be a hard one for me to pass.
>> Well it' be great value for the Giants
because you'd be getting to me the third
and fifth best players in the draft in
my opinion and they're taking them at
five and 10.
>> So I think they did an excellent job.
Now for the Cowboys you could be looking
at getting my number one player at pick
12. Yeah.
>> So, it Miami is the one like, are we not
worried about Miami? Cuz they could go
in a lot of different directions.
>> I always worry about Miami cuz
>> they could take any player possible.
>> Yeah. Miami is terrifying just because
of it could be anything you want at any
potential moment.
>> And Miami is a team with John Eric
Sullivan as the new general manager
there. They, you know, there's no
history with him. You, you go back to
what they used to do at Green Bay and,
you know, oh, they don't draft
receivers, they don't do this, they
don't do that. But, you know, you wonder
that's a team that is like they're, you
know, they're shedding players, the cap,
all that stuff like that. You know, he
might be looking to grab some picks. And
I kind of had I had the Detroit Lions as
a team to potentially if one of those
offensive linemen going from 17 up to
11. Now, that would help the Cowboys if
that's the case, but uh you know, we'll
see. We'll see how that all plays out.
Like I said, I I am now worried about
this Giants pick if you want downs.
>> Okay. If you're worried at 10:00 and
you're worried at 11 about downs
possibly going in either one of those
situations, are you on the clock with
are you on the phone with Cleveland here
trying to trade up to go to nine?
>> Well, we Yeah, we talked to Cleveland
before. I mean, it we we've talked I
mean everybody's had that you know
everybody Dallas going to six, you know,
specifically maybe you can maybe you can
figure it out.
>> Would you have to throw in extra
selections because remember that was the
reason they moved back in the first
place.
>> Yeah, I think so. You would probably
have to throw in it'd be the same math
as it would be the to Kansas City,
right? Because they have 29 round now.
>> Yes. Sorry, I was very distracted
watching and texting.
>> Uh they're they're talking in there
right now and and Will's got his hand
ready on the phone. Um they're talking
to somebody.
>> Cleveland's pick is in and I don't think
you're trading with the Giants, which
means I would assume that they're either
talking about going back Oh, Stephen
just dropped his head. I would assume I
would assume they're talking about going
back
>> or
>> one of those one spot flips. We always
see one of those in the first round.
Just the single spot flips.
>> Like a Miami Dallas 112. You just make
sure you go get downs.
>> Why would you say no to the Giants at
10?
>> Why Why do you think that's not a
problem?
>> I don't think I just don't I don't think
the Giants would do it with you.
>> No. Interesting. Okay.
>> I I think I think
>> the same exact trade interdivisional
happened for for Micah Parsons. Remember
Dallas was at 10. They took the deal
from Philadelphia at 12 and they flipped
back two spots.
>> Yeah. No, no, it's Yes, it's the same
spot. Now, that was Philly.
>> Now, Phil, the Giants may not appreciate
that they were at 11 in that instance
and you let them flip.
>> That's true. Here's the Browns at nine.
>> The Cleveland Browns select Spencer
Fono.
>> Okay, here we go. All right, this is
good.
>> Utah.
>> This is This is That part is good.
>> So, that keeps Malinoa on the board for
the Giants.
>> Giants potentially. Potentially.
>> I think they've got to take him. I mean,
look, like they don't have to, right?
>> They could take
>> They could take downs. Now you got Downs
and Reese and your defense is freaking
stacked. I I don't want that to happen.
I think they need the offensive lineman.
I'm praying Caleb DS, the best player in
this class, makes it to 12 and then we
can all chug Miller Lights together.
>> I like that idea. Remember, Miller
Light, the only beer of the Dallas
Cowboys. It is Miller time.
>> Tell me a little bit about Spencer Fondo
here, Brian, the offensive tackle out of
Utah.
>> I need to pull up my notes if I could.
If Bobby got
>> I can I can already tell you what
Brian's gonna say about him.
>> He's like tackle. I I don't like my
light tackles. He does not like he
doesn't like his lightweight tackle.
>> He's only 311 pounds.
>> Yeah, this this this is a little bit of
an issue, you know, for me. It's
something that I have a problem with,
but this guy is a he is a tremendous
athlete and when you watch him play, you
could you could see that. You could see
the athletic ability, the way he's able
to play in space, I think is pretty
impressive uh with with him. I can say I
just have a real problem with these
lightweight tackles. He he is a right
tackle. He's played both both sides in
his career. He's fluid. He's flexible.
He's got body control. He's got balance.
You rare you see him on the ground. He
can be an outstanding run blocker when
it comes to getting
>> They're clapping there. They are pumped.
>> So, did they I
might Giants might have taken that. They
might have taken the tackles. Here we
go. Here is the Giants selection at 10
with Roger Goodell going to the podium
>> with the 10th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The New York Giants select
Francis Maui Noah.
>> There you go.
>> Wow.
>> Tackle Miami.
>> Francis Minoa. As we talked about, one
of the top offensive tackles in the NFL
draft goes to 10 with the New York
Giants. The Miami Dolphins are on the
clock at pick number 11 and then it's
the Dallas Cowboys at pick number 12.
So,
>> boy, as pumped as they were on that
video just now,
>> that seemed like a pick,
>> right?
>> Or or they just secured the spot,
>> that was the thing is they secure a
spot, but Jerry looked like he was on a
on a telephone there for a minute.
>> Well, if they secured a spot and then
called, I mean, if it was one spot up,
then
>> he's still going to be on the phone at
some point in time.
>> So, the Cowboys have traded up to pick
11. So
>> yeah, we knew the Dolphins were going to
be a team that that you know, give me
picks, give me picks. So is this Caleb
DS?
>> I think this is probably
>> it's got to be Caleb DS, right?
>> Or they're going to stun all of us. And
I mean they I just know they have loved
him during the process. Absolutely.
>> And it makes so much sense.
>> Where is he on your board, Brian?
>> He's number one.
>> Number one overall player.
>> Number one overall player. Yes, sir.
>> When you look at it, Bobby, what is he
on your board?
>> Uh he's three.
>> Okay. Yeah, it was it was Bailey Reese
and then it was uh it was downs.
>> Okay. Nick Harris, who is back in the
room from the Fort Worth Star Telegram.
I know you're probably tweeting you're
doing your job.
>> He's number two on my board.
>> Number two on your board. Tommy Yish,
number one overall.
>> Okay. He's number four for me. So, top
five player in the NFL draft.
>> Christian Parker was on the phone. Who
else do we have in there?
>> This is This is a pick.
>> Yeah, it's a pick.
>> So, Dallas probably just went one spot
then, right? Is that Is that what we're
doing? Well, that's what the the
selection was and that's what the news
is. It's being broken across the board.
Dallas trades from 12 to 11
with the Miami Dolphins. We'll get some
compensation there in a little bit. What
What on the trade chart would that take
here? Uh Bobby, when you talk about some
of those
>> 112 probably if you're going to do a one
pick flip, I would I would guess it'd be
something like 112.
>> Would you I would do that for downs in a
heartbeat.
>> It's now official by the way.
>> Is it official? Okay. what the trade is.
>> The trade is
>> Do we know what the compensation is yet?
>> Not just yet.
>> Okay.
>> Sounds like two- fifths.
>> That's
>> Yeah, Ian Rapour saying it's for 177 and
180.
>> So, if you trade back from 20, you can
pick that back up easily. If if you're
trying to get more bites at the apple at
the end of the day,
>> two giving up two fizz is a little tough
to stomach, but it's a lot easier when
you have potentially a really
game-changing defender.
>> If you don't make the trade here,
>> if this is the pick, I'm just telling
you, if this is the pick, every one of
you is getting hugged. Okay, that's fine
with me. The if if they don't make the
trade up to 11, that's a wipeout
scenario. Look at all the names that are
off the board to get to this point.
Mendoza, one to the Raiders. Bailey two
to the Jets. Jeremiah Love three to the
Cardinals. Tate four to the Titans. Arll
Reese to the Giants at five. Mensor Lane
six to the Chiefs. Sunonny Styles to the
Commanders at seven. Jordan Tyson eight
to the Saints. The Browns at nine take
Spencer Fono. And then the Giants at 10
take Francis Malininoa. The best player
on your board is Caleb DS, right?
>> On my board it is. Not even close.
>> Yeah, it's he's the number one player on
>> Who's the next highest graded player? Is
it Ruben Bane?
>> It would been Malinoa.
>> And he's off the board to the Giants.
>> Yep. Absolutely. So, you have a
significant opportunity here to just
move up one spot and either take the
best player available or turn around and
have a possible wipeout scenario where
the Miami Dolphins across the board can
take anybody. They're bad enough that
they can take anybody. I just had a
feeling that Miami was going to be the
team that was going to move and I
worried about somebody taking their pick
and lo and behold, it's the Cowboys.
>> They are too they are too happy for
this. I I feel like I feel like this is
this has a very real shot to be.
>> We're trying not to give it away in
terms of
>> No, we're just talking about how excited
they are in that room.
>> They should be excited. This guy's a
hell of a football player if in fact
he's the in fact he is the selection
which we all
>> pick is in.
>> Okay.
>> Pick is in for Dallas.
>> John Steven Jones almost took off
Steven's hand giving him a high five
when up and
>> celebrated there.
>> I just want to play devil's advocate
here. Who else could it be outside of
Caleb DS? Is it Bane?
>> Ruben Bane. I would I would think.
>> Um
>> could it be a tackle?
>> Yeah.
>> Freeling still there?
>> Could be. I mean, if they
>> might be a possibility of 20 though.
>> Yeah. Um
I I can't I don't I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know who else. I don't
know who else.
>> Well, I mean like with
>> Bane I I mean the only thing I Bane
would be it. Bane or
>> Lemon? I mean I'm just
>> They really liked Lemon. You know who
they liked? They liked Omar Cooper a
lot.
>> Yeah.
>> I think they liked Omar Cooper more than
Lemon.
>> Okay. Okay. Well, then that I'm just
going off.
>> Yeah. No, no, no. I But I think that
that would be I I think that's who it
would be.
>> Yeah. So, once again, just a recap, the
Cowboys originally slated to pick 12th
overall and 20th overall, have traded
the 177th pick in the fifth round and
the 188th or 80th pick in the fifth
round to go up one spot from 12 to 11.
Their pick is in in the first round.
They flip spots with Miami and they are
celebrating in the round. probably were
worried that Miami was going they
probably had to give a little extra
because probably worried that Miami was
going to Miamiy's going to sell this
pick.
>> Sure.
>> You know, so Dallas had to
>> or take the player they wanted.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> And that's one thing that if you give
credit to the front office as they
draft, they don't normally give up who
they want to draft. Even though I think
everyone could telegraph if you're
Dallas, you're moving up one spot to go
get a certain player, right? or at least
anybody that has any sort of knowledge
of the situation here in Dallas.
>> Sure. And Caleb DS probably would have
been the best player available for Miami
as well. So, it just kind of
incentivizes you even more. Now, we look
at the camera and we see that's Derrick
Ansley, the defensive back's coach, Ryan
Smith, the secondary coach, Robert
Muschamp, the secondary assistant, all
making their way around McNeil.
>> Who could it be?
>> Everybody listen got your guy Kenneth
Murray on this. We're not we're just
who's standing there. Listen, there's an
NFL Network commercial. They are
dragging it out as long as they possibly
can and they're they're going to come
back and it's going to be another two
minutes and then we're finally going to
get the pick. So, you're right. I think
everybody kind of knows here. But just
for the sake of theater, we can just
kind of have that conversation.
What does this do if he is the pick
Brian and it becomes official? What does
this do to your
>> defense? Listen, this is this is the
things that we're kind of trying to
learn about Christian Parker. This is
where, you know, the the nickel
position. We had this discussion about,
you know, just trying to get players
that could come in here and play roles
and play him at a very very high level.
This kid is super smart. He's tough. He
can cover. He can tackle. There's so
many things to like about this guy as a
player. had Dave Campo come on and talk
with uh with us, you know, uh on on our
platform with me and Votch and he was
talking about Downs and what he could
bring and all the things and the Darren
Woodson like comparisons that he was
saying, hey, listen, when we had Woody,
we could do this and we could do this.
And he thought the same thing about this
Caleb DS in fact if he is the pick.
So the pick is in for Dallas in
Pittsburgh. It looks like they are back
from commercial break and shortly we
should hear from Roger Goodell about who
the Dallas Cowboys are picking at the
11th overall selection in the 2026 NFL
draft. Once again alongside Nick Harris,
Brian Bratis, Bobby Belt, Tommy Yarish.
Here's Roger Goodell with the Cowboys
pick at 11th overall
tonight.
>> With the 11th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Dallas Cowboys select Caleb
DS.
>> So there you go.
>> Cheers to Cowboys Nation. This has been
a name on their list at the top of the
list from the early moments of the draft
process. Dallas said they wanted to be
aggressive this off season. They said
they wanted to make a difference on the
defensive side of the ball. They just
showed two things in one swift swoop as
Bobby Belt actually does hug everybody
in the room. Caleb DS is the newest
Dallas Cowboy. exceptional football IQ,
rare instincts, anticipation, the way he
supports the run. He's a super reliable
tackle. You go back to his when he
started his career at Alabama. This kid
wanted to go play for Nick Sabin, and
Nick Sabin is one of the toughest
defensive back coaches in the country.
He's hard on his players, but he ma he
was always, you know, this kid wanted
that type of challenge. He led the team
in tackles as a freshman. He was a big
part of the championship run that the
Ohio State Buckeyes had two years ago.
Uh he's very good when it comes to the
reactions. He really thrives in the
situations. You might have to live a
little bit with some gambling traits
that he has. And I'm talking about
gambling, you know, with some of the
plays and stuff on pass coverage, but
overall though, he is a he is a much
better player. Like I say, put him down
around the line of scrimmage and he's
going to find ways to make plays. This
was always the guy. This was always the
guy for them. They loved him. And this
is I tweeted it about, I don't know,
three, four weeks ago, some cutups of
him, and I said that uh one player isn't
going to fix your defense, but this dude
comes pretty damn close. He he
absolutely
changes the entire DNA of what they want
to do. Yeah, we talk about versatility
with Christian Parker and what he's been
trying to do and I think Caleb DS
directly plays into that
>> and there are plenty of opportunities
for us to talk about how he fits into
it. We're going to hear from Caleb DS.
We'll get to talk about his possible
role in Christian Parker's defense. A
whole lot more reaction still to come as
Caleb DS is the pick for the Dallas
Cowboys, 11th overall in the 2026 NFL
draft. Cowboys still have that 20th pick
as they have another selection in the
first round for now. Let's step aside.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> Sorry to cut you off there, Nick. Had to
get the break in just in case something
else happens here. But continue to your
breakdown there for Caleb. Yeah, when we
talk about versatility and what
Christian Parker has been trying to
emphasize in the secondary throughout
the off seasonason, Caleb DS directly
plays into that. He can step in, be that
back-end safety. He can be a nickel
corner. I think in this defense, if
you're asking me, I want Caleb DS to
come in and play nickel corner day one.
I want him playing close to the line of
scrimmage. I want him throwing that 511,
206 pound frame at the line of scrimmage
in the run game and getting after the
quarterback in some blitzing situations.
This is going to be an ultimate chess
piece for Christian Parker. And you
know, I I can't really oversell how how
great of a pick this is. He's number two
on my board. Um he's the highest
defender on my board. Um I I am very
confident that this man is going to have
a really really strong career in the
NFL. And uh man, the Cowboys are super
fortunate they see him fall and and get
him at 11. If you if you want to talk
about the Miller Light moment,
>> Cleveland taking Feno
>> allowing
>> allow and then that made MAOA get to the
Giants
>> that that opened the door for the Giants
to take and and you know that that the
talk was about him. They loved Downs,
but they needed offensive linemen. You
know, if Malinoa had say gone to had
gone to Cleveland, then you're now in a
situation where I don't know if the
Giants take Feno. I think they take
downs and you kind of and and and they
they they they move on with their day.
But that was a that was a big big
selection for the Cowboys when when uh
when Feno went to the Cleveland Browns
there uh at at nine.
>> You talk about value, too. He was the
last player in my top 10 that was still
on the board through the first 11 picks.
I I mean, they they picked up incredible
value here. And and Tommy, this kind of
shows a shift in the thinking. The last
time Dallas took a safety at any point
in the NFL draft, not even just the
first round, any point in the NFL draft
was 2019. It's been a long time since
they've taken a safety and they did so
and they did so by trading up to go get
him.
>> I I think that Caleb DS is the best
player in this draft class. I I've had
him there since day one and he's stuck
there. And I I really haven't had any
reason to move him off. I've said this a
couple times on the draft show.
Caleb DS has been the smartest player on
every football field that he stepped on
from high school to college. And I think
he's going to come in day one and be one
of the smartest players immediately for
this Cowboys defense. With all the talk
about Christian Parker saying he hates
gray area and he wants his secondary to
be on the same page with each other at
all times. Caleb DS is a guy that can
come in and immediately take that all
away once he gets a hold of this
playbook. You know, he may not have all
the tangibles for the 40 time and the
measurements and things like that, but
he is one step ahead of everybody else
in front of him. He's versatile. He can
play all over the field. It wouldn't
shock me if he played nickel safety at
the same time. Just moving him around in
different places throughout the course
of a game and keeping opposing offenses
guessing. Uh but that that's the biggest
thing about Downs is his football IQ is
second to none. I think he's going to be
a really special player for a very long
time. Do you guys felt like I know they
only traded up one spot, but was this
one of those things that because I know
in various platforms I was on radio and
all that I saying Dallas has got to go
up. Dallas has got to go up. They've got
to go up and get one of these players.
>> Their patience played off. Was this a
positional value thing? I was going to
ask the same question.
>> Um, probably. Now, this is Dallas is
going to view him differently because
that is your starting nickel corner.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> Caleb DS is playing nickel for them this
year. Um, and then in base he'll he'll
play safety, but otherwise that's that's
going to be the guy that's out there in
the nickel. And he is he is the perfect
modern nickel, especially for what they
look for. Um, you know, just within
Christian Parker's scheme, he is going
to be asked to do a lot in run sport.
The stuff at the line of scrimmage with
him is ridiculous. He he is so good at
the line of scrimmage. He is such a
difference maker. Uh, and and this is
Uhhuh.
>> So, the Dolphins trade back one spot
with the Dallas Cowboys at the 12th
overall selection. They take Kaden
Proctor out of Alabama. But once again,
the Cowboys moving up one spot to the
11th overall selection. They take safety
out of Ohio State. Caleb DS continuing
to react here inside the Star in Fris
with Bobby Belt, Brian Bratis from 1053
the fan, Nick Harris from the Fort Worth
Star Telegram, Tommy Yarish, and myself,
Kyleman's from DallasCowboys.com. As DS
is the newest Dallas Cowboys.
>> Yeah, that's great. He's awesome. You
are not going to just blow by my chance
to say I told Nick that Proctor would go
near the top 10 and he said no way. No,
actually didn't. He didn't say no way.
He just made a joke about him eating too
much. But I I I got to you got to at
least at least let me spike the football
really fast. And now now we go back to
Yeah, there it is. I told you. Now we're
going back to
>> I just kind of feel like though that
this was a guy when Proctor Remember I
was talking about Detroit coming up.
>> Yeah.
>> If for and it right around this spot was
I was kind of thinking you know and
Miami. Yeah. They end up, you know,
Dallas makes the deal, but th this is
where Proctor was kind of talked about
with a lot of people, believe it or not.
>> Yeah. When you look at now the pick on
the clock or the pick is in for the Rams
at 13.
>> They have been tied really consistently
to Mai Lemon.
>> Yeah. Okay. Interesting. Uh we'll we'll
talk about them in a moment. Uh let's go
ahead and listen to the secret audio
from Caleb DS. This is the type of
exclusive turnaround that you get here
on the draft show. Caleb DS, safety out
of Ohio State, taken by the Cowboys at
pick number 11.
So, it doesn't seem like the audio, we
can hear it in our headset, but on the
program side of things, apparently it's
not going out over program is what I'm
being told. So, we'll get that audio
very shortly and it'll fire up uh here
in a moment. But, yeah, we can hear it
in our headsets there uh with our tech
team in the back working on it. Yeah,
these are always special moments when it
comes to the the secret audio and that's
the live production of the NFL draft.
You never know what's gonna happen.
>> A lot of fun.
>> Uh once again, the Rams are on the clock
at pick number 13. Then it's followed by
the Ravens at 14, the Buccaneers at 15,
the Jets at 16, Lions at 17, Vikings at
18, Panthers at 19, and then the Cowboys
pick again at pick number 20. Nick, as
we try and get the the secret audio back
here in a moment, what do you think the
possibility is uh for Dallas to pick
there at 20 or possibly trade back?
>> Yeah, I think you give up those two
fifth round picks, 177, 180. You want to
pick on day three because you want that
that fifth round has been really
beneficial to them over the course of
the past decade. I I think trading back
from 20 makes a lot more sense now. And
as I've mapped out over the course of
the last week or so, it that's going to
be a sweet spot for a lot of these teams
to want to come up for an offensive
lineman. Um you're going to have uh
players like Blake Miller, Max Ianer, um
Monroe Freeling, uh Kaden Proctor just
went off the board, but we haven't seen
Oliva Yon. I would imagine he's gone by
then. Um but there's going to be some
offensive linemen, and there are a ton
of teams behind the Cowboys at 20 that
need offensive linemen. And so I wonder
if one of them call the Cowboys and say,
"Hey, we won our pick of the litter.
We're coming up. We'll give you this,
this, this, whatever it may be." They
could very well end up at the end of the
night with more capital than they than
they had coming in. If they play the
right trade, it could be 25 with the
Bears, 28 with the Texans. Those two
make some sense. Um, but this this is
certainly not over and it could very
well end up being an A+ night for the
Cowboys. Um, I think at the very very
worst, I think you got a B+ night.
Albert Berer, uh, who used to cover
things here in Dallas, he's with SI now.
He said that he got a text from a head
coach earlier today that Vegas odds on
the guy with the best chance to get a
gold jacket is Caleb DS.
>> Wow.
>> I could see that. Especially
>> I mean, he's just
>> What about a Super Bowl ring?
>> I mean, you got the more the more of
those guys you have,
>> it serious.
>> The more of those guys you have with the
gold jackets, the more likely you're
going to get it.
>> Yeah, you've got a couple of options
there. All right, I believe we have the
secret audio. Here is Caleb DS as the
11th pick to the Dallas Cowboys.
>> Hey, Caleb.
>> Hey, Caleb. Can you hear me?
>> Caleb, this Jared Jones, you're a
cowboy.
>> Hey man, congratulations.
Caleb, you're a cowboy.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I appreciate it.
>> Oh man, we're happy. Here's coach.
Here's coach.
>> All right. Caleb, what's up, brother?
>> What's up?
>> Hey, congratulations, man. Hey, we get
to play knockout a little bit more, man.
>> Hey. Hey, we gonna have to play
knockout. I'm going have to beat you
with again.
>> Hey, damn right, brother. Hey, I can't
tell you how excited we are, brother.
This is This is the perfect spot for
you. God, cannot wait. I hope you're
excited, man. Hey, CP. Hey, hold on. CP
wants to talk to you. Hey,
>> congrats, man. Hold on one second.
Here's Christian Parker, our DC.
>> All right. Yes, sir.
>> Caleb.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir. You hear me?
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir. I hear you.
>> Hey, let's get to it, baby.
>> Let's do it, bro.
>> Hey, bro.
>> I thank you for this, coach.
>> Hey, man. We going to make it happen,
bro. Hey, look. You We going to make
each other great.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's get it done, baby.
>> All right.
>> All right, bro.
>> All right. There you go. Caleb DS and a
lot of excitement. You heard a couple
things there. Playing knockout, putt,
putt, Tommy. When do they do all of
that?
>> Yeah. Always good uh to gauge your
competitiveness of your new player when
he challenges the head coach to knockout
after on the on the draft call. But I
think the interesting thing there was uh
hey is it was Christian Parker saying
hey we're going to make each other
better. We're going to make each other
better and I will step aside for Vash.
>> May I May I say one what you got?
>> Hold on. Let's go to the Rams selection
here at pick 13.
>> Is this what it is?
>> What is this? Does come down that way?
has no pressure to play. Amazing. Get
ready.
>> With the 13th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Los Angeles Rams select,
>> Ty Simpson.
>> Wow.
>> I I don't hate it. I I hate at 13 cuz
they definitely could have bailed and
gotten I I think him at like 24.
>> Baile. He got the third best.
>> But I like the fit. I like the fit cuz
he can learn behind Stafford for a
while. But my goodness, that is wild.
>> Yo, Nick, we got Caleb DS. We ain't got
time to be wasting our breath on this
nonsensical stuff other teams got going.
I just wanted to say one thing real fast
and I'mma leave.
>> Bobby Belt.
>> Yeah.
>> Nick Harris, Brian Brus, Tommy Y, Kyle.
How many times in Cowboy land last year
we'll be watching the game
>> and they'll lose by one possession. It
was it like five games they lost by like
one possession or something. And it was
always one big play in the game, right?
One deep ball. And some corners looking
back at Malik Hook like, "Hey dog, what
was I supposed to do right there?" Yeah.
what was supposed to happen right there.
That don't happen with Caleb DS and
Jaylen Thompson, bro. It just simply
don't happen. It don't happen.
>> I like it.
>> How many more games do you simply win?
And I know it's a lot to put on a rookie
like that. I'm just excited. I'm lit.
Pardon me. Miller Light number one.
Listen.
>> Listen.
>> The only beer that
>> The only beer. Listen. How many games do
you win if you simply don't have
nonsense in your secondary going on?
Yeah.
>> You know what I'm saying?
>> I'm just way too lit for this.
>> Number two player on my board. Yeah.
>> I've been saying all year on this on
this dag on program on this one and on
me and Brian teams really will just like
let good players fall to you.
>> Yeah.
>> Teams will just let good stuff happen to
you. You know what I'm saying? And the
National Football League let Caleb DS
get to the Dallas Football Cowboys.
>> I I think the NFL let him get to 11. I
would give a lot of credit to Dallas for
taking initiative to go up and get your
guy be aggress.
>> He fell to that point. I bet you they
tried at 8 n 10 before 11. If the
Cowboys were picking at six in this
draft, I think they're taking Caleb
down.
>> For sure.
>> Yeah,
>> for sure. One more thing before I leave.
I would drink all these Miller lights
>> if they mess around T Ruben Bane at 20.
>> Well, he is still he is still available.
>> Hey, let me tell y'all something.
>> Let me tell y'all something. And drink
Kyle Kyle, what was your little show bet
about your little about your little
scuba shoes and your marathon? So if
they take if they take Kendrick Faulk at
any point in the first round, Dallas
specifically, I have to run the draft
day 5K on Saturday in scuba flippers.
>> Brian, let me tell you something. I'm
not coming to work tomorrow if they mess
around and get Ruben Bane at 20. I'll be
back in like 30 minutes, y'all. Word.
>> Thanks, VC.
>> Good job, man.
>> Good job. Congratulations.
>> So, there is kind of a a small Cowboys
tie here with Tai Simpson. You might
have seen it if you're got a dual stream
with the NFL Network on. Tyler Booker
was there with him. He and Ty Simpson
are best friends. They've been best
friends since they played together at
Alabama. And pretty cool. A year apart,
they go one pick apart in the first
round. So Tyler's talked a couple of
times while he's been here about the
relationship that he has with Tai
Simpson. So again, you saw him there in
the in the draft room again.
>> And now they can hang out whenever the
Rams come to Oxnard for joint practice
and training camp as they inevitably do
every couple of years. So I'm sure
that'll happen at some point in time.
>> Thought you were breaking news for a
second. Oh no.
>> Well, I don't know why that hadn't
really registered with me until Vox just
said it, but I mean depending on what
the Ravens are about to do. Like you are
looking at we're potentially 14 picks
into this with no Ruben Bane off the
board.
>> That's very true. Uh let's break down
the last couple of selections just for
those that are listening on the audio
side. Starting at 10 with the New York
Giants, Francis Malinoa goes offensive
tackle from Miami. He pairs with the
fifth overall pick, Arll Ree. Really
good haul there from the Giants at 5 and
10. And the Cowboys trade from 12 to 11
with the min or with the Miami Dolphins.
They take Caleb DS the D or the safety
from Ohio State. The Dolphins at 12 take
Kaden Proctor off into tackle from
Alabama. And then one pick later, the
Rams at 13 take Alabama teammate to
Kaden Proctor, quarterback Ty Simpson.
The Ravens are on the clock at 14, which
means best player on the board is now
going to Baltimore as it always happens,
Brian.
>> It's it's a tradition like no other
right here. So yeah, it wouldn't be
surprised like you say. We'll see.
>> Who's the best player on your board
right now?
>> Well, it's it I I did not move McCoy
because of the injury stuff. So it'd be
McCoy. Bane would be in the mix. Lemon
would be in the mix. Terrell from
Clemson would be in the mix and then
Hood from Tennessee would be where I'm
at right there.
>> Did you have Hood in the first round?
>> I did. He was player 13.
>> I really like I really liked
>> Hood. I did too. Yeah. The ones that I
think I would mind him at 20. The
question wouldn't either. The questions
I have is the thing with with Terrell.
That's the one that I think might come
back and get me. The 46, you know, but
if you watch the tape, the guy makes a
ton of plays. So, I I I we all kind of
doubted his brother a little bit. Maybe
this one will be even better than his
brother. B, but you're right. Baltimore,
a great player always seems to fall to
Baltimore. Wouldn't be surprised here if
maybe they take the uh that Oregon tight
end.
>> That's my number one player on my board.
Yeah,
>> you could maybe see a tight end going
there. Here's Roger Goodell with the
pick at 14 and Baltimore.
>> I don't know this is as much for the
commission.
>> 14th pick
>> in the 2026 NFL draft. The Baltimore
Ravens select Olive Avenga.
>> Yeah.
>> Guard Penn State.
>> There you go. One of the best players
remaining in the draft. Olivia Wenger
or or Vingga Yawwan out of Penn State.
>> You want to run that back?
>> Uh, Olivia Va
or
>> I think it was Vega.
>> Yane. Yeah, you could just go with Vega.
>> Or Venga.
>> Wa is what they say on the official one.
Wa. Yawan.
>> I love it.
>> There you go. You said Maagoa the whole
draft process.
>> Menoa.
>> It's Ma Noa, dude.
>> Oh, well,
>> there's no G, bro.
>> Okay. Well, sorry. I was going to say
you started us with Mao. I think you
were the first one to say it like that.
Now you pivoted and you've confused us.
>> Yeah. And I I've heard it's Ma and Goa.
But uh Hey, can I can I talk about
Oliva?
Change
>> the subject. Tommy, take it. Tommy, take
>> No, you got it. You got it.
>> Yan.
>> I'm not saying it right. I'm sorry. I I
I've given up.
>> Go for it, Tommy. Get Get after, dude.
Uh I was He's the He was the best player
available for me at that spot. Uh I
think he's an immediate plug-and-play
starter. Good build, strong at the point
of attack. keeps his pe keeps his feet
moving uh to maintain his blocks,
creates huge lanes in the run game, and
he can hold up against stronger rushers,
too.
>> I don't know if you heard that, but
Chris Beam is in the back. He's telling
us that we have the newest Dallas Cowboy
on the line. Caleb DS is on the phone.
Caleb, first off, congratulations to you
and your family for a lifechanging day.
Just tell us what's going through your
mind right now as you were picked 11th
overall for the Cowboys. Yeah, just
extremely exciting, extremely blessed to
be here. Uh very highly favored and um
just
just excited to be uh be a cowboy, ready
to go play football.
>> What was it like through the draft
process getting to know the the Cowboys
front office? We heard your secret audio
with with the coaching staff and talking
to Brian Shottenheimer about shooting
hoops and playing putt putt. I mean,
what was it like and how much contact
did Dallas have with you uh over the
last few months? Yeah, I knew there was
a a big interest there and I was I was
really excited about that interest. Uh I
had a great feeling on our 30 visit and
uh had a great great visit formal visit
with them as well. So actually we didn't
have a formal visit. We actually missed
out on that. So uh but it all worked out
in the end. So uh yeah, I mean great
great to be around coach Shotti. Um I
appreciate the Joneses for making this
uh
making this pick and I'm just very
thankful to be in the situation I am.
>> Hey Caleb, congratulations. You
mentioned that 30 visit while you were
going around and and meeting this
Cowboys coaching staff and Christian
Parker, the defensive coordinator, what
were some of the things they were
telling you about if you did end up here
like you are now where they feel like
they can use you in the secondary to
help this defense.
>> Yeah, just being able to play in uh a
lot of different facets, be able to make
plays near the line of scrimmage and in
the deep part of the field. So, uh was
very interested in how they were going
to use me and um so we'll see how it
goes now and I'm excited.
>> Caleb, welcome to Dallas. you know,
there's a a a obviously a an air that
comes with being a Cowboy and and and a
level of weight that comes with that. Uh
why do you think you're prepared for
everything that comes with being a
Dallas Cowboy?
>> Uh I think I'm just prepared in myself,
honestly. Um I played on big stages
before and I'll continue to be me no
matter where I go and I'm just uh I just
say, yeah, that's just myself. That's
who I am.
>> Caleb, I I want you to talk to fans
about what they are getting, not only on
the field, but off the field. I want you
to talk about your temperament,
everything that uh is Caleb DS that's
going to be arriving in Dallas in the
next 24 hours.
>> Yeah, you're getting a man of faith. Uh
somebody that leaves leads with their
faith first. Um and everything else,
he's just humble and hungry. Uh ready to
go get it. Uh ready to put in the
effort, ready to put in the time to go
out and do it. And uh just just trying
to make an impact, make plays on the
field.
>> And then last year's first round pick
was Tyler Booker. You spent a year with
him at Alabama. Y'all good friends?
>> Great people. Yeah, he was just in the
green room. I gave him a big hug when
they when I walked by him. Uh we lowkey
talked about it a little earlier today.
So, uh I'm just excited. Blessed.
>> Kayla, we heard that you beat coach in a
putting contest. What's our handicapping
golf? What do we got going there? We got
we got sticks.
>> I'm like a 14 and a half handicap. So,
I'm like 86 87 right around there. But
yeah, he had he struggled that day.
>> He struggled. I'll tell you what, they
they've got they've got plenty of great
golf course. I know that golf course at
Ohio State is legendary, but we got we
got some good golf courses here. So,
we're looking forward to having you out
there, man.
>> Well, I'm I'll be out there soon, so you
can count on that.
>> No doubt about it. Caleb, uh, once
again, congratulations on being the
newest Dallas Cowboy. Can't wait to talk
to you a little bit more down the line
and and we'll see you at the Star
tomorrow.
>> All right. Appreciate y'all. Thank you.
>> There he goes. Caleb Down, safety from
Ohio State. Cowboys 11th overall pick
here in the 2026 NFL draft. You're
listening to our 2026 NFL draft coverage
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, back on the.com side. Good
stuff from Caleb DS getting to talk
about his usage possibly with Christian
Parker's defense. Pick is in for the
Buccaneers at pick number 15. They're
pretty fired up in their war room down
in Tampa as the Buccaneers pick right
after the Baltimore Ravens at 14.
If you're Dallas here and and we've
talked about the possibility of trading
back, Nick, you you did a great job of
outlining that a moment ago.
Who are you trying to fall or get to
fall to 20 if you're Tampa, New York,
Detroit, Minnesota, and Carolina
standing between you and the 20th
overall pick?
>> Yeah. Um, if I'm looking at my board,
um, gosh, I I I do like Peter Woods. I
don't think they would take Peter Woods
in this scenario. Uh, we've talked about
their interest in Malachi Lawrence, the
edge rusher out of UCF. Uh, the
assistant defensive line coach for the
Cowboys is Dmitri Brim. Came from UCF
last year. Uh, so there is a connection.
They have in-house connection with with
Malachi Lawrence. Um, so maybe maybe
that's one to keep an eye on. I I don't
want to say I'm completely diminishing
secondary, but I'm looking at secondary
as a less priority now, obviously,
because you have a secondary piece that
can play in so many different ways. So,
I'm looking at edge rusher. Um, and I I
would still would not discount offense
at the end of the day either. So, uh, if
the best player on the board isn't is an
offensive player, what does that look
like? I'm not 100% sure. I really like
Blake Miller out of Clemson. Um, that
that's my highest rated uh offensive
player on the board, but uh, we'd have
to see how it shakes out. Here's the
Buccaneers selection at 15.
>> In the 2026 NFL draft, the Tampa Bay
Buccaneers select Ruben Bane Jr.
>> linebacker Miami.
>> Love that fit.
>> That's a great player at pick number 15.
Tell me a little bit about Ruben Bane
and why they're getting one of the best
players, if not the best player
remaining on the board. Yeah, I've
continued to say year after year that I
I love the way the Buccaneers have
constructed their roster and they have a
pass rush unit that is fit to uh you
know allow Ruben Bane to not have to
play 80% of snaps. He can come in there
and be a 65% snap guy and I think that's
probably what he would be best at at the
NFL level because you see that power.
That power is uh it's tough to deal with
if he's rotating on the field. I'll tell
you that. And you're trying to battle up
against a a long drive and he can put
the end to that really well. He he
closes games out really well, too. And
that that's a demeanor thing. And if you
have that type of demeanor thing as a
defensive lineman, you're going to be
all right. Obviously, the arm length is
a big thing that people worry about. You
see it right there. 30 and 78. It's
going to be one of the shortest arms in
the NFL since 2000. I believe it's top
10 shortest in the NFL since 2000. But
he knows how to use his arm length.
There's a move that he does where he
gets his elbow under the armpit of an
offensive tackle and uses his power to
throw him down. I haven't seen anyone in
my gosh five years looking at draft
prospects to be able to use that move as
effective as Ruben Bane does. If he can
still get away with that at the NFL
level because there is a fine line
between hooking and holding um then he's
going to be really special. I do. And
the the things you worry about with the
arm length of course are okay when he
goes up against these longer tackles,
how can he get under them? How can he
work them into a phone booth? Uh, but I
he's shown many times in his time at
Miami to be able to do that. Uh, I just
love his pass rush arsenal. He's got
multiple moves. Uh, and he can make it
happen for uh, Tampa Bay. I I love I
love the pick.
>> Yeah, he can play a lot of different
spots, too. You'll see him line up up
and down the line of scrimmage there.
He's really a fun player to watch. I The
shorter arms thing, man. For 17 weeks, I
watched him just get past offensive
tackles, guys with longer arms, guys
with more reach. His ability to get
small, to get narrow, to not get let
them get his hand their hands on him, I
think is one of his best traits though.
He has got the f full arsenal when it
comes to rushing the passer. He plays
the run really well. He's super strong.
The leverage that he plays with, the
power he plays with. This was one of my
favorite players watching in the draft.
Ruben Bane 15th overall to the
Buccaneers. The New York Jets are on the
clock at 16
and five picks away from the Cowboys at
20. Who are some of the names that we
should probably start looking at if
we're Dallas remaining on the board that
could be in play there at 20?
>> Um, so I think you are just personally
pretty set in the secondary at this
point or or that's where a lot of your
resources have gone. First, I think the
the top thing I'd wonder about with them
is if they're trying to trade back.
>> Mhm. I think that would be something
where they'd like to potentially pick up
some extra picks if they've if they've
got to stand in there and pick. I don't
know that there's a linebacker that
makes a ton of sense. Maybe CJ Allen
from Georgia. Um, one of these edge
rushers that could potentially be on the
board. We've heard some chatter about
Malachi Lawrence, Keldrick Faulk. Um,
and on the offensive side, Omar Cooper's
still there. I think they like them or
like him. And then one of these
offensive linemen, if they get pushed
down the board, they got him graded high
enough, maybe they take a gamble on a
tackle.
There goes Ruben Bane Jr., one of the
top edge rushers in the NFL draft to the
15th overall selection in the Tampa Bay
Buccaneers. A great pick by Tampa Bay as
they continue to revamp their defensive
side of the football as well. Well,
let's recap the last five selections.
Starting with the Dolphins at the 12th
overall pick after they traded with the
Cowboys up to 11. They take Kaden
Proctor at 12, offensive tackle from
Alabama. The Rams at 13th with one of
the biggest surprises we've seen so far.
Ty Simpson, quarterback from Alabama,
goes 13th to LA. Ravens at 14th overall.
They take Vega Yawan, the offensive
lineman from Penn State, the Buccaneers.
And then at pick number 15, they take
Ruben Bane Jr. edge rusher from Miami.
The New York Jets are on the clock at
the moment. Pick is in. And here's Roger
Goodell.
>> The 16th pick in the 2026 NFL draft, the
New York Jets select, Kenyan Sadique.
>> There you go, Joe.
>> Tight end Oregon.
>> So, they're going two tight ends here.
>> So, the tight end there to the Jets at
pick number 16. Sadique widely thought
of as the number one tight end in the
draft. Bobby, was this kind of an
outside possibility for Dallas at 20?
Just if you're looking at best player
available on the offensive side, even
>> maybe. I I mean, I think he had his fans
here in Dallas. Uh I
I I have a hard time envisioning that
when when it got down to it, if they
would really look at it and go, "All
right, that's the guy we got to take." I
I feel like no matter how the board
shakes out, there would be another
option there. Now, if they were to trade
back a little bit, um, and he were to
still be there maybe in the mid20s,
maybe that falls a little bit more
likely. But I think they liked him. I
just don't know if it was ever going to
shake out on the board the way they they
would have, you know, been in a scenario
where they would have taken him.
>> It's interesting. They took your
favorite tight end in last year's draft,
Bobby Mason Taylor, the tight end out of
LSU in the second round.
>> Yep.
>> Uh, and then they go first round tight
end this year. Kind of an interesting
backtoback. And I mean, the fact that
everybody was so sure they were going to
grab one of these receivers and instead
they've decided to go Sadiq who I mean
obviously is not
>> your classic big build inline tight end
and and maybe could be a little bit more
of a hybrid, but um you know it's
they're probably just looking at it as
get us the best pass catcher possible
>> and that's possibly what they did here.
Tell me a little bit about Sadi, Tommy.
>> Yeah, P pass catching ability is really
the thing that stands out about Sadique.
This is an interesting one, too, because
you think about they drafted Brian's
guy, Mason Taylor, last year, and he had
a solid rookie season for him as well.
Uh, I think he's a freak athlete, really
chiseled build. I think that's evident
when you watch the film. Uh, very
imposing physical attributes. Creates
instant mismatches on linebackers and
slot corners when he's isolated. He's
plenty fast enough to make plays after
the catch. He's got a tendency to miss
some of the layup plays and make easy
catches, but I think he's got plenty of
room to grow there. That's something
that you can work on. uses frame and
physicality better as a blocker in the
run game. Um he kind of struggles I
think in line when he's blocking, but
overall I think you know what he's
giving you and we mentioned Taylor a
little bit there who they picked last
year out of LSU. I think you've got a
pretty solid tandem there for in in New
York.
>> Yeah, probably going to see a little bit
of that uh that two tight end set every
once in a while if they do continue to
think Taylor is the future at tight end
there along with Sadique across the
board. Taking a look at some of the
highlights on the the
internet side of things with Sadi out of
Oregon. 16th overall to the Jets. Now
it's the Lions, the Vikings, the
Panthers, followed by the Cowboys at 20.
>> Was I wrong for just not like loving
Sadi, by the way? Like he was clearly
the best tight end, but I did I did not
like love him.
>> Like, is he going to have a better
rookie year than Harold Fannon had?
>> Probably not.
>> Yeah, that that's kind of how I viewed
it. That's the That's the standard, I
guess.
>> I am I'm known for being pretty uh
bashful against tight end value, though,
in the draft. I I just I think you can
>> I think it burns teams way more often
than it does.
>> Exactly. Exactly. It's
>> even even when they're good, Kyle Pittz
is a good player. Kyle Pittz did not end
up being the guy you wanted to take that
high in the draft.
>> Sure. And that was what, fourth overall?
>> Uh yes, way a couple years back.
>> If you're the Lions here at 17, who are
some of the
>> offensive line?
>> Yeah, left tackle. Yeah, I think that uh
you know again we our Arizona State kid
I that's that's who I would have on if
it
>> who's the top left tackle. Who's the top
right tackle
>> on the board right now?
>> Yep.
>> Left tackle Monroe Freeling right tackle
Blake Miller Clemson.
>> Okay. So if they were to go for whoever
they have graded higher I would guess
that's going to whoever they have graded
higher. I would assume that's going to
depend where Pane Su plays.
>> Yeah.
>> So if they have Miller graded higher SU
goes to left. If they have uh
Freelanding graded higher, then they
keep Su at right tackle.
>> Taking a look into the Cowboys war room
at the moment. Will Mccclelay's got his
hand on the phone.
>> Little quiet though. It seems like he's
just kind of they're they're having a
bit of a conversation here.
He's looking at the phone.
Will is actually trying to explain
something maybe why they would if they
were going to go up, you know, that
maybe that or or the order. Maybe
they're trying to kind of figure out too
if they were to go down who he's maybe
trying to explain the pocket of players
that might be there if they're, you
know, and then maybe on the uh the
you're getting like usually sometimes
the pro guys will get involved and talk
about team needs and then bring that up
and then you know the it helps the the
decision makers with like hey can we
should we go back you know that was a
rule I had in the in the war room myself
is like tell tell me who needs what and
then you kind of explain and that gives
the the Joneses the ability to kind of
say, "Okay, we could trade back and we
should be okay here or we just need to
stay where we're at." As they sit and
and it's the normal situation for those
from left to right at the end of the
table, it's Brian Shottimer, head coach.
He's on the left side. You've got Jerry
Jones in the middle, Steven Jones on the
right side, and then it's a seat that
has Stephen's son, John Steven Jones, in
between him and Will Mle. and will mle
on the right hand side of the screen for
our audio listeners. And both Stephen
and Will have a phone. Stephen has a
phone that he's semi shares with Jerry,
right? Yeah. The the banks of phones, if
you're watching on the site, the the the
banks of phones are all uh geared
towards the NFL team. So, whoever the
decision maker, general managers,
whoever they need to talk to, it's
automatic. Just dial says hit the
button. it goes right to Atlanta or
Tampa, wherever they need to go and then
Will Mcclelay is responsible for to get
the player on the phone. So that's the
phone he deals with with but the bank of
phones in front of them are all either
league office personnel or the various
teams around the league. Roger Goodell
in the slow walk up to the stage as he
has the Lions pick at number 17 overall.
The NFL is proud to be part of the
global community of wish makers taking
action to support Make a Wish during
World Wish Month. Tonight, you all have
the opportunity to help grant an
unforgettable wish.
I'm joined here by Een, a 14-year-old
Lions fan whose wish is to announce the
first round draft pick for his favorite
team.
I'd like to ask all of you to join me in
cheering on East as he makes his wish
come true. Take it away, Eston.
With the 17th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Detroit Lions select, Blake
Miller, tackle Clemson.
>> All right, Penul, you are a left tackle
now.
>> Yeah.
Tell me a little bit about Blake Miller
out of Clemson here and what he's
taking. Don't ask me about Blake Miller.
>> Yeah.
>> Got to ask about Blake Miller because
you say not to ask about it.
>> I I'm I'm Listen, Blake Miller to me,
this is this is the blind spot that I
live with when I do these players. Mhm.
>> 66 315. I don't deal very well with the
nonp powerful guy, offensive tackle, but
this guy is a really good athlete and
he's he's made a lot of starts. He
hadn't missed a start his entire college
career. He does have some bend. He does
have some flexibility for the position.
He's kind of nimble in the way he moves.
He plays well in space. He could be a
little off balance, but he can recover
when he gets pulled out of position.
Majority of his snaps are in two-point
stance. The kick, the slide, all that
stuff's really good. The thing that the
thing that that that you don't see him
do is he doesn't overset too much. So,
he's generally in good football position
to take on the rusher, then kind of get
his hands inside. You could see him that
the defender will put his hands on them
and he'll slap him down and then reset
his hands for that. But then sometimes
there's snaps where his hands will get
too wide and then they and then it and
it's a problem for him. I I just think
that that he's got to go to a team that
utilizes the zone blocking concepts
because he is not a powerful guy. He
just does not get a lot of movement in
the running game. He's more of a shield
get in the way kind of guy.
>> Do the Lions use that more than you
think?
>> I you know with with the Lions with with
Ben Johnson there was a lot of movement
with their offensive line, you know,
with the way that they played. So I
Yeah, there's some concepts of that for
them. I see why they they drafted this
guy, though. Here's the Vikings at 18.
>> With the 18th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Minnesota Vikings select
Caleb Banks.
>> Wow.
>> Defensive end Florida.
>> That was earlier than I thought.
>> Very much so. We'll talk about that in a
matter of moments. It is 19th overall on
the clock. The Carolina Panthers
currently making their selection. And
then it's the Cowboys back on the clock
at 20. You're listening to the 2026 NFL
draft on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com.
>> We
Yes,
>> we have a trade
>> with who?
>> The Philadelphia Eagles.
>> Who Who is Philly trading with?
>> Uh the Dallas Cowboys.
>> Oh, really?
>> Eagles are moving up to 20 uh according
to reports here and the Cowboys are
getting two fourth round picks back.
Okay, so according to reports, nothing
official quite yet, but
>> Dallas would move back three spots and
they would pick up what?
>> Uh, two fourth round picks.
>> Oh,
>> you just walked out of the night with
more capital than you had walking in.
>> You have and Caleb DS. Sorry. What the
picks are?
>> Uh, not at the moment.
>> They may only have two. That that may be
all they have.
Uh looking
here at it in the fourth, the
Eagles have 114
and they have
>> 137.
>> Yeah,
>> that's it.
>> So that's the two the two picks that
Philly had in the fourth round. Those
are two solid picks in a spot where you
didn't necessarily think
>> you were picking at any point.
>> Cowboys Cowboys went on the trade chart
with that. If that's the return,
>> what would that be pointwise? It's about
15 20 points ahead for Dallas.
>> Well, I mean, think about you forget the
points. You moved up one spot to get
Caleb DS
>> and you picked up two fourth round
picks, moving back three spots, and you
gave up two fifths.
>> Say it again in the for the people in
the back, Tommy. Say, forget the forget
the picks. Forget the points.
>> Evidently, it's not, you know, forget
the picks, but forget the points either.
But I'm just saying you you move up one
spot in the first round and take Caleb
Bounds. And if that's the reported
compensation, you get two fourth round
picks, then go ahead.
>> Cowboys also gave up a seventh rounder.
So 218's gone.
>> Okay, so you gave up two. That's
disappointing.
>> There goes the Peyton Hendershot pick.
>> How mad Patterson UT Peran Bas.
>> He's going to be an undrafted free
agent. We'll see.
>> But
>> were you guys surprised by the the the
Banks pick with
>> Yes. Yes, I was.
>> Yeah, very much so.
>> Banks is the most footballlooking player
in the draft. He was the first player
not in my top 100 to get drafted.
>> He was 45 for me and that's mostly
projection.
>> Yeah, the medicals are bad there.
>> Medicals. What are the
>> That's what I was worried about foot,
right?
>> Cape isn't great either.
>> Um production, too.
>> Yeah. I mean, like I said, Caleb Banks
is the guy you draft because it's like
that looks like a football player.
>> When you look at Caleb Banks though, why
does he fit with the Vikings? Why did
they need that compared to some of the
other interior defensive linemen in that
area?
>> Well, everybody for months has been
projecting Theamman or Emil Emanuel
McNeil Moore in there.
>> Yeah. And they did not go that route.
>> Dallas could possibly look at either one
of those guys. Theaman I know was high
on their board. If he's there at 23,
>> I think who we're looking,
>> especially now that there's a trade
back,
>> I think we need to be zeroing in on
Malachi Lawrence here.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, I agree with you on that. As long
as it's Malachi Lawrence and I don't
have to run a 5K with
>> although I would not rule out
>> flippers
>> depending on if there's specific
offensive linemen on the board where
they pick that is not impossible.
>> Yeah, I could see that at 23 especially
with now you only have four picks in
between you and your selection.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh after Banks goes off the board to the
Vikings at 18. Panthers, Eagles,
Steelers, Chargers, and then it's back
to the Cowboys. you're going. It's
likely you could have a tackle that you
like there.
>> Sure.
>> So, good stuff there from Dallas. We'll
recap the trade and give you all of the
extra details as we get back on the
radio side of things and then the
Cowboys will select in the 23rd overall
spot here in the first round. Remember,
>> got Caleb DS already. I feel good about
whatever happens from here on out and
this is just adding to the list. So,
who's the this is receiver or offensive
line for Philly, right?
>> Panthers. Yeah. Yeah.
>> No, no, but Philly Philly trying to come
up to your spot.
>> That could be Mai Lemon.
>> Lemon or I mean, I would think you'd try
to get a big ex receiver like Denzel
Boston has been a very common projection
for Philly, but I'd be surprised if he
went above Lemon and Cooper.
>> How
do we always talk about their safety
play with the Eagles? Uh I mean they
just lost one.
>> I mean is this
>> maybe they're jumping up to get him in?
>> Maybe is this is this to go
>> could be
>> because it's like Reed Blankenship and
all it was always that you know we
always like oh their their safety play
not great. He needs his running mate.
>> They would cycle Chanty Gardner Johnson
in and out of there.
>> That's what I'm saying. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Andrew Makuba was what second round pick
last year too. He just got hurt in it'll
be when he can come back.
>> All right. Here is the selection for
>> they need a quarterback too.
>> Carolina at 19 with Roger Goodell going
to the podium
>> with the 19th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Carolina Panthers select
Monroe Freeling,
>> tackle Georgia,
the trade.
>> All right, the 19th pick in the NFL
draft is in. Monroe Freeling. The tackle
out of Georgia goes to the Carolina
Panthers. That was a name that Dallas
could possibly have had their eye on at
pick number 20. However, the Cowboys are
not on the clock at pick number 20. We
have a interdivisional trade between the
Philadelphia Eagles and the Dallas
Cowboys. Dallas goes back to pick number
23 and swaps two fourthround picks from
Philly. Dallas sends the seventh round
pick in return. So once again, Dallas
goes from 20 to 23 and they pick up two
fourth round picks. One is 114, the
other is 137 and they send a seventh
round pick at 218 to the Eagles to move
back a couple of spots.
>> So according to Adam Shfter, the seventh
round is actually going to Dallas.
>> Oh, so the seventh and two4s
>> according according to Adam Shfter here.
So
>> So that's even more. Okay.
>> I I was a little distracted texting. Did
you just read off the Carolina pick?
>> I did. Yes.
>> Okay. That was somebody that Dallas
would have considered a 20.
>> And that was also part of me reading off
the
>> See, and that's that's why it's good to
listen, Kyle.
>> Sometimes people don't listen very well.
>> That's exactly right. Well, let's listen
to the Philadelphia Eagles pick.
>> He doesn't even know.
>> Here's the pick at 20 for the Eagles.
>> With the 20th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Philadelphia Eagles select
Mai Lemon.
>> There you go.
>> Wide receiver USC.
>> All right. And
>> said this was a possibility, Brian. They
go up to get that receiver. Yeah. AB:
Absolutely. And then this guy, when you
watch him play, man, he is he's got some
he's his ability to go get the football,
the routes that he's able to run across,
uh, the way he gets across the field,
the intermediate stuff, the underneath
stuff, the run after catch. USC has done
a great job of putting some wide
receivers into this draft. He's one of
these guys that rarely misses balls. He
can He's I think he's a really good
route runner. He has a way. He's not
probably the fastest guy, but he's his
ability to separate catch in traffic,
run after catch. A lot of good things
about uh about Lemon. Uh and you know,
the Eagles, you know, they continue to,
you know, they've had some questions
about the wide receiver. We'll see what
they do in fact uh you know, when the
draft is over here. But this this kid
will definitely help them the way he
makes plays.
>> Lemon goes to the Eagles at 20. That is
who Philadelphia felt it was necessary
to trade up and go get Dallas. And they
sent two4s, possibly a seventh. We're
trying to get some clarification. That
was what Adam Sheffer said. Two fours
and a seventh round pick.
>> That was what you're cooking, man.
>> That's good stuff.
>> Oh, they are cooking.
>> So, you basically turned two fives into
two fours and you move picked up an you
move back. you pick and you just you get
Caleb DS dog. Like
>> that's phenomenal drafting.
>> Shouts out to the Cowboys and just
flipping day three. Like that's that's
like you don't lose anywhere in that.
You know what I mean? Like you you get
your guy and day three is much more fun.
I thought that, you know, if you're
going to trade back, you're going to try
to get another day two pick, but I I
won't be stingy. I won't be stingy at
all. Shouts out to them.
>> Well, now the rest of the season is
having a nice night. I will say that was
my top receiver. I hope he stinks now
going to the Eagles, but uh maybe those
crazy eyes will will do some damage for
him. Lemon is very Jaylen Hurst
friendly.
>> He is very he
>> because I think Jaylen Hurst all
>> certified bad ball catcher.
>> Bad ball catcher and and yet guy.
>> Yep.
>> And got a couple things working his way.
I do want to reset things here at the
top of the hour. We've got our all of
our coverage, all 257 picks across the
Dallas Cowboys radio network this
weekend. We are now 20 picks down, still
rolling on in the first round. I'm Kyle
Yas from DallasCowboys.com. We've got
Tommy Yarish from DallasCowboys.com.
Zack Walchuk and Brian Bratis from 1053
the fan the flagship station of your
Dallas Cowboys and Vot Lombardi YouTube
superstar and from Crown Global Media.
Roll into your next tailgate in style
with your own Club Car. The official
golf cart of the Dallas Cowboys. Club
Car lowspeed vehicles deliver the
performance and quality that Cowboys
fans expect with the features and
comfort you command. Visit clubcar.com
today. Just to recap, the Cowboys picked
at 11. They take Caleb DS, the safety
from Ohio State, currently two
selections away from picking again at
number 23 after they trade with the
Philadelphia Eagles.
>> So, we've got the official trade terms
on this trade per the Dallas Cowboys
Twitter account. Uh Dallas receives the
23rd overall pick, 114 and 137. Those
are those two fours. The Eagles receive
20 and that seventh round pick which is
218.
>> What was the second one? 114 and
>> 114 and 137. And so Dallas will have
three picks or excuse me two picks in
three picks essentially because they get
they have 112 already. That was their
fourth round pick. Now they go again two
picks later at 114.
>> So what you're telling me is that we had
it right and Shfter got it wrong.
>> That's what happened. Sorry.
>> And that's why you turn on
dallascowboys.com. You turn on the the
Dallas Cowboys radio network to listen
to your draft coverage just to be safe.
All right, Vatch, you you were out of
the room for a little bit there, except
for the one time you came in to talk
about how great Caleb DS is.
>> If you're Dallas at 23, what are you
looking at with the guys left on your
board?
>> I'm a sicko and I'll go secondary again.
You know what I mean? I mean, that's
just me. I like Cotton Hood a whole
bunch. Uh, has has Dylan Thamman been
drafted yet?
>> He has not.
>> Boy, I would
>> take both safeties.
>> I don't care about nothing. Well,
because in my mind, DS is going to be
more move around. He's going to be more
nickel. Um, also too, I said this back
there, I love what the Cowboys did, like
you you're active in free agency and
Jaylen Thompson, you you get to put the
pressure on the veteran to be like the
lead nickel player guy. So, you're
letting the rookie come in and just,
hey, I get to be a rookie and just
figure it out. And then in like two
years or so, maybe next year, Caleb DS
takes the the the the whole thing over.
But why I'm such a sicko, man, put Dylan
The on the roof and leave him on the
roof and you get to move Caleb DS and do
what you want. I'm me personally, I'm a
sicko and Dylan Theamman on my board, I
know he's really he's really high on
Tommy's board there. He's 16 on mine. So
if you take him at 23 and he's 16 on the
board, that's value right there.
>> Do you have a first round grade on him?
>> Second round grade. I had 12 I had 12
first round grades.
>> I had 17 overall. So that would be
second round for me.
>> Top of the second for me.
>> He's 14. He's my last first round grade.
>> There you go.
>> Wreck 17 for me. I had a second. There
you go.
>> We all in the same place.
So, do we all have we all have Lawrence
after him?
>> Yes.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I got Lawrence as 24 and that's still a
good value for him to
>> 23 for Lawrence.
>> I want to recap the last four selections
before we get the Pittsburgh Steelers in
their hometown pick. I know that's
probably going to take a little bit of
time as they're on the clock and their
pick is in at 21. Let's go back to the
Lions at 17. They take Blake Miller,
offensive tackle out of Clemson.
>> Athlete, good feet. The Vikings take
Caleb Banks, the interior defensive
lineman from Florida.
>> Big DT tackle.
>> Nah, big D tackle.
>> Very big.
>> Lot of room to grow. I thought that was
I thought that was a little high for
Banks for me though. I would assume if
you're going to go tackle some some guys
that I had hires like Kate McDonald, Lee
Hunter. I would have rather have gone
those guys early after them. That's
that's that's their business.
>> The Panthers in 19 taking Monroe
Freeling, offensive tackle from Georgia,
who was a possible offensive tackle
target for Dallas in these later picks.
And then the Eagles take Mia Lemon, the
wide receiver from USC
at 20th in the trade with Dallas. So
it's the Steelers on the clock. Their
pick is in Chargers at 22 and then the
Cowboys picking again at 23.
>> Based on how the board is looking,
remember this is the second tier of
players that we've talked about through
the entire draft process, right? where
you get outside of those early names.
You're picking from a similar group of
guys, maybe different positions, but
similar value of guys from pick 20
through about 40. Do you think Dallas is
looking at a possible trade back again
and maybe picking up more value later in
the draft?
>> I I would There's a lot of players here
that I'd be very interested in. I mean,
Chris Johnson, the quarterback from San
Diego State, is probably my top guy.
Colton Hood right after him, the
cornerback from Tennessee. Theamman
still there. I'm with you, Vot. That
would not turn me away from taking
Theamman. Uh Jacob Rodriguez, anybody
who has listened to to my content
leading up to this knows that I
absolutely love him. I think that's way
too rich for now. So, I'd like them to
move back. Here is the Steelers hometown
selection in pick number 21.
>> Football players up there.
Yeah. fitting jersey.
>> They only have certain sizes and
numbers. How he gets under there,
>> Jerome
gets under.
>> The Jerome Bettis
Leadership Award recognizes high school
football players who demonstrate
leadership, character, and service both
on and off the field. Congratulations to
each of you.
>> We wish all of you the best as you
continue your football journeys.
The last time I introduced the Steelers
first round pick, I was fortunate to
introduce TJ White.
>> And with the 21st pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Pittsburgh Steelers select
Max
>> Ehanur
State.
>> I love that pick for them.
>> Talk ahead and protect him. Why you like
him that much? You know, I would not be
surprised if he ends up being the best
tackle in this either when it's all said
and done. I mean, this is a guy, his
story is incredible with him being
Canadian. Uh he's only played football
for a few years, but he's just so raw
and the talent is outstanding. He didn't
start playing football until junior
college in 2021. The upside's through
the roof. The technique does need to
improve, the consistency, but I mean,
this guy is one of those guys that plays
with power. He sustains. Once he gets a
hold of you, it's game over. the grip
strengths there. He's got the ability to
reset and adjust with athleticism and
footwork. You see the basketball playing
background in him sometimes as well. I I
think he's a guy that you see him
improve throughout the game. He kind of
gets a feel for what defensive ends and
and edge rushers are trying to do to him
and he works a plan. I mean like the
football IQ and the intelligence I it's
there. I mean he the athleticism is
outstanding. I think he could play left
tackle if they need him to or right. He
will dirt people. I like the play
temperament. He can play mean. This
guy's just getting started and and much
like I I talked about Sunny Styles
earlier, I mean, this dude's an
ascending football player and and you're
banking on a little bit of a projection,
but the tape's fantastic. I mean, if you
guys were out there, you got to see him
at the Senior Bowl. He was awesome.
Absolutely outstanding.
>> He was one of the best offensive linemen
in Mobile when we were out there at
Hancock Whitney Stadium. When it when
you look at this guy, you look at all of
the intangible, like you said, the
traits are great. He moves well, he hits
well, he's got some physicality. He also
when you turn on the film against TCU,
Texas Tech, Colorado with no matter who
you faced in the Big 12 and some of
those high-end edge rushers that he went
up against, he he handled them quite
well, Brian. And I thought for somebody
that still has so much room to grow, 21
may be a little bit rich for me, but the
ceiling is there for a guy at the
position that still new at what he does.
>> I got friends in the Steeler scouting
department. I just text them. I said, "I
love you guys." uh the the this guy
right here when you watch him play and I
mean everything about him there's the
the the way that he goes about that for
him to only be playing football since
>> man it does not look that way you see
him sit down on rushers you see him like
those watch the Texas Tech film
>> just watch those watch how he deal he
dealt with those guys he does a really
good job of finishing blocks I can only
see this guy getting better he did have
some shoulder surgery stuff in the
spring, but it appears it didn't bother
him in the fall. But man, he is he is
one of these guys. It's just beautiful
to watch a guy that's 66 325 move the
way that he does. By the way, the pick
is in for the Chargers at 22 overall.
And that means the Dallas Cowboys are on
the clock at number 23 at the moment.
having a conversation inside the war
room in what will be their second pick
in the first round after they take Caleb
DS the safety out of Ohio State at pick
number 11. What are we talking about
here in terms of the war room? Will
Mcclelay is pretty adamant here having a
conversation with the end of the table
with Steven Jones, Jerry Jones, and
Brian Shottton.
>> This is when this is when it it it it
talks about, you know, maybe they've got
a couple of guys in their stack. They're
right there with each other. They
probably are just making sure that
they're talking through it. You know, is
there possibility we're talking about
them potentially trading down again? Uh,
you know, maybe Will's explaining, hey,
we need to stand here and pick this
player. Let's not move down again. You
know, everybody's having a little bit of
an opinion about, but uh, you know,
obviously I think they've got their guy.
I think they've got their guy. I just
think that they're waiting to see like,
okay, is there is there a way that we
can maybe move back, get some more
capital, and maybe there's another guy
we like right there. But just making
sure I think Will is trying to get
everybody on the same page like, hey, we
like this guy because and getting into I
think Jerry's Jerry's kind of making
sure of that, too. He's he's making sure
that everybody's completely uh locked in
uh to uh to who they're going to take
here. All right, the Chargers just took
22nd overall edge rusher from Miami.
Hakee Mesador, the opposite side from
Ruben Bane. One of the elder players of
the draft. He's going to be nearly 26 by
the time his first NFL season comes to a
close, but man, he was uber productive
with the Hurricanes this past year and
he goes to the Chargers at 22.
>> He does everything, man. Good good verse
the run, good verse the pass play, a
little bit of B gap as well. uh double
digit sacks, put put pass rush to move,
put pass rush moves. Yeah. Uh counters
and all this kind of stuff. Like if he
wasn't, and look, I really don't care
that he's 25 years.
>> I don't either.
>> Or that or that his foot was hurting. If
if he was 21, he'd probably be a top 10
player in his draft. Just just based on,
hey, I'm on the other side of Ruben Bane
and sometimes I look a little better
than him. That's just how I feel
personally. And he was uh what 13 on my
board. So, I mean, you know, shouts out
to them. Good value.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> He wins in so many different ways. Uh, I
think he's where he's at his best is
when he's moving his hands. I think
that's where you see the Arsenal pass
rush moves and clearly you just saw him
go to another level this past season. It
might have taken a while, but he finally
put it all together and, you know, I
think he's similar to Bane in the sense
that you might be able to move him up
and down the line a little bit. Like Vch
pointed out, this is a good pick and I
think it it probably would have been an
option for Dallas, too, had had he not
gone here to 22.
>> Will is being very animated. Yeah, I
think this is kind of reminiscent of
like the Mazy Smith debate he had.
>> Well, I think this very need
just just for point of reference like
he's explaining the two players and this
is why I Yeah, I totally agree with you
on this one.
>> How much do coaches play a factor now
compared to in the past because that was
in the past a little bit with Mike
McCarthy and his Ryan Shottimer and
Christian Parker have been very very
connected through this entire draft
process. I think this is where like the
coaches do get involved. And this is
where I think that Jason Garrett back in
the day would have stood up. I think
that's why Brian Shottenheimr is going
to stand up. He's kind of surveying what
everybody's talking about. And maybe
he's going to be the guy that kind of
steps in. You remember with the Dak
Prescott when they drafted Dak. It was
Jason Garrett that stood up and kind of
made the final final speech. Sure.
>> In order to get this uh to get that
pick. So, yeah. I I think that you know
it looks like to me Brian's given
everybody a lot of a lot of leeway here
and Will trying to explain exactly they
got they got the consensus.
>> I mean look to me it it'd be Malachi
Lawrence. You just had an edge go at
Keem Meadors off the board. My next best
edge is Malachi Lawrence and I think
this dude the production's been there
throughout his entire career at UCF. If
he ends up being the pick we can get
more into that but I mean that's a name
that we had heard that they might be
interested in. Kendrick Folks also
there. I know for Kyle's sake let's not
do that. Zion Young is another name
that's an all-around team. The size is
there, but if you want a true edge
that's going to get after the
quarterback, the best one on the board
for me right here would be Malachi
Lawrence.
>> Who are some of the other names that we
could possibly throw into the fold here
if Dallas is having the conversation now
that the pick is in? You see Christian
Parker, he's the first one up to come
up. So, thinking defensive side looking
for other position coaches. Uh Colton
Hood maybe
>> Hood they loved him and I think they
would actually take him at 12. So to get
them here, that'll be fantastic value
for them.
>> Yeah, interesting stuff.
>> And then and then just thinking about
Cowboys as like cornerback room. They
got a bunch of dudes that can play
nickel, but how many of those guys are
like trusted outside guys the whole
time? I think Cotton Hood's would fit
fantastic in that.
>> Hood, Chris Johnson, both those guys are
right there for me. Chris Johnson's at
14, Hood's at 16. And then I I wonder
about the linebacker. I mean, this to me
is probably too early to take those
guys.
>> Yeah, I think so, too.
>> It wouldn't be for me. I'd take
Rodriguez, but for them, I think it
definitely is.
>> Yeah, the two corners that I've got,
I've got Chris Johnson, San Diego State
above Colton Hood, but they do love
Colton Hood from Tennessee. Uh, I
wouldn't be surprised at all that's
here, but like Kyle said, we'll see if a
position coach comes up here.
>> Still don't see anybody yet in terms of
position coaches. Brian Shottimer just
handed the phone back to John Steven
Jr., so they're done on the phone,
>> it looks like, or at least they're move
maybe they're moving the phone. Still no
position coaches. I think I think I
think we're right about Malachi
Lawrence. I think we are. I I think
because to me talking to people in the
organization, it was like they were
never comfortable taking him like at 20,
but if they backed up and they didn't
have to go too far, they just went they
went back a couple of spots. So, I I
think this is I think this is Malachi
Lawrence. This this makes this pick
makes me happy because I think they've
got run defenders. M
>> we've all seen this guy play live and
the way that he comes off the football,
the way he's able to redirect things
like that. If this is a pick, this guy
gives them a legitimate pass rusher that
that's got all the counter moves.
>> One thing that was told to us throughout
the draft process is that if it comes
down to a couple of players, a lot of
times they will tend to look at and get
the input of Christian Parker on the
defensive side. He's going to break some
ties throughout the weekend, not just
here, but across the board. And one guy
that has loved Malachi Lawrence from the
jump
>> has been Christian Parker. So, if that
ends up being the case, Yeah, maybe. So,
if if that ends up being the case, and
he is indeed the pick here at 23rd
overall, then I think Christian Parker
has not only an influence, but a very
heavy influence in the draft room in his
first year here in Dallas,
>> which I think he he earned. I mean the
pedigree that he's got if he at we've
heard that he was super involved in
taking Cooper Dean who fell to the
second round and then of course Quinion
Mitchell who went late first in Philly.
>> All right, Roger Goodell is on his way
to the stage in Pittsburgh. The Dallas
Cowboys selection at 23 overall
>> from the Eagles. So they improve those
picks to take this one.
With the 23rd pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Dallas Cowboys select Malachi
Lawrence defensive end University of
Central Florida.
>> So with their two picks in the first
round, the Cowboys get a game changer in
the secondary with Caleb DS at pick
number 11. And then a dozen picks later
at 23rd overall, they take Malachi
Lawrence, a difference maker in the
front seven. Votch, tell me about the
UCF product.
>> Bursty of feel, counters, counters,
counters. Uh, ton of tools. What I liked
about the most is it it didn't look like
he rushed with a plan, but he rushed
with a feel. Like, I feel like something
is coming, so let me spin here. I feel
like this is here. Let me go in my bull
rush and all these other kind of moves
like this. I love how he just effort,
high effort, tempo, all this kind of
stuff. I even seen him change like
change tempo at the line of scrimmage.
come off slow a little bit, breeze past
you, or I'm just gonna fly off the
football because I've been setting you
up with, you know, tempo the whole game.
I love Malik Lawrence pass rush. He's
going to be standing outside. Watching
the film, you know, they use him as like
a fourey type guy sometimes. I didn't
like that at all. So, I would imagine in
Cowboy land, he would be standing
outside linebacker. Fantastic pick for
them.
>> Man, this is I mean, Brian knows I I I
love this guy. All Big 12 first team.
He's had at least five sacks every
single year of the last three years. He
just understands leverage. Like this is
a guy who is always putting himself in a
favorable position with his pad level to
make it incredibly difficult to get
hands on him. He can manipulate
offensive linemen. He triggers quickly
to shoot shoot gaps, get in the run
game. I think he's much better versus
the run than people have given him
credit for. I mean, he's one of these
guys that's also always attacking the
football. You want to force turnovers.
He's looking to strip the football away.
He can play three-point. He's also very
effective in a two-point stance. The
play recognition's there. He's playing
with his eyes. He's got patience. uses
his arm to extend with power, keep
lineman off his chest, the dip unders,
he was one of my favorite players in the
entire draft to get downs and get
Malachi Lawrence. This is an all-time
night to be a Dallas Cowboy fan in my
opinion. And you have some extra capital
in day three that you can play around
with as well with a couple of picks in
the fourth round from the Philadelphia
Eagles by trading back from 20 to 23.
The Browns are on the clock at pick
number 24. We'll continue our reaction
with Malachi Lawrence, edge rusher from
UCF, being taken by the Cowboys at the
23rd overall pick in this NFL draft.
We'll have secret audio and we will hear
from Malachi Lawrence himself in the
coming moments. You're listening to the
2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
radio network and DallasCowboys.com.
All right, continuing our reaction here.
Tommy Malachi Lawrence, edge rusher.
Where are they going to play him in that
34 base 425 front that we're going to
see a lot of the time with Christian
Parker?
>> Yeah. Outside linebacker, I think, you
know, this is a little bit different
from as a Rocku pick in the second round
last year where he's a little bit of a
smaller guy, but he still had that kind
of savviness to him. I think you're
getting a player in Lawrence who's
bigger, 6'4, 253 pounds, who's got a
strong blend of that size, speed,
athleticism. What popped to me, and
you'll see it here on some of these
clips, when he beats his guy and turns
that corner, how fast he closes. It
feels like it is lightning quick. And he
has a knack for kind of reaching out for
the football, too, and trying to knock
it away. He had a couple forced fumbles
last season along with seven sacks. So,
>> um, that that's what really stands out
to me. His get off is great. There's a
lot to like here. I think still too, his
foot his best football is in front of
him. But this is a guy that I think
Christian Parker, the defensive
coordinator, really liked. And again, we
we mentioned it a little bit, but you
are seeing how much of an impact he is
having on the draft strategy here to
turn this defense around. The Cowboys
needed help in the pass rush and now a
different Lawrence is coming into town
to to help them in that department. I
mean, just look at that. He he he just
flies around that corner and arms are
extended. He's looking to knock the ball
free. Missed it that time. Almost got
him the second time and then brings him
down on the ankle tackle on that play.
>> Yeah, this guy's super disruptive when
you watch him play. I mean, he is
relentless effort. Uh the pursuit, the
scouts will tell you that he's a really,
really good character guy. Uh he can win
inside, he can win outside with the way
he rushes. You'll see him chase the
quarterback out of the pocket, then run
them down. He can redirect if he gets
too far up the field. If he's going to
need a little work on something, it's
going to be on his strength. Uh you
know, as far as taking on some blockers
at the point of attack, but his rushing
the passer will be his calling card
until he kind of figures out some things
about how to defend the run. He he is he
sure looks the part for the position
when you stand next to him on a on a
football field.
>> When you look at his production and and
what he continued to do at UCF, which I
I thought was just really an interesting
story. He stayed at UCF all the way
through. Yeah. Uh first team all Big 12.
He led the team in forced fumbles, led
the team in sacks, he had seven of them
last year. Tackles for loss, he had 11.
Uh he was also honorable mention all Big
12 back in 2023. He finished top 10 in
UCF history in sacks. He had 20 over his
career. Played four full years there uh
with the Knights down in Orlando. So,
you talk about loyalty, you talk about
traits, you talk about athleticism, all
of that off the charts for a guy that,
like you said, I like the way you put
that, Tommy. It's another Lawrence.
Maybe not Tank Lawrence, but it's
Malachi Lawrence that comes in. We got
to give him a new nickname. uh and then
see what he can do off the uh the edge
there for the Cowboys after being picked
23rd.
>> Played a little tight end in high
school, too. Did he really?
>> Maybe he's got some uh flexibility if
you want to put him out there in some
>> throw him out there. Some like red zone
stuff.
>> Yeah, why not? Shotp put medalist as a
junior in 2020.
>> Hey, shot just find little nuggets.
Now's the time to just kind of unload
him right now.
>> That's the That's the second shot put
medalist on this roster, I believe. I
think Otto Aona, the nose tackle, was
also Pan-American Games medalist in the
shot. you just off the behind me.
>> Nugget of the night. Yeah. Katy Taylor
guy.
>> Okay, here's the Browns selection and
pick number 24. Roger Goodell. Take it
away.
>> In the 2026 NFL draft, the Cleveland
Browns select KC Conpion.
>> That's a great pick. Texas&M.
>> Okay,
>> everybody. Texas A&M Aggies stand up,
right? And the KC Conpsion pick. Man,
this guy can do a little bit of
everything.
>> I know. He's one of these dudes when you
read your notes on him, like, did I have
Casey Conpsion too slow or too low on
this?
>> Did you?
>> I might have. Where' you have him?
>> I think he's fantastic on my stack.
Let's see. I put a two on him. I had him
as my 28th best player.
>> He was 19 for me.
>> Welcome in. Just a couple moments ago,
the Dallas Cowboys with the 23rd pick in
the 2026 NFL draft select Malachi
Lawrence, edge rusher from UCF. They
pair him with Caleb DS and the two first
round picks are made by the Cowboys in
the first round. We continue on with
YouTube superstar Vach Lombardi. We've
got Brian Bratis and Zack Walchuk from
1053, the fan from DallasCowboys.com,
Tommy Yish, and myself. I'm Kyle Yman's.
Glad you're with us all the way through
the NFL draft this weekend from the star
in Fris. Momentarily, we will hear the
secret audio from Malachi Lawrence.
We'll get to talk to him on the phone
lines. And then we are at the 24th pick
in the NFL draft. Casey Conception, the
wide receiver from Texas A&M, goes to
the Browns at pick number 24. Less than
10 picks remaining in the first round.
Things moving quickly with that 8
minutes on the clock instead of the
traditional 10 that we've had over the
last few years. Things are moving
quickly, which means it's not very long
until we'll hear from the Cowboys front
office after their first round
selections. And Brian, they've done some
moving and shaking, but it's worked out
in their favor.
>> It absolutely has. And and then there
was some talk about them going, you
know, going up in the draft. You know,
they they, you know, the the words we
were starting to hear, you know, when
people were saying, "No, they're going
to sit there. They're going to be
comfortable. They're going to they're
going to pick the players. They're going
to let the board come to them. There was
some things happened in front of them.
They I felt like they caught a huge
break with with with with Cleveland
taking Feno that opened up the Giants
being able to take uh you know Malaninoa
there at 10. So it it just really worked
out for the Cowboys very well on that
aspect. and then to back up a little
bit, pick up some, you know, some draft
capital for day three and to get a guy
that they were talking about trading
back for that maybe they didn't like him
at 20, Lawrence, but maybe at 24, maybe
at 26, maybe if you traded with Kansas
City at 29, that was where Malachi
Lawrence, but where he was taken uh
right there at 23 was, you know, where
Dallas was completely comfortable with
that. I was very outspoken over the last
week about Malachi or about Kendrick
Faulk specifically and how confident I
was that Dallas would not take Kendrick
Faulk in the first round.
>> He was right down.
>> The reason why is because of Malachi
Lawrence. They were so
>> infatuated with Malachi Lawrence all the
way through this draft process that
>> when it came down to it and the value
stacked up specifically, I don't think
Kendrick Faulk's a bad player. No,
Malachi Lawrence just had the eye of the
Cowboys so much so over the last week
that when it came down to it, whether it
was at 12, whether it was at 20, whether
it was in a tradeback scenario, I think
or I thought no matter what, just based
off of what they were talking about with
Malachi Lawrence and how highly they had
him regarded, they were never going to
look at Kendrick Faulk over a Lawrence.
Now, if Malachi Lawrence went earlier,
he goes before 20, he goes before 23 in
this scenario, then I think Kelrick
Faulk is maybe in play, but with
everything that had led up to this
point, it was very much so going to be
Malachi Lawrence over Kendrick Faulk.
And they stuck to their board and they
ended up making the pick. That's why I
really do like this selection. They were
they were convicted in what he brings to
this defense. And now you pair him with
secondary help that you had at the 11th
overall pick. Dallas has done some
phenomenal work in the first round of
this draft.
>> Also too, Kyle, the the Cowboys have
done a ton to like fix the the rundown
stuff, but you still needed pass rush.
You still want somebody that was kind of
twitchy and bendy and Kendrick Faulk,
shouts out to him. But the big talk
around him is that, hey, he can develop
into maybe one day he can be possibly
Malachi Lawrence is ready to rush the
passer right now. He's ready to grow as
a pass rusher, right? far ahead of Faulk
as a pass rusher. So, they just let you
know that the Cowboys had that more in
mind than to bring in a a bigger edge to
be a a rundown guy.
>> So, with that being said, one of the
things Dallas targeted throughout the
draft process are guys that are NFL
ready that can contribute right this
second on the defensive side. Tommy,
Caleb DS, Malachi Lawrence, where do
they fit in specifically as NFL ready
production right now going into 2026?
>> I think Caleb DS is absolutely a
plug-and-play starter. The the bigger
question is going to be where. We've
talked a lot about nickel. That seems
like the most likely option, but I
wouldn't be surprised if over the course
of a game. Excuse me. You see Caleb DS
move into a lot of different spots
across the field. Malachi Lawrence, I
think, has a good base for where he
started at, but I think there still is
room to grow, not just in the pass rush
department, but as a run defender as
well. Still though, that base is pretty
solid. And I think again, we talk about
Christian Parker liking Lawrence as a
prospect. And the Cowboys right now have
to trust that. And clearly they've shown
they have a lot of trust in the
evaluation of Christian Parker and how
he evaluates defensive players. So
that's that's what we're working with
right now. I think DS is more pro ready
than Lawrence is. But Lawrence has a I
think bright future as a pass rusher.
>> What's interesting now and I'm looking
at Zack because I know you really do
value what is happening in the second
round of this draft.
>> Now we wait.
>> Dallas Dallas didn't make a move to get
a second round pick. They made their
first two picks. They stuck in in and
and they they traded up a little bit to
go get Caleb DS at 11. They trade back
and go get Malachi Lawrence at 23. But
ultimately, they are now done unless
something crazy happens and they use
future draft capital
>> to come up and get a player or maybe
later draft capital now that they have
two fourth round picks, but they're
probably done until 92 or at least
around that area.
>> Yeah. And it's one of those where you
have those two fours now.
>> Mhm. If there is a player in the second
round, specifically a linebacker,
whether that is, and please let it be
Jacob Rodriguez from Texas Tech, or
maybe for a feeling you were going that
direction.
>> Maybe for them it's CJ Allen, you know,
from Georgia. You know, I'm not sure how
they have these linebackers stacked, but
if they somehow came away at tomorrow,
>> here's the Bears at 25.
>> With the 25th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Chicago Bears select Dylan
Daman. Oh, that's a great pick. A hell
of a pick.
>> That fits great for Chicago. I mean, I
know this was one of the top players you
had on your board, Tommy. Tell me a
little bit about Dylan Theamman.
>> Yeah, 14th overall player on my board.
He's a hybrid safety. I think he can
operate all over the field in coverage
and he can step up into the box, play
against the run really well for you, and
you have no worries at all against I
think that really flashed on his Oregon
tape. I think Purdue, you saw him cover
more of the deep part of the field just
because they didn't really have the
defensive assets to cover that part of
the field. At Oregon, you saw a lot of
things taken off of his shoulders and he
still shined. I felt like can at times
be a little bit overaggressive when he's
coming downhill and tackling, but I
really just don't see a lot of flaws in
his game. uh quiet I think like I said
that quieter production this last year I
think is only because the increased
caliber of players around him on that
Oregon defense but uh Chicago can play
him really wherever they want to they
lost their safety pairing of Jaquan
Brisker and Kevin Bard in free agency so
this is a guy that you know they signed
Kobe Bryant from the Seahawks they
they've got themselves a new safety tanm
that safety tandem last year had a lot
to do with them going to the playoffs
and even if you want to play him at
nickel I I think that you can do that
too. There isn't really a lot that
Theamman can't do.
>> Yeah, he also returned punts uh during
his time there at Purdue. All Big 10 uh
led all Big 10 defensive backs and
tackles his sophomore year. I mean, the
dude just has a nose for the ball. Plays
single high. Everything you nailed, you
nailed the guy there, uh Tommy, in terms
of the description of him, I will say.
Okay, cuz I was waiting for the pause. I
was waiting for it. You didn't give it
to me. We talked about playing with your
eyes. All right. This guy's got a
tremendous feel for the game. I think
he's a big hitter. You can play him down
in the box. But I do love the Purdue
tape with him as a pre safety, the
interceptions, taking the football away.
This dude's uh definitely a
differencemaker in the secondary.
>> I will say there was a list of names
that if the Cowboys got wiped out that
it was just being thrown around at at at
12. Theamman wasn't named like that.
Faulk wasn't named like that. I even
heard like Peter Woods was a name like
that. I'm just glad that it worked out
the way it worked out. You know what I'm
saying?
>> I am a little bit surprised that it
wasn't Peter Woods. I think I think they
need the defensive line. Not that again,
not that Theamman is not a good player.
I actually have Woods higher. Woods is a
first round grade for me. I think it was
just a matter of usage at Clemson. Um
I'm surprised that the Cal, excuse me,
Chicago didn't go defensive tackle
there.
>> He's the highest play or highest player
remaining on my board. Uh as Peter Woods
uh could possibly uh go very quickly
after this, we need to step aside. We
are currently in the 26th overall
selection of the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> Back here on the internet side of
things, as I was trying to say and
couldn't quite get out there, Peter
Woods, number one remaining player on my
board. Uh he was touching tags with
Dylan Phenomenan. So, I I still think
that's good value and it makes sense for
Chicago there at 25. Feedman was the
number 16 player uh on my stack across
the board. He was the very top of the
second round. So, with that being said,
you look at some of these other names
available. Where do you like uh who do
you like that's still remaining on the
back half of this first round? the the
thing that I feel like that me
personally now looking you know as we go
here 25 picks in
>> I didn't get these cornerbacks right
>> I don't feel like that I got now McCoy
because of the need
>> was and now you're talking about Terrell
and and Vot you and I talked about this
a bunch
>> did we get these guys right did we get
were there too many questions were there
were there guys like Terrell whose film
was good put in the first round, but he
runs 464.
>> Sure.
>> You know, what are teams? And then Hood.
We really like Hood. We like Cece. I
know. I like Cece.
>> But all the top the guys, all the top
guys I have left are these corners.
>> See, Brian, I was higher on corners and
edges than I was the offensive tackles.
The offensive tackles went early, but I
thought that Mason Thomas, I thought
that like, you know, Cash Cashes How
would be in this range somewhere. And
then my my corners, Hood, Cece, Terrell,
Abney, Johnson. I just knew that they
was going to be going around this time,
but maybe they're going to be the guys
that that go um higher in the second
round here.
>> Yeah, I think a second round run. But
the the thing was,
>> you know, with with McCoy again, McCoy,
the injury, the knee is all that you
could watch that. That's that's okay. I
just put him where, you know, the film
is good. You go back and watch the 2024
film. I'll I'll finish my thought after
this. Here's the Texans at 20 26, excuse
me. Traded up with Buffalo.
>> The Houston Texans select Keelin Rutled
guard Georgia Tech.
>> They traded up to do that.
>> Yeah, they sure.
>> The Texans traded 26 and 91 to Buffalo
for 2869 and 167.
>> Interesting. So, they jumped the 49ers
to go get Keen Rutled.
>> Okay.
>> Guard out of Georgia Tech.
>> Physical player.
>> Uhhuh. strong uh body mover, you know
what I'm saying? Uh I thought he was a a
pretty solid guard. Yeah, I got four
other guards ahead of him. But uh hey,
shout out to Ke Rage. I thought he was a
bit, you know, he didn't have the best
lateral movement and all that. He's not
but he's not like a zone type guard.
He's a guard that if you're going to,
you know, try to move guys like that's
what he does well. I just thought it was
some better move guy guards on the board
right now. There's a bit high for me. I
I I got relig in the in the third, but
them take him here. Shouts out to him.
>> Player 79 on my board. So yeah, I
thought there was some limitations with
him as a player, but man, you you watch
him play, he's a powerful guy and but
the the movement and stuff like that, I
think was a little bit lacking with him.
>> I just had guys like Farmer and Pon and
Dunker had those guys.
>> I mean, I I love is it pregnant?
>> I'm just going to call him Pon because
it can't be it just can't be pregnant.
>> He was actually my top guard. I had him
slightly over Vega. I I I and that might
have been one of my hot takes, I guess,
in the draft, but I loved him. Rutled I
had as as a second rounder right behind
Chase Basantis from Texas A&M, but I do
love the way he plays. I mean, the dude
the dude's mean. He moves people. Uh
he's constantly turnurning his feet. I I
do think it's a little bit of a reach
for me, but hey, when it comes to
offensive lineman, go for it, man. Go
get your guy. We saw that with Travis
Frederick here.
>> Yeah, that's true. some of the more
skeptical picks that you've ever made.
And you never really know what other
teams are looking at, too. They're if
they're sitting in there at 28 and
they're hopping in front of the 49ers
and trading with the Bills to to get
that deal done. Maybe they have intel
that the 49ers were looking at them.
>> Sure.
>> And so you you still want to get your
guy, but you go and you use a little
bit. That's kind of what Dallas did to
go get their guy.
>> Hey, teams draft certain kind of ways,
Kyle. Okay. Shouts out to him.
>> No doubt about it. So the 49ers, you
know what you really want to say. Great.
Grades vary.
>> Uh-huh. Yeah, they do. They do. The
49ers traded this pick to Miami. So, the
Dolphins are on the clock at 27. Then
it's followed by the Bills who just
flipped picks with the Texans, followed
by the Chiefs, the 49ers, and the
Patriots Seahawks. Final now six
selections of the first round in the
2026 NFL draft. We still got an hour and
20 minutes of coverage tonight as we
continue on through the weekend.
>> Yeah.
>> So, Miami has this pick currently then,
right?
>> Yeah. The terms were San Francisco gets
30 and 90. Dolphins get 27 and 138.
A little bit of surprise in the 2026 NFL
draft at spot number 26 as the Texans
trade up from the 28th pick and they
take Keelin Rutled, offensive lineman
out of Georgia Tech, who most of us on
the panel had as a day two possibility,
but the Texans felt like they got their
guy and and they take him at 26 overall.
Recapping the last five picks real
quick. The Chargers take Aake Meador,
edge rusher from Miami. The Cowboys at
23, take Malachi Lawrence, edge rusher
from UCF. Browns take Casey Conpioner,
wide receiver from Texas A&M. The Bears
have a good pick with Dylan Theamman,
the safety out of Oregon at 25. And then
the Texans, of course, with Keelin
Rutled as we just mentioned out of
Georgia Tech. Back with F Lombardi,
Brian Bratis, Zack Walchuk, Tommy
Yarish. I'm Kyleman's now joined by the
newest Dallas Cowboy, Malachi Lawrence,
edge rusher from UCF is on the line.
Malachi, congratulations.
What was that moment like getting the
phone call from Jerry Jones in the
Cowboys front office?
>> Uh, it was amazing. Uh, it was like
first things all glory to God, but it
was it was a blessing and a dream come
true. Been playing football since I was
five and always wanted to play in the
NFL. So, like I said, it was an amaz
It's something I can't even explain.
>> No doubt about it. I'm going to ask you
to explain it a little bit. Malachi, you
you stayed there at UCF. You you
finished top 10 in terms of their career
sack leaders, and you're one of the best
players in program history. What does it
mean to you and your family to now have
the the first round tag next to your
name and get to live out that dream now
here in Dallas?
>> Right. Like I said, it's a blessing. Uh
a dream come true. like you said. Um I'm
just ready to come in and work. Like
like you said that first round tag like
at the beginning of this year I just
didn't even I couldn't dream of it but
like just the work that I put in like
like I said all glory to God and I'm
just proud of myself and thankful for
the people that helped me along the way.
>> Malachi, congratulations, man. Welcome
to the Dallas Cowboys. We can't wait to
have you here. What's the relationship
like with you and Coach Brim, who's also
now on staff here in Dallas, and how
much did that maybe help during this
process?
>> Right. Uh, my relationship with Coach
Brim is great. I think it helped
definitely a lot. Um, like I said, we
were at UTF together. He helped us a lot
with film work, uh, as well as on the
field just giving us little tips and
then like just having those one-on-one
talks with him was just a great thing to
have. And then just being able to have
him in Dallas now, that's just like I
said, it's a great thing to happen.
>> Malachi, welcome, welcome, welcome. You
know, just watching your film, you know,
some guys rush with a pass rush plan and
you know, surely you do, too. But just
watching you, it seems like you pass
rush more on feel, like something
happens and you just kind of react to
it. Uh, you know, break down break down
how do you pass rush and put different
rush moves together,
>> right? Um, like you said, it kind of
comes off field and also like just game
plan and watching film and like I
believe that I have a good repertoire of
moves that I can work and so just going
up against those tackles. Some some
weeks I can't use the same moves as I
could other weeks on different on
another tackle. So it's just like having
those moves also in my bag just in case
a tackle gives me a different set and a
different look.
>> That's hard. Yeah, good stuff. Malachi
Lawrence joining us here on the Dallas
Cowboys Radio Network. The 23rd overall
pick in this year's NFL draft. Tommy,
you have something for Malachi?
>> Yeah, Malachi. Hey, congratulations,
man. Uh kind of tell Cowboys fans out
there that are listening what what kind
of player and person are they getting
here in in Malachi Lawrence?
>> Right. They're getting a a relentless
player, someone that's just ready to
come in and work. um a relentless motor
like I'm just going to chase that ball
no matter what. And then as a person
though, you're getting a great person,
someone who's going to bring a great a
great face and uh like have the Cowboys
name in good hands.
>> No doubt about it. Tell us about a
little bit of your background. Who
inspired you early in your career and
who are some of the players maybe in the
NFL now that you've modeled your game
after as you continue to grow uh and get
to the next level?
>> Right. Um, coming into UCF, um, uh, uh,
this edge rusher named Trayon Morris
Brash, we called him drop. Uh, I'd say
he definitely inspired me just how he
practiced and the moves he would use at
practice and then like I would kind of
replicate those and then I would do them
with my own little craft or my own
little way. So, I say him and then um,
what was the other question?
>> Yeah. NFL players, anybody that you
model your game after,
>> right? Yeah. I like to watch Chandler
Jones, Will Anderson, um Denil Hunter. I
like those guys. They're different,
unorthodox, and they know how to use
their their strengths.
>> Have you talked with Christian Parker at
all about how your usage will be uh in
this defense moving forward throughout
the process,
>> right? Yeah. Um yeah, we talked a little
bit about it like I'm I'm gonna be that
edge edge defender, edge rusher, getting
to the quarterback, ready to play the
run, ready to be scouted. So, yes, sir.
talk about that.
>> Awesome stuff. Malachi Lawrence, edge
rusher from UCF and the newest Dallas
Cowboys joining us on the phone line.
Malachi Guin, congratulations. Go
celebrate with your family. Can't wait
to talk to you tomorrow.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you so much.
>> There he goes. Malachi Lawrence, awesome
stuff. Really excited to see him.
>> Let me just say, people that Shotti's
been drafting, like they've all been
like, "Good dudes. We going to work
hard. We all leadership. We all locked
in." Like, they all sound the same. like
all those I don't want I don't want to
say the right kind of guy cuz that's
like Jason's you know you know you know
Jason Gar's era or whatever but they all
sound like hey man I'm locked in I'm
leadership I'm going to work hard I'm
the right kind of dude so man shouts out
to the Cowboys for having a type now
>> high energy love football
>> and he's not run down a millie you got
>> no I I I I'd love to hear him talk about
rushing with a plan or how you know like
react or just you know watching the film
and just kind of going based I can't
rush guys the same kind of way I'd love
to hear that cuz a lot of these young
pass rushers run down the middle of
people and I hate it.
>> No doubt. Couple picks to catch you up
on while we were on the phone with
Malachi Lawrence. 27th overall. The
Dolphins take Chris Johnson corner from
San Diego.
>> Zack hurt.
>> Good pick.
>> Yeah, it's one of the best picks I think
in the entire first round. I mean, they
got an absolute steal here. That was my
14th best player that they just took
what at 27. Two-way star. If you go back
and you watch him in high school, this
dude is the definition to me of sticky
in coverage. Do you have something,
Ryan? No, I was just laughing because I
just got a text message from a scout in
the league
>> and he just asked me. He said, "Votch
like our pick."
>> Oh, there you go.
>> Which pick was that?
>> Well, the the the Steelers love Votch.
>> Okay.
>> They watch the Steelers like to watch
Votch work
>> and so they asked my Scott. Yeah.
>> He goes the scout goes to approval.
>> The VC love our guy that we picked.
>> Love mixed to pieces.
>> They're listening to you right now.
>> That's awesome. The other pick that we
missed while on the phone with Lawrence
was Caleb Lomu, offensive tackle from
Utah, goes to the Patriots at pick 28 as
Buffalo bails out of that 28th pick. Uh,
and they they take offensive tackle
there for the Patriots.
>> The next time the next time the next
time someone tells me that the the the
Dolphins, this Green Bay group doesn't
take first round cornerbacks and all
that, I'm going to go tell you to f
yourself right now. I'm serious because
that I mean we were it's like well they
don't you know they like to develop and
they like to Chris Johnson was a great
pick by the way. That's a great pick for
them and so next time that someone says
oh you know these Packer guys don't take
first round corners.
>> Well they just took one.
>> Tough can blitz the technique sound. I
mean
>> sorry I was I diverted.
>> No you're good. He only allowed 18
completions this season in coverage on
43 passes defense. I mean I I think he's
got some inside flex. I I absolutely
love Chris Johnson. He could end up
being arguably the best corner him and
Delane in this class. For me, that's a
steal for Miami.
>> You said Packer guys.
>> Well, Packers, yeah, like the John Eric
Sullivan is from Green Bay and and and
their coach is from Green Bay and so
Jeff Hley, they're all down there and
Halfley was like, "Oh, I can develop
guys and I don't need to draft first
round." Yeah. You you just drafted a
first round one. You did
>> that you really don't have to develop
because he's really a good player. And
the Dolphins at 27 are who made that
pick just to be clear. Sorry about that.
I was jumping around.
>> All right, the Chiefs are on the clock
at 29. Their pick is in. But we've got
some secret audio from Malachi Lawrence.
Let's hear the moment that he was
drafted by the Cowboys with the 23rd
overall pick.
>> Malachi.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I got somebody who wants to talk to you.
Hold on.
>> Okay, bet.
>> Malachi.
>> Hey,
>> you are a Dallas Cowboy.
>> Yes, sir. Let's go. I'm telling you,
we're excited about you.
>> My man is a Dallas Cowboy.
>> Well, we're proud of you. You should be
proud. We've been watching you play.
>> Well, we're proud for you, Malachi.
Here's your coach. This Jerry Jones, but
here's your coach. Hey, Coach Sean.
Congratulations, brother.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you. Appreciate it.
>> Hey, man. We are so excited, man. So
fired up, brother.
>> Hey, hold on.
Hey, you're going to come here and eat,
man. You're going to come.
>> Hey, hold on one sec. Here's our DC.
>> Yes, sir.
>> What's up, baby?
>> What's up? How you doing?
>> Huh?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Hey, man. Look. Got it done, bro. Glad.
>> I can't even hear you. You're so loud.
>> Man, look. Hey, you enjoy the moment,
bro. Look, your boy Demetri Brim right
here, man. He's smiling from ear to ear.
Yes, sir.
>> Hey, look. Uh We we'll hit you later,
man. You enjoy the party. Enjoy the
moment, bro. Congratulations.
>> Incredible stuff. You got to hear from
Jerry Jones, Brian Shottenheimimer,
Christian Parker, as Malachi Lawrence is
taken there by the Cowboys with 23rd
pick. Just in case you didn't know, just
in case you didn't know, this is Jerry
Jones, by the way.
>> It's Jerry Jones.
>> This Jerry Jones, bro.
>> Want to make sure it wasn't Bill Clinton
who showed up to the pre-draft press
conference, too.
>> Yeah, that was wild. All right, steps
away from AT&T Stadium, the National
Medal of Honor Museum showcases the
stories of ordinary Americans who took
extraordinary action in the service of
others. Real people, real courage, real
close. Plan your visit at museum.org.
Back alongside Vot Lombardi, Brian
Bratis, Zack Walchuk, Tommy Yarish, I'm
Kyle Yman. Here's Roger Goodell making
his way to the podium in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania for the Chief selection at
pick number 29. Second pick of the night
to go with Mansour Delane.
>> With the 29th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Kansas City Chiefs select
Peter Woods, defensive tackle Clemson.
>> Nice.
>> Chris Jones getting up there a little
bit in age.
>> Mhm.
>> Peter Woods is now he is not the pass
rusher that one Chris Jones is, but you
know exactly what you're getting in
Peter Woods. And that to me was probably
the best rundefending defensive tackle
in the class.
>> He was the highest remaining player on
my board. Not to mention they got him
and they took Mensor to Lane. That's
>> nice picks.
>> Top 10 player and a top 15 player on my
board. Yeah.
>> Uh they've they've had a pretty good
haul this time around on the defensive
side of the ball. I know Patrick Mahomes
might need a little bit of help on
offense out there in KC, but man, they
their defense is getting some help.
>> Well, they got some receivers on the
board. They're in round two, so I don't
know if they're necessarily blank there,
but yeah, Peter Woods, 13th best player
on my board. He's got great size and
athleticism for a player his size.
Strong upper half. He's able to make
shedding blocks one-on-one. Look really
easy against the run like Zach pointed
out. Uh I think he's a little bit high
in his pad level. Um he kind of does
that consistently. Lineman can kind of
get under him and push him back, but u
tackling techniques not great, but he's
able to make it into the back field. He
slows runners down. That's a big plus.
uh you know all these Clemson guys on
defense, you you're probably a little
underwhelmed from the 2025 season. I
think some of that is utilization. I
wouldn't buy too much into that. I think
you're going to see Peter Woods be a
really good football player for a really
long time. And when he is next to Chris
Jones, that's going to be a lot of fun
to watch.
>> I think he nailed it with the him when
it comes to playing too high. When it's
pad levels down, he's extremely
disruptive.
>> He runs through people. It's it's the
leverage with him. Like he just runs hot
and cold, but when he is when the
leverage is on, he can slip in between
blocks. He's disruptive. He's in the
back field. He he looked a lot smaller
this year compared to 2024. I don't know
if he lost some weight in the games that
I saw him in in 2025 versus the year
before. I went back, you watched against
Texas, South Carolina. I mean, he looks
like an out. He's just a different type
of player uh versus the 24 tape to the
25 tape. But I I like this pick. I think
it's good value. I think I had him as my
25th best player and they're getting him
here at at what pick 29. So good good
draft for Kansas City.
>> You know, when you watch the SMU game,
he was awful, you know, and but you can
watch him against LSU and Georgia Tech
>> for sure
>> and he's playing well and then you watch
him against SMU and you're like
thinking, I wonder if there's something
wrong with him,
>> you know, just physically. Um he had
three sacks when I by the time I did
this he had three sacks through eight
games and when he when he he could play
with momentum he could be a problem. I
mean like he could get up the field and
he could be a dominant player but when
he's not playing like that like he did
against SMU
>> he just like he's just so just
methodical and not you know not doing
anything to kind of get
>> consistency is the big
>> Yeah. I mean like the the power, the
movement, all that stuff.
stack shed
>> Jets pick
>> but man it's he he can he can he can
have some problems on I could that SMU
game wasn't very good for him
>> here's the Jets at 30
>> maybe that's Omar Cooper wide receiver
from Indiana is the pick
>> another Jets at 30
>> yeah and well and there was some talk
right they could have taken him at 16 so
they go with Kenyan Sadique the best
tight end of the draft now you take my
wide receiver three and no more Cooper
Jr. The yak is real with him.
>> So burst off the line of scrimmage. Yak
guy tracking the ball in the air and
gray hands. Fantastic.
>> And they traded back into the first
round in order to make this selection.
They were sitting at the top pick in the
33rd pick overall. So they trade up to
go to 30 with San Francisco. That pick
at 30 changed hands four times. The most
out of any pick in the NFL draft so far.
Denver to Miami to San Francisco and
then to the New York Jets where they
take Omar Cooper Jr. wide receiver from
Indiana. It's time for us to take a
break. You're listening to the 2026 NFL
draft on the Dallas Cowboys radio
network and on dallascowboys.com.
All right, so Omar Cooper is the pick
there at 30. Two more selections
remaining. The Bills are now on the
clock and followed by the Super Bowl
champion Seattle Seahawks to round out
the first round today. Once again, if
you're just now joining us, Caleb DS,
the Cowboys take him at 11th overall.
One of the best players on the defensive
side of the football in this draft. And
then they get some pass rush help at
23rd overall with Malachi Lawrence as
they trade from 20 to 23. and they pick
up two fourth round picks and they ship
off a seventh round pick to Philadelphia
in a trade with the Eagles. Tell me a
little bit about Omar Cooper Jr. here,
Tommy, before you have to get up and go
to the uh to the press conference here
in a moment.
>> Uh just a well-rounded, consistent
player. That that's really what I put
about him. Uh I think he's got an
excellent build for the position. He's
got great body control, contact balance.
The frame again makes it tough to bring
him down on first contact. He's got soft
hands, good speed. He can win deeper on
inb breaking routes. Um I feel like his
cuts could be a little bit sharper, but
he makes it work. You know, when Indiana
needed something offensively in through
the air, you've got the Heisman winner
and Mendoza. They they looked his way.
They looked number three's way and he
got the job done for him this past
season. So, I I think this is a good
pick for the Jets. By the way, the
Titans just traded back in to the first
round as well. Just like the Jets just
did, the Titans go back up and trade
with the Bills at 30 31 overall. They
are now with their pick in. So, the
Seahawks are on the clock.
>> Was that pick that that uh the Jets
made? What was the number on that pick?
Was that number 30?
>> 30. Thank you very much. Appreciate
that.
>> So, they were on 30. The Bills just
shipped off New England's original pick.
Uh remember New England traded with
Buffalo to go from 31 to 28 to take
Caleb Alomu uh the offensive tackle out
of Utah. I'll reset all the picks when
we come back on the radio side of things
here in a matter of moments. But Robert
Salah in Tennessee looking on
>> as the Titans trade back in to the first
round.
What have you thought? What's been the
biggest surprise so far in the first
round for you guys? Ty Simpson at 13
100%. I think
>> I think you could make an argument too
for Fondo at nine with Cleveland.
>> Uh that's I think Brian pointed it out
earlier. That's probably the reason why
Dallas has Caleb DS on their team right
now. Um but but Simpson was the the one
that made me drop my jaw a little bit.
>> Yeah, Carnell Tat even at four I thought
was a pretty big surprise to Tennessee.
I didn't necessarily see that one
coming. But then Caleb Banks to
Minnesota at 18, especially coming off
of a broken foot. I mean, I get it with
Caleb Banks. The talent's there with the
player, but the tape was not great last
year. He's got the injury. Uh, I thought
at 18, I mean, they'd been linked to
Dylan Theamman. I thought safety was
where they would go. Maybe even Man
Emanuel McNeel Warren. So, that was an
interesting pick. I thought there Caleb
Banks going at 18 to Minnesota.
>> Yeah. See y'all tomorrow.
>> Blake Miller was the one for me, you
know, and I and I that that one I did
not see I thought Detroit, you know,
Detroit usually plays and they've got
athletic guys. Miller. I I just really I
question his power. This is going to be
the Colton Millers, the Nate Soldors,
the David Bakiaris. There's all these
guys are the the the nonp power guys
that play. We'll see about Blake Miller.
>> Here's the pick for the Titans.
>> Before the Titans pick,
>> congratulations. You set a record for
the first night of the draft. 320,000
people here tonight. N we had more
watching than ours.
>> Awesome
team cowboy.
>> Javon Curse
>> in the 2026 NFL draft.
>> The Tennessee Titans select Kendrick
Faulk, defensive end Auburn.
>> All right, you're gonna have to run
those flippers now.
>> Really good player. Kendrick Faulk going
to the Tennessee Titans at 31 overall.
>> He is a good player. I'm not being
sarcastic there. I am happy I don't have
to run a 5K and flip it.
>> I think we like Kendrick Fog. Just
Kendrick at 12 was like un unsettling.
>> He wasn't he wasn't going to be an edge
here.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, so if you're talking about like
if you expected him to come in here and
like really go after the passer, that
was not what he was going to play here.
>> Four eye guy, right?
>> Yeah. Four four eye. He was going to
play head up on the tackle next to
Quinnan and Kenny.
>> And I would argue he would need to put
on about 10 to 15 pounds to play that
four eye.
>> Yeah. That would have been that would
have been that would have been the plan.
they would have brought him in here.
They would have bulked him up a little
more.
>> Try and get him to about 285, 290. He's
sitting at 276. So, not only was it the
the love for Malachi Lawrence on top,
but it was also the immediate fit for a
guy who I think can be really good, and
he might be one of the better pass
rushers by the end of his career. Yeah.
That Tennessee has seen in a long time.
>> I think he's an outstanding run
defender, but I mean, Tennessee, that
was the the comp with Mike.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. No, we we did hear
Tennessee from earlier that
>> there were suggestions that Tennessee
would be the one to take fault
>> and to move up and go get him. They
clearly did covet the player. I mean,
that fits with Robert Solo wants to do,
the type of defensive lineman he likes.
>> Can I uh Well, we're going to come back,
I guess.
>> I hate you, Payton. I guess.
One of the names that had been talked
about quite some time throughout the
2026 NFL draft process for a Cowboys
fit. Kendrick Faulk goes to Tennessee
who trades back into the first round in
the 31st overall selection to take the
edge out of Auburn. Wrapping up the
final five picks to this point. The
Seahawks are on the clock with the final
pick in the first round. And we'll hear
from the Cowboys front office shortly.
But at 27, the Dolphins take Chris
Johnson, corner from San Diego State.
The Patriots at 28 take Caleb Lomu,
offensive tackle from Utah. The Chiefs
take Peter Woods, the interior defensive
lineman from Clemson. Jets take Omar
Cooper Jr., wide receiver from Indiana.
They pair him with Kenan Sadi, the tight
end out of Oregon, a pair of pass
catchers for the Jets in the first
round. And then, as we just mentioned,
Kendrick Faulk, edge rusher from Auburn,
goes to the Titans at 31. We're with
Vach Lombardi from YouTube and Crown
Global Media from 1053, The Fan, a trio
of radio host, Brian Bratis, Zack
Walchuk, Bobby Belt. I'm Kyle Yman's
from DallasCowboys.com.
>> Kyle,
>> yes.
>> I got a question. What's that?
>> It's for It's for Brian, actually,
because Brian says this every year, and
I don't think we've ever asked him the
the actual question that led up to this.
>> So, who what tackle in your scouting
history scared you off of the lighter
ones?
>> For instance, I know like I know uh who
was it? It was uh Terrell Buckley. You
got scared off of smaller corners from
you you got scarred from when you guys
picked Buckley.
>> So, so was there like a tackle in your
time with the Packers that like scared
you off of the the lighter tackles?
>> No. Ever since I got out of the league,
I can't evaluate these light tackles. I
can't. I mean, it's weird. It's it's a I
I I'm always mentioning the names like
David Baktiari with the Packers.
>> So, those are those are those are
players who ended up
>> Colorado had like all these light
offensive tackles and I couldn't get
them right. And today I'm like,
>> okay. And I know better. I know better.
And but uh yeah it was it you know
Colton Miller at UCLA and it's just it
bothers me when you when you watch these
guys block and then that Nate Solder I
watched him when he was with New England
and went to the Giants
>> just try to run him up the arc. You just
try and get him up
>> and you just run over him you know and
you're like okay that's but uh yeah it's
a it's a big blind spot for me. It
really really is.
>> So with the Seahawks on the board with
the final
>> what running back is on the board right
now?
>> Darian Price. Yeah, from
>> John Snyder will take a running back lot
of sense.
>> He always does and it actually makes
sense for him to do so as Kenneth Walker
goes to Kansas City, right?
>> He tried to he tried to trade I think
he's trying to trade back. I mean, I
think he he wants some more picks here,
but
>> I don't know. We'll see how the uh
>> Colton Hood's still on the board.
>> Well, as we yeah, as we entered near the
end of the first round, I got to just
wait for this last pick to come off the
board before I go into my Twitter
bookmarks and tweet at every single
person who told me I was nuts when I
said Gerard McCoy would not go in the
first round.
>> Yep. That's part of it.
>> I've got all y'all saved. If you tweeted
it at me, you need to be ready.
>> No, this
>> you're gonna get a tweet from me in
about the next 10 minutes.
>> I think it's unfortunate though.
>> I do too with the name.
>> I don't I think it's unfortunate for Jam
McQuay. Do not think it's unfortunate
for the people I'm about to tweet at.
>> Okay. To you.
>> Well, you're going to also assuming
Seattle doesn't take him here. You were
right about Jacob Rodriguez. No, I mean
Sunny Styles is the only linebacker that
went.
>> See, I think I think where we I think
where we we lost our focus a little bit
and I'm saying we but those linebackers
were all kind of those we always thought
they were all in the late 20s, maybe
early 30 or maybe the third, you know,
29, 28, somewhere right around there.
>> But in actuality, they're more like 38
to 45 to 50.
>> We're going to see a run on linebackers
early tomorrow.
>> Yeah, 30 to I mean, yeah, probably the
33 to 60 range. I mean at 51 all my guys
are right there. Hill's still there.
Allen's still there. You know,
>> Rodriguez, Josiah. Yeah, they're all
there. They're all there. A lot of
corners.
>> Final selection in the first round. 32nd
overall. The champion Seahawks on their
way to the podium. Roger Goodell
bringing an end to the first round of
the 2026 NFL draft.
As we conclude round one of the 2026 NFL
draft, we're proud to continue
recognizing our longstanding partnership
with Makea-Wish this World Wish Month.
I'm thrilled to be joined by Dylan, a
huge fan of the Super Bowl champion
Seattle Seahawks, who bravely battled a
brain tumor and is now a twotime cancer
survivor.
>> Wow.
>> This is a wish come true for Dylan and a
chance to take part in one of the most
exciting moments in our league. Dylan,
when you're ready, stage is yours.
>> What's going on?
>> Oh, microphones.
>> I'm so excited to be here to represent
the twelves.
OH, AND the
Super Bowl champion Seattle.
should have taught him about
microphones.
>> If the Cowboys win a Super Bowl, I'mma
scream at somebody microphone.
>> With a 30sec pick in the 2026 NFL draft,
the Seattle Seahawks select Jadarian.
>> Wow.
>> Man, you should have
>> I wasn't playing this. This was This is
exactly what I threw in my mock draft
every single time.
>> Makes sense.
>> Yeah. That's what John Snder does. He He
can't help himself.
>> And it won him a Super Bowl. I love this
guy. I love him and he can't help
himself. And when they pick again, he's
going to take another running back.
>> He'll take Mike Washington from
Arkansas.
>> He is a Super Bowl champion general
manager twice.
>> Yep.
>> He loves running backs more than any
person. I mean, it's amazing.
>> They needed a starter, though. I mean,
because you got Zack Charbanet who's now
>> physical runner, too. Like, they all
that same kind of guy. Jarian Price, you
know, obviously split time there with
Jeremiah Love. So, this is a guy that I
think is ready to take on a leadership
role as the as the lead dog. Dennis High
School local product, averaged 9.3 yards
per carry. He missed his freshman
season. He had a torn Achilles. He's
come back and been absolutely fantastic.
I love the size, the contact balance,
the speed, the initial burst and
acceleration. He's always falling
forward. The issue for him is he needs
to prove he can catch the football and
he needs to get better as a pass
blocker. But just as a runner, he to me
was clearly the second best back behind
Jeremiah Love.
>> He's got some incredible vision, too. He
was a kick returner. Actually, I think
he was an all-American kick returner at
that as well. And you talk about what he
was able to do even in limited action.
That's the biggest thing is he's coming
in fresh, fresh legs despite the
ruptured Achilles that he had early in
his career. I think he's going to be a
next level runner. It's interesting to
see what they do with Zack Charbanet
though. Now they've had a tandem
backfield in Seattle the last couple of
years with Kenneth Walker and then
Charbanet. Now you bring in Jadarian
Price to add to that. Is he the number
two back?
>> I think the featured one.
>> I think Charbanet is going to be like
the lead guy for like a year and when
this when the contract is up, I
highlight you. They're going to draft
another running back in the first round
in a year or two.
>> Talk about it again just like we are.
>> Jarion's going to be the lead guy and
the new running back is going to be
right behind him. It's a factory.
>> There you go. Cowboys fans, while the
team has been making big picks, make the
smart pick at home. Call Onimex Experts,
the official AC, Heating, and Plumbing
partner of the Dallas Cowboys. Fast,
reliable, always on time. That's on time
experts. Visit ontimeexperts.com
and click book now.
>> All right, the first round has come to a
close. We'll talk about running through
the the first 32 picks of the NFL draft
here in a moment.
>> Everyone's been tweeted at, Kyle.
>> Oh, good. That was quick. That was
really fast.
>> I had them in bookmarks.
>> I love it. Good.
>> Kind of take me through your impressions
of what happened tonight just across the
league, not just with Dallas, but across
the league. What did we see trends wise
and where the league is headed just by
the way they allocated the first 32
picks?
>> Um the for a draft where people said,
you know, throw positional value out the
window, it it was still your classic
positional value draft for the most
part. Um now you could say, well, what
about the running back?
running backs that we've seen some of
them go in the top five uh over the last
several years if if there were really
big time talent, but um I I think you
saw the league prioritizing the classics
of you know going out there and making
sure you get the uh you know the tackles
and get the offensive lineman and you
know picking a quarterback at 13 that a
lot of people didn't think was a even a
second round quarterback just by the way
people would grade it. Um, downs getting
to do it at 11, which is insane and and
the greatest insanity possible. Um, I I
think all that is the Cowboys. I like a
lot of people like Malachi Lawrence. Um,
>> but you a lot of people could also look
at that and say Malachi Lawrence is
another example though of like just
classic value for the position and
saying let's go take him at 23. Um,
because you know I think a lot of people
initially didn't think Malachi Lawrence
was going to go in the first. Yeah.
>> Um, but if they like him, they like him.
So I think what you saw here is the big
trend overall was just
sort of a reverting back to this is this
is what the league looks at as in terms
of important valuable positions and
that's why you see them get lower than
you probably initially thought. This is
why uh DS gets to where he goes and why
it's surprising to me that Colton Hood
is still on the board.
>> Yeah.
>> You see the same thing Brian? I think
that's well said by Bobby.
>> Yeah. I you know the thing I I I kind of
go back in my mind when I was talking
about these cornerbacks you know and and
and then it was the struggle of like
where where would you put these guys you
have you know with Cece he was a guy
that I had pretty high from South
Carolina hood you going back and forth
and you're kind of thinking man teams
need these corners and so it's a little
bit surprising that teams really didn't
take corners they didn't well they took
corners but they didn't take the corners
that I kind of thought were going to be
the guys those tape, you know, really
really showed up. Tomorrow, let's see if
guys sleeping on their boards and gals
sleeping on the board tonight. Will they
tomorrow when we start the second round,
will we see a run on these cornerbacks?
I think we're going to see a run maybe
on some of these wide receivers, too.
You know, get ready for for that. But it
was very surprising that some of those
top corners just did not even get a a
sniff uh when uh when it came down to
first round action.
>> What?
>> And just uh looking at my board and
Brian taught me how to highlight the
players on my board just to kind of get
a feel for it. Uh Ty Samson I had a
fourth round grade on. Man, it is what
it is. Shouts out to him. Let them knock
themselves out. Uh but four players from
my third round grades. Um Lomu, Miller,
Rage, and Banks. all those guys kind of
went and they're like trench guys, too.
So, I guess uh the offensive tackle
thing like really happened fast. So, now
the best offensive tackle I have left is
a fourth round tackle like Trey Zoom
like like we're way down like they they
took those guys off the board. So, if
you're looking for offensive tackle, you
had to get him early. And if you didn't,
you're stuck with a Austin barber or
like a Caleb Tieran. And look, I I say
stuck with all due respect, but I but
these are just guys I don't think can
like play for you like day one. They're
like developmental swing guys at at this
point. Um, and hell yeah, man. Is
there's a bunch of wide receivers left,
corners left, uh, most of your
linebackers are there, and there's a
bunch of uh, safeties as well. So, day
day two,
>> there's a bunch of players I like on the
board. So, the Cowboys not having the
two. I feel confident that somebody I
like can get. Would would you like to
hear who the league has as some of the
best players left on the board?
>> Love that.
>> Uh, Boston receiver, Washington.
>> Me, too. Uh, we've got Cece corner South
Carolina. Uh, Hood corner Tennessee.
>> McNeel Warren, safety Toledo.
>> I was about to say that.
>> Parker, edge rusher, Clemson. Uh,
McDonald, defensive tackle, Ohio State.
>> I'm a little shocked about both of those
two at the last two names that you just
read.
>> Stunns went above McDonald.
>> Yeah, especially McDonald.
>> I wonder if some teams just look at that
and maybe this is the case. I wonder if
some people just looked at that defense
and decided that McDonald was not
McDonald was a beneficiary of what was a
really ridiculously talented Ohio State
>> defense hell because if anything he's
the the nose of the defense and it may
start with him in my personal opinion
like the pass rushes around him the line
no it starts with Caleb DS let's be
clear cowboy bias for sure it starts
with the with the nickel player for sure
but to other teams go
>> we need to take a break because the
press conference is coming up very
shortly and we'll hear from the front
office. We'll step aside for a moment.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> Got to lay it back.
>> How long are we on the air for? Are we
done?
>> We've got till 11.
>> Whoa.
>> On the air. So, it depends on how long
this goes, but uh we are still on the
air for now until they start the press
conference for a little bit here.
>> Um and then we'll go into the press
conference whenever they get to that
point. So,
>> so we're done after the press. Are we
done after the press conference or
>> maybe?
>> Well, you're on right now.
>> Yeah, we're on now.
>> Oh, the currently we're live currently.
This is just Hey, this is live radio if
you're on
>> Oh, hey. Hi. Hi, live radio.
>> Yeah. Hey, guys. Uh, yeah. So, we'll
stay on until after the the presser.
I'll see.
>> Okay. And it's starting up soon. I guess
>> they're going in now. You said Chris
Beam. Oh, they left the room. Okay.
>> So, that's how close this can all
happen. And that's live for you. What is
your your biggest miss so far in terms
of projection of where somebody was
going to go? Is it the corners for you,
Brian?
>> Oh, it's it's all those corners. Yeah,
I'm sorry. Yeah, it's the corners. I
know with McCoy, Terrell, Hood, where
all those guys.
>> I was very I was very wrong about where
Cooper went. I thought Omar Cooper would
go earlier than 30.
>> I thought Theamman would go much earlier
than 25.
>> I think Theamman's thing is a lot of
teams do view him more as a traditional
safety. I don't know how much they view
him as the hybrid guy.
Um, I'm looking at I'm looking at McCoy,
Parker, Hood. McCoy, we know
>> McCoyy's Yeah, that that's a little bit
of extreme circumstances.
>> Tough Parker Hood. Uh, CJ Allen,
possibly medical there, too.
>> Preon from Oregon.
>> Zaki Wheatley. I I love Sake Wheatley.
That's the out state. I He's up there
for me.
>> I do think, by the way, now that we're
we're past everything, if Dallas would
have just stayed at 12.
>> Yeah.
And let's say every player could have
slid down the board to them like of the
guys that reasonably were talking about
there.
>> I think the order of preference would
have been Downs, Dellayine, Styles,
Tyson.
>> Completely agree.
>> I think that's the order they would have
gone.
>> So when they come out and say we got the
best player on our board, they probably
not lying to us. They probably
>> out of reasonably to get to them. Yes.
Because if you're talking about like
Reese and Bailey, they were going to be
very very high on their board. But I
would not be surprised if DS was a top
three to five player on the board for
them.
>> They wouldn't be wrong about that.
>> Every team that had multiple picks in
the first round really came out with a
pretty good hall. You look at the Jets
with David Bailey, Kenan Sadique, Omar
Cooper, the Giants with Arll Reese,
Francis Malaninoa, and then Dallas, I
mean, you got Malachi Lawrence and Caleb
DS.
>> Reese went five. If Dallas is picking
six, I think they're still taking downs.
>> Yeah, I would agree. Now, I do think
they would have taken Ree. If they were
sitting at five or something like that,
they'd probably take Reese over downs.
>> And I think when you keep the whole
picture in mind in a team that traded
two fifth round picks to go up one spot
to make the pick and get the guy that
they wanted, then they ultimately flip
it and they end up getting two fourth
rounds instead. I love that value.
>> Let's uh let's walk through the the
other circumstance. They obviously ended
up with Lawrence. What if they would
have had Reese at their pick? They pick
Reese initially or they let's just say
they take Styles so they didn't address
secondary.
>> Sure.
>> I think when they're sitting there at
20, Lawrence is still a discussion.
>> Yeah.
>> But I think there's a high high chance
that that pick would have been Chris
Johnson.
>> Yeah. It could have been Chris Johnson,
could have been Dylan Feeman.
>> So you think them taking safety took
corner off the board in round one?
>> Because I don't think they views as a
safety.
>> I think I think they view him as you're
an an allorld defensive back. He's going
to when they're in nickel looks, he is
going to be lined up as a corner. I
think
>> so. So, they don't even look at him as
like a nickel corner. Like he's nickel
player like like they've been talking.
>> He's he's corner and nickel. He is
safety in base
>> which they're not going to be in base
very often. I would guess that when
they're when they're in their nickel
looks it's going to be bland Revel downs
when everybody's healthy
>> and then you've got Thompson and Hooker
and then when they're in base then it's
going to be Bland Revel and then
Thompson and Downs are the safeties.
>> That's hard.
We are just a few moments away from
hearing from the Cowboys front office
here at the Star in Fris following the
first round of the NFL draft. And the
Cowboys select Caleb DS with the 11th
overall pick. They trade up one spot
with the Miami Dolphins. They send two
fifth round picks to Miami to make the
deal to go get Caleb DS. And then
originally at the 20th spot, they make a
trade with the Eagles. They get two
fourth round picks in return, but they
do send a seventh round pick and pick 20
to the Eagles. They then take Malachi
Lawrence with the 23rd overall pick in
the NFL draft. Hope you've had some fun
throughout the night with us as we
continue our coverage. Just getting
started on the weekend. We'll be back
tomorrow 600 p.m. Central time right
here at the beginning of round two. The
Cowboys don't pick again, at least at
the moment, until the 92nd overall pick.
So, we'll be waiting for a little bit,
but trust me, we've got plenty of
analysis and we've got all the film
study that you'll want to hear tomorrow.
The same group of individuals will be
back in the building. Brian Bratus, Zack
Walchuk, Bobby Belt, all from 1053, The
Fan from Crown Global Media and a
YouTube 100,000
uh subscriber
superstar, Mr. Vach Lombardi. I'm
Kyleman's from DallasCowboys.com. We'll
also have Nick Harris from the Fort
Worth Star Telegram and Tommy Yarish, my
co-orker with DallasCowboys.com
tomorrow as well. We were just talking
about maybe the the value and where it
kind of lined up for the draft and where
it ended up in the first round so far.
When you look at Dallas and how they
attacked these two spots today, safety
with downs, edge rusher with Lawrence,
where do you feel like 92 is the most
likely for Dallas tomorrow?
>> Keep it on defense. uh look and see what
the linebackers look like who who uh
fail to you and I don't think that they
they they're flat out done with safety.
I mean, there's a lot of safeties that
play multiple jobs. So, a guy like Kyle
Lewis that can play linebacker and
safety for you. Uh there's going to be a
lot of options, but it's a long wait,
though. So, you're going to have to wait
and see what the board uh does to you.
But, um I don't even think tackle's out
of the question like d uh dtackling and
you know, there's a bunch of dudes that
could uh that could that could fall
there. So, ton of options, but I'm I'm
really excited about day three and them
fours that you got today. I'm I'm really
excited about that.
>> And remember, you you you pick at 112
>> 114 and 137 in the fourth.
>> Yeah. I mean, I'd consider to move.
>> You could move back up.
>> Yeah. And I would I mean, I I'd consider
to do that, especially if you like one
of these linebackers, you know. Is CJ
Allen their guy from Georgia? Uh could I
get him to ride with me on Jacob
Rodriguez from Tech, Anthony Hill Jr.
from Texas,
>> Troder from Missou? I think those those
are the guys that I think, you know,
those are plugandplay. They can be
instant starters. Uh I I think that
maybe at 92 you could look at a Jimmy
Rder from Michigan. He's a player I like
a lot. Bryce Bcher, maybe Keshan Elliot
uh from Arizona State. Maybe those are
guys that you could look at. But guys,
there's so many good defensive backs.
Like corner is in and safety. Like these
guys are going to be steals on day two.
Whether it's Pawns from Indiana, Rivers
from Duke, Bud Clark from TCU a safety.
I mean, Traden Stokes is still out
there. He'll probably come off the board
pretty quick tomorrow. Uh, but and then
wide receiver, I I I still think in the
third round, and I Bobby, I think you've
made the point of like they're not going
to come out of the draft without a
receiver.
>> There could be, if they stay at 92,
could a Skyler Bell from Yukon get
there?
>> Uh, could Elijah Serat from Indiana,
Jeremy Bernard from Bama, Ted Hurst from
Georgia State's, a player I love in this
>> Hurst is going to go Hurst will go early
tomorrow.
>> Okay. Stribbling is a guy from
Mississippi State that's got a ton of
buzz right now. There's a lot. I mean,
where does Chris Bell from Louisville,
who I think could have been a
firstrounder, but yeah, because of that,
I mean, does does he slide? There's a
lot of really good names.
>> I know last week there was one team that
said Chris Bell was a fourthrounder.
>> Okay, give me the picks again that
Dallas obtained that that we were
talking about in the fourth round. What
numbers are they, please?
>> 114 is what they got today. 137.
>> So, they got they've got 112, too,
right?
>> Yes, they do. I'm looking at that combo
112 and 114. They could move one of
those two picks. Pair it with 92 and go
up a little further.
>> Now, this is where I'm going to do this.
I'm probably going to take that for that
114 or 112 and I'm going to trade it for
a veteran linebacker
>> is what I'm going to do.
>> Wow.
>> I'm going to do I mean, we talked about
with the Dolphins, you know, the
possibility. I think this is where I
think that the fact that they they have
these picks. I know there's some
linebackers on this, but man, I I kind
of feel like listen, if you can
>> get them both, get a vid,
>> get them both. If you want to if you
want to draft a linebacker and then take
one of those picks and move it for one
of these leagues, you know, the that
there's teams out there that are
interested. Let's see what's going on
down in Houston. You know, circle back
with with uh with them. Miami, circle
back with them. Looks like Miami wants
to collect picks.
>> Yeah. you know, just circle back with
these teams that you maybe had some
conversations are. I think they're going
to need to go get a veteran guy and
maybe this opportunity of moving, you
know, 114 or 112 might be the might be
the ticket to do that. Plus, then take
the whatever pick you don't use and then
draft and kind of get both those
linebackers taken care of at one time.
>> And let's say one of those teams,
>> Brooks at Miami, right, is who we're
talking about.
>> I don't know. I don't know that we can
>> we can't talk about Oh, I'm sorry. My
bad. My bad. My apologies. My
apologetical
hypothetical.
>> Okay. You can you can Jimmy Brooks is
the GM in Miami.
>> Yeah. I think he's on the coaching
staff.
>> Brought us thinking about Robert Brooks.
He used to play receiver for him in
Green Bay.
>> We talking about
>> South Carolina. He was a good player.
>> He was.
>> Yeah.
>> Even though his middle name is Brooks.
>> Let's say one of those teams wants a
third round pick. They want a third
round pick for one of those veteran
linebackers.
>> Yeah.
>> You could take 92 and ship that off.
>> Or you could take 112 and 114 and get
back into the third yourself. there's
enough value there where you could get
back into the third cuz 92 is the back
half of the third round.
>> You know, Jerry Jones and then I know
they moved a third for for George
Pickkins. I mean, it the four didn't
work out for Lance. The four didn't work
out for uh uh for Mingo, but that's now
you've kind of got that and and like I
say, there's teams I'm looking at, okay,
I'm looking at these teams that
potentially have these these linebackers
that teams are willing to move. Let's
let's see. Let's entice them. maybe
going into the day thinking, "Hey, would
you be willing to and and and and make a
run at one of these guys?"
>> All right, so as the first round comes
to a close, Cowboys take Caleb DS at 11.
They take Malachi Lawrence at 23. We're
going to step aside and hand things over
to the AT&T media center up here at the
Star in Fris and hand it over to the
front office of the press conference
following the first round. Good contact
balance